<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Harper's Magazine</title>
        <link>https://harpers.org/</link>
        <description>null</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 03:26:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/ruicosta042/rssconv-action</generator>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Memoriam: John Cullen]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/in-memoriam-john-cullen/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/in-memoriam-john-cullen/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 20:38:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Readers may be wondering why I haven’t posted a new, translated column in the past two weeks, since I write monthly (almost without fail) for <em>Le Devoir</em> of Montreal. There are two reasons: the first is that Catholic Quebec shuts down the day after Easter, so my column was delayed a week from its usual first-Monday-of-the-month publication schedule, and the second is that during the delay my friend and translator, John Cullen, fell ill and died. John’s passing, at seventy-nine, is a terrible loss for his partner, the novelist Valerie Martin, and for his family and friends back in New Orleans, where he was born. If you knew him, you would instantly recognize the easy and ironic humor of John’s hometown in every story and every joke he told. Raconteur is one of those French words that has gravitated seamlessly into English, and it describes John to a T. Like the city that bred him, he was never boring, and like the people he grew up with, he always took sufficient time to tell a story with style and aplomb. New Orleans is America’s most unusual and, in some respects, most “foreign” city, with a culture that defies American stereotypes. I suspect that it’s the mélange of New Orleans French, Creole, Spanish, and English that turned John into a linguist, and it was his ease in commuting between cultures that made him such a good translator. That facility, with varied tongues and nationalities, is no doubt what made him valuable to novelists and journalists alike.</p>
<p>You might ask why I had my column translated all, why I didn’t just rewrite myself in English. The answer is partly because I don’t have the time or the patience, and partly because I think so separately in two languages because my mother was French and my father was American. But there’s another very specific reason. In 2014, when I stopped writing my column in the <em>Providence Journal</em>, I suddenly had no regular outlet in English for the first time in many years. The easiest solution was to have my French column translated, and, I thought, wouldn’t that be a novelty? But I almost never read French in translation, so I didn’t know any translators or even how to judge them. Then I remembered John Cullen. I hadn’t met him, but I knew one of his star clients, the novelist Philippe Claudel, from having moderated a discussion between Claudel and A.M. Homes at NYU’s Maison Française back in 2011. It was there that the actor Robert Adrian read an excerpt of Claudel’s extraordinary work <em>Le Rapport de </em><em>Brodeck</em>, and it struck me: “This is how Claudel should sound in English.” It was pitch perfect. My American mind heard my French understanding of the novel and read it back to me so well in English that I hardly noticed the difference in languages.</p>
<p>Later I learned that John occasionally translated francophone journalists like Kamel Daoud, whose pieces on the op-ed page of the <em>New York Times</em> betrayed none of the standard awkwardness from foreign contributors. Lost in translation is a well-worn cliché, but it’s axiomatically true that meaning gets dispersed and hidden from one culture to another, one set of idioms to another. When I asked John if he would translate my column, he at first demurred. But he finally agreed, and from February 2016 until this past March, for fifty-three columns, John explained my French conception to my American readers. With considerable editing help from <em>Harper’s Magazine</em>’s then editor Ellen Rosenbush, we turned it into something resembling my “voice.” Sometimes it worked perfectly, and Ellen, who continues to edit the column, changed almost nothing. Sometimes we struggled, but those occasions had more to do with my French construction failing me than with John failing me. Now that he’s gone, I will have a hard time finding a replacement. And I know that while I miss him very much as a person, I’m also missing something inside my head, and I don’t quite know where to look for it. Is it in French or is in English? I may have to go to New Orleans to find out.</p>
<p><a href="https://obits.nola.com/obituaries/nola/obituary.aspx?n=john-christopher-cullen&amp;pid=198368944" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Read John’s obituary in the </em>Times-Picayune.</a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/in-memoriam-john-cullen/" target="_blank">In Memoriam: John Cullen</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost in Thought]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/lost-in-thought/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/lost-in-thought/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 02:58:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">As work subsumes leisure time, worldwide anxieties mount, and a pandemic reshapes comfort and togetherness, meditation has been touted as a panacea. People who are stressed out (are there any other kind?) can take a meditation course, read an article, go on a retreat, or use an app; the hope is to gain from meditation peace, health, productivity, focus, or a good night’s sleep. It comes almost universally recommended and has precious few public detractors.</p>
<p>David Kortava’s article “<a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/04/lost-in-thought-psychological-risks-of-meditation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lost in Thought</a>,” from the April issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine</em>, is an investigation into the possible negative side effects of meditation. Kortava reports on a practitioner’s bout with psychosis during an extended stay at a vipassana meditation center that had her wishing for death. Kortava presents evidence of meditation’s potential to distress and harm. In this episode of the podcast, <em>Harper’s</em> web editor Violet Lucca speaks with Kortava about the experiential gap filled by meditation, the perils of a one-size-fits-all approach, and the gulf between the origins of meditative practice and its modern-day deployment.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe title="Lost in Thought by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1035050125&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/lost-in-thought/" target="_blank">Lost in Thought</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-mass-shooting-fukushima-water-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-mass-shooting-fukushima-water-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 17:55:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">In Indianapolis, a 19-year-old killed eight people and wounded several others at a FedEx warehouse where employees were unable to call the police or family members because of a company policy forbidding workers from carrying cell phones.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/16/politics/mass-shootings-america-guns/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/fedex-indianapolis-cell-phone-policy-employee-shooting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a></sup> A police department in Minnesota released body-cam footage of an officer killing an unarmed 20-year-old named Daunte Wright, some 10 miles away from the courthouse in which another officer, Derek Chauvin, is on trial for the death of George Floyd; the City of Chicago released a video recording of an officer killing 13-year-old Adam Toledo after he had lifted his hands in the air; Kenosha, Wisconsin, law enforcement announced that the officer who shot and paralyzed Jacob Blake would not face disciplinary action; and one of the police officers who shot Breonna Taylor in Louisville, Kentucky, was given a book deal.<sup><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1_H710uztOQ3b6G-OvE_XWhlLQsMXypGHkrUW25JCzFU/edit?ts=607ee496#gid=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/15/us/adam-toledo-chicago-shooting-video.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/nbcblk/no-discipline-kenosha-police-officer-who-shot-jacob-blake-chief-n1263986" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.thecut.com/2021/04/one-of-the-cops-who-killed-breonna-taylor-got-a-book-deal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a></sup> Federal health officials called for a temporarily halt to distribution of the Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine after six people out of the more than 7 million who have received the shot fell ill.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/13/us/politics/johnson-johnson-vaccine-blood-clots-fda-cdc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> President Joe Biden announced that the United States will withdraw all troops from Afghanistan by September 11, and Republican members of Congress announced, and then subsequently canceled, plans for an America First caucus that would work to foster “common respect for uniquely Anglo-Saxon political traditions.”<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/biden-us-troop-withdrawal-afghanistan/2021/04/13/918c3cae-9beb-11eb-8a83-3bc1fa69c2e8_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a></sup> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/04/20/marjorie-taylor-greene-implosion-america-first-caucus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>9</sup></a></p>
<p>The assistant defense minister of Australia reminded the nation’s armed forces that their chief mission remained the “application of lethal violence” after a controversial commissioning ceremony for the HMAS <em>Supply</em> that featured a dance troupe twerking in front of the 21,500-pound replenishment oiler.<sup><a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-04-14/military-reminded-lethal-violence-defend-australian-values/100066796" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> A Czech man turned over to authorities a T-34 tank and a SD-100 tank destroyer as part of a nationwide weapon-amnesty program, and a Yorkshire, England, woman whose partner was killed with a crossbow issued a call for British legislation regulating access to “medieval weapons.”<sup><a href="https://praguemorning.cz/czech-nationwide-weapon-amnesty-prompts-citizen-to-turn-tank-over-to-authorities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/apr/16/woman-who-lost-partner-in-crossbow-attack-wants-medieval-weapon-regulated" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>12</sup></a> The city council in Placerville, California—whose nickname, “Hangtown,” derives from a series of 19th-century lynchings—decided to remove the noose that had been featured on its seal, and Facebook apologized for removing the official page of the French town of Bitche after it was mistakenly flagged for containing offensive language.<sup><a href="https://localnews8.com/news/2021/04/14/city-known-as-hangtown-votes-to-remove-noose-from-its-logo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://www.cityofplacerville.org/placerville-city-history" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/13/lifes-a-bitche-french-towns-facebook-page-shut-down-over-offensive-name" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>15</sup></a> “The name of our town seems to suffer from a bad interpretation,” said Bitche’s mayor. The Florida House of Representatives passed a bill forbidding transgender students from participating in women’s high school and college sports, and authorizing genital inspections in cases in which a student’s gender is disputed.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/changing-america/respect/equality/548534-floridas-new-ban-on-transgender-students-in-sports-would" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> “This is about giving women and girls an equal chance to succeed,” said one Florida Republican who supported the bill. “It’s simple.” A Republican state senator in Missouri introduced legislation to designate January 12 as Rush Limbaugh Day, and Tennessee lawmakers proposed naming the ladder as the official state tool.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/548526-missouri-state-gop-lawmakers-propose-rush-limbaugh-day" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a> </sup><a href="https://www.wkrn.com/news/local-news/ladder-could-be-named-official-state-tool-of-tennessee/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>18</sup></a> An Austrian court ruled that intentional flatulence contains no “communicative content” and thus is not protected by the freedom of expression.<sup><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/z3xb59/man-fined-for-farting-on-cop-argues-farts-are-protected-forms-of-expression" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup></p>
<p>Japan announced plans to release into the Pacific Ocean more than 1 million tons of treated wastewater that was contaminated in the Fukushima nuclear disaster, prompting a spokesperson for the Chinese Foreign Ministry to urge Japan’s deputy prime minister to drink it himself.<sup><a href="https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2021/04/japan-plans-release-fukushima-s-contaminated-water-ocean" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> </sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/04/14/china-japan-fukushima-water-drink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>21</sup></a> “The ocean is not Japan’s trash can,” said the spokesperson. The islanders of Tanna, who view the late Prince Philip as a “recycled descendant of a very powerful spirit or god that lives on one of their mountains,” mourned the royal’s passing.<sup><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/prince-philip-death-vanuatu-tribes-tanna-worship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup> Darius, the world’s largest rabbit, was reported missing; a mysterious creature spotted in a tree in Kraków was revealed by animal-welfare workers to be a croissant; and a group of scientists created chimeric embryos consisting of both human and monkey cells.<sup><a href="https://www.livescience.com/worlds-largest-rabbit-darius-missing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a> <a href="https://www.euronews.com/2021/04/16/mystery-animal-sighting-in-krakow-ends-up-being-a-croissant" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> </sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2021/04/15/987164563/scientists-create-early-embryos-that-are-part-human-part-monkey" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>25</sup></a> “My first question is, why?” asked one researcher who was not involved in the project. A study determined that the total number of <em>Tyrannosaurus</em> <em>rexes</em> that ever existed was roughly 2.5 billion, though only about 20,000 adults were alive at any given time.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/lifestyle/science/like-godzilla-actually-real-study-shows-t-rex-numbered-25-billion-2021-04-15/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-mass-shooting-fukushima-water-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Town of C]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/town-of-c-richard-rothman-lyle-rexer/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/town-of-c-richard-rothman-lyle-rexer/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 12:00:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The photographer Richard Rothman spent more than a decade taking pictures in a small town along the Front Range of Colorado’s Rocky Mountains. The resulting monograph, <em>Town of C</em><em>,</em> was published by Stanley/Barker, and <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/03/town-of-c-richard-rothman/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a selection of the photographs</a> appears in the March issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine</em><em>.</em> The book’s scope is comprehensive, documenting the grandeur and the despoliation of the region’s geography and the lives and spaces of its poorest—and richest—residents. “Through portraits and landscapes,” the critic and curator Lyle Rexer writes in his introduction, “Rothman presents the paradox of expansiveness and confinement, of possibility and crushing limitation.”</p>
<p>In this episode of the podcast, Violet Lucca brings Richard Rothman and Lyle Rexer together for a conversation about Rothman’s new work and the current state of art photography. They discuss how the focus and narrative structure of <em>Town of C</em> changed over time, the role of art photography in a culture oversaturated with images, and the hundreds of minute decisions that go into composing a photograph.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe title="Town of C by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1029594775&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/town-of-c-richard-rothman-lyle-rexer/" target="_blank">Town of C</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-amazon-union-chauvin-trial-white-lies-matter-toilet/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-amazon-union-chauvin-trial-white-lies-matter-toilet/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 18:46:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Workers at an Amazon warehouse in Bessemer, Alabama, voted against joining a union by a margin of 1,798 to 738.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-56695667" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a></sup> Amazon, which hired 400,000 workers last year and is America’s second-largest employer, had last faced a union vote in 2014, and the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union said that it would contest the Bessemer results, arguing that some of the tactics used by the company, such as asking the USPS to install a mailbox at the facility the day before voting began and then to remove it after voting ended, were illegal.<sup><a href="https://fortune.com/2021/04/08/amazon-usps-mailbox-union-vote-labor-law-violations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a></sup> In Kentucky, the Republican-led legislature passed a bill expanding voting rights, and a town in Missouri said that it will consult state law to determine how to fill positions on its board of trustees after an election in which not a single vote was cast.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/03/30/politics/kentucky-early-absentee-voting-bill/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/wireStory/small-southwest-missouri-town-voted-tuesday-76949950" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a></sup> After multiple companies announced boycotts of Georgia in the wake of new laws limiting voter access, Senator Mitch McConnell, whose super PAC in 2020 accepted a combined $475 million from corporations and corporate CEOs, said that corporations should “stay out of politics” before adding, “I’m not talking about political contributions.”<sup><a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2021/04/mitch-mcconnell-corporate-donors" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> JetBlue resumed donating to one of the lawmakers who voted against certifying Biden’s Electoral College victory, and Mad Dog PAC, which once received a $5,000 donation from Anthony Scaramucci, paid for a billboard in Crestview, Florida, that reads <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">matt gaetz wants to <span style="font-size: .8em;">“</span>date<span style="font-size: .8em;">”</span> your child.</span><sup><a href="https://about.bgov.com/news/jetblue-makes-1st-pac-giving-to-election-objector-after-halt-1/?utm_medium=bgov&amp;utm_campaign=97C31796-9871-11EB-A137-22B24F017A06&amp;utm_source=twitter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://www.nwfdailynews.com/story/news/politics/2021/04/08/crestview-florida-billboard-claims-matt-gaetz-wants-date-your-child/7138781002/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> </sup><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/political-action-committees-pacs/mad-dog-pac/C00663211/donors/2020" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>8</sup></a> In a deposition as part of the NRA’s attempt to claim bankruptcy and move from New York to Texas, the association’s executive vice president, Wayne LaPierre, said that after the mass shootings at Sandy Hook Elementary School and a high school in Parkland, Florida, he feared so much for his safety that he took refuge on a friend’s yacht called <em>The Illusion</em>.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/546639-nras-lapierre-sought-refuge-on-yacht-after-shootings-thank-god-im-safe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a></sup> “This was the one place that I hoped could feel safe,” LaPierre said.</p>
<p>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration announced that despite a pandemic-driven reduction in greenhouse-gas emissions last year, atmospheric carbon dioxide reached its highest levels in the past 3.6 million years; the planet was 7 degrees warmer and sea levels were 80 feet higher when carbon-dioxide concentrations were most recently so high.<sup><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/climate-change-carbon-dioxide-highest-level-million-years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> In Taiwan, which is experiencing its worst drought in 56 years, a man was able to recover a cell phone he had dropped into Sun Moon Lake last year because the water level has decreased by nearly 40 feet.<sup><a href="https://www.shine.cn/news/nation/2104107245/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/taiwan-man-drops-iphone-in-lake-gets-it-back-after-a-year-it-still-works-101618030304408.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a></sup> “I had fish disappear,” said Reince Priebus, the former White House chief of staff who once acted out a script Donald Trump had written about winning the 2020 election, of his 200-gallon home aquarium.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/former-trump-officials-stick-around-washington/2021/04/05/19a627ae-9164-11eb-a74e-1f4cf89fd948_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://www.axios.com/trump-election-premeditated-lie-ebaf4a1f-46bf-4c37-ba0d-3ed5536ef537.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a></sup> The Brooklyn district attorney announced that he would move to dismiss as many as 90 previous drug convictions because a detective in the narcotics unit was charged with perjury.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/06/nyregion/brooklyn-criminal-convictions.html?campaign_id=9&amp;emc=edit_nn_20210407&amp;instance_id=28950&amp;nl=the-morning&amp;regi_id=92715581&amp;segment_id=55022&amp;te=1&amp;user_id=d82a0b4f5c6518303913d2a754464085" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> In the trial of Derek Chauvin, the Minneapolis police officer accused of killing George Floyd, a pulmonologist pinpointed the exact moment of Floyd’s death on video; in Oregon, one of only six states that originally refused to ratify the 15th Amendment, the House of Representatives unanimously approved a bill making Juneteenth a state holiday; and in Selma, Alabama, a group calling itself White Lies Matter stole a chair worth $500,000 from the United Daughters of the Confederacy and threatened to turn the seat into a toilet unless the UDC hung a banner with an Assata Shakur quote at its headquarters.<sup><a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/derek-chauvin-trial-week-2-takeaways_n_606f77d3c5b6616dcd7512ee" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a> <a href="https://www.opb.org/article/2021/04/09/oregon-lawmakers-house-vote-juneteenth-state-holiday/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a> <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2016/07/racist-history-portland/492035/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a href="https://www.al.com/news/2021/04/500000-confederate-chair-stolen-from-alabama-cemetery-used-as-toilet-will-be-returned-tonight-group-says.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> The White House announced that it would reverse a Trump-era policy and resume sending humanitarian aid to Palestinians, New York State announced a $2.1 billion fund to provide payments to undocumented residents excluded from past federal pandemic-relief legislation, and border agents announced that in March they had encountered nearly 19,000 children at the border, the largest number ever recorded in a single month.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/07/world/middleeast/biden-aid-palestinians.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/08/nyregion/covid-relief-undocumented-workers-nyc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/10/us/politics/biden-immigration.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>22</sup></a> A police officer in Kansas testified that the state’s Senate majority leader, Gene Suellentrop, had driven the wrong way with double the legal limit of alcohol in his blood, called the officer “donut boy,” and claimed that he could “take” the officer because he had played sports in high school.<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2021/04/09/gene-suellentrop-kansas-donut-boy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>23</sup></a></p>
<p>A Minnesota woman was fined after accidentally setting a swamp on fire while she was making maple syrup, and in Ontario, a couple making maple syrup accidentally exploded part of their porch after they left a propane burner on while they watched the sunset.<sup><a href="https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/minnesota-woman-sets-field-swamp-on-fire-in-maple-syrup-mishap-1.5378666" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> </sup><a href="https://www.baytoday.ca/local-news/maple-syrup-mishap-likely-cause-of-explosion-at-lakefront-home-3616992" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>25</sup></a> The Australian government announced that it has given up its goal of vaccinating the entire population by the end of the year, and that legislators, judges, and public servants will no longer be exempt from rules against sexual harassment in the workplace.<sup><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/health/australia-astrazeneca-vaccine-1.5983756" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a> <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/4/8/australia-to-end-sexual-harassment-exemption-for-politicians" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a> </sup>TUI Airways revealed that on a flight between Birmingham, England, and Majorca, Spain, it had underestimated by 2,600 pounds the amount of thrust needed for takeoff because its software system had automatically classified every passenger identified with the title “Miss” as a child, registering their weight as 77 pounds.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/09/tui-plane-serious-incident-every-miss-on-board-child-weight-birmingham-majorca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a></sup> The current Mrs. World was arrested after tearing a crown from the head of the winner of the Mrs. Sri Lanka pageant and falsely claiming on live TV that the woman, who was later hospitalized, was in fact divorced and thus ineligible for the competition.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/08/mrs-world-arrested-for-grabbing-crown-from-head-of-mrs-sri-lanka" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29</a></sup> The BBC received a record-breaking number of complaints for what viewers felt was excessive coverage of Prince Philip’s death.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/apr/12/bbcs-prince-philip-coverage-breaks-uk-tv-complaints-record" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a></sup> “Why [not] just put it on one channel for those that want to listen to that drivel and the rest of us can have a bit of music,” read one complaint.—<em>Cameron French</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-amazon-union-chauvin-trial-white-lies-matter-toilet/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Crow Whisperer]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/the-crow-whisperer/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/the-crow-whisperer/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 17:16:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">“S<em>ous les pavés, la plage</em>!” (“Beneath the pavement, the beach!”) was the rallying cry of the May 1968 protests in France. As demonstrators tore up paving stones in order to build barricades or to hurl at the police, they discovered that there was sand beneath the streets. Though this was a typical building practice, it reinforced the protesters’ belief that everyday life wasn’t quite what it appeared to be, but was rather an illusion manufactured by modernity, capitalism, and consumerism. During the early months of the pandemic, we were all confronted with the same truth. The levels of noise, garbage, and greenhouse-gas emissions pumped into the environment were drastically reduced because so many schools, workplaces, and restaurants were shuttered. Just as people abruptly changed where and how they spent their days, all sorts of wildlife began venturing into public places they’d previously avoided: deer roamed the streets of Paris while coyotes wandered around San Francisco. But these incursions weren’t really incursions at all: the natural world had been there all along. It became clear that animals, rather than living apart from human society, had always been living alongside us—our belief in absolute anthropocentric control was an illusion.</p>
<p>In “<a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/04/the-crow-whisperer-animal-communicators/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Crow Whisperer</a>,” which appeared in the April issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine, </em>Lauren Markham writes about the ways we might rethink our relationship with the environment. Following an incident involving some friends, their dog, and a murder of dive-bombing crows, Markham delves into the world of animal whisperers—specialists who serve as translators, negotiators, or arbiters between members of different species. In this episode of the podcast, <em>Harper’s </em>web editor Violet Lucca talks with Markham about the complexity of animal psychology, epigenetics, climate change, and a crow’s talent for nursing a grudge.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe title="The Crow Whisperer by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1028799556&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/the-crow-whisperer/" target="_blank">The Crow Whisperer</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-gaetzgate-derek-chauvin-trial-honor-of-kings/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-gaetzgate-derek-chauvin-trial-honor-of-kings/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 17:27:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">­It was reported that the Justice Department is investigating Representative Matt Gaetz of Florida, the chief opponent of a 2015 bill in the Florida state legislature that prohibited revenge porn, for violating federal sex-trafficking laws.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/30/us/politics/matt-gaetz-sex-trafficking-investigation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.orlandosentinel.com/news/os-ne-matt-gaetz-revenge-porn-20210405-5qbme6ilzna3rhry6gzqeevwpq-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> </sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/03/31/982909698/rep-gaetz-denies-allegation-claims-hes-victim-of-extortion-plot" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>3</sup></a> Mobile payment receipts show that Gaetz and Joel Greenberg, the former tax collector for Seminole County, Florida, who was indicted on charges of, among more than 30 other things, sex trafficking and the embezzlement of over $400,000 of COVID-19 relief funds for a cryptocurrency-mining operation, had transferred money as payment for sex into the accounts of women they had allegedly recruited online; the DOJ is also investigating whether Gaetz, Greenberg, and other members of their social circle had sex with a minor.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/02/us/politics/matt-gaetz-investigation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/apr/03/matt-gaetz-republican-sex-trafficking-scandal" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.orlandoweekly.com/Blogs/archives/2021/03/31/former-seminole-county-tax-collector-accused-of-embezzling-money-for-cryptocurrency-schemes-defrauding-covid-19-relief-programs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/01/us/politics/matt-gaetz-justice-department.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> Gaetz, who grew up in the house that served as the set of the 1998 film <em>The Truman Show,</em> denied the allegations on <em>Tucker Carlson Tonight, </em>in which he also asserted that Carlson, his wife, and one of the women involved in the case once had dinner together and that David McGee, a former federal prosecutor, had attempted to extort Gaetz’s father for $25 million in order to locate Robert A. Levinson, a former FBI agent who disappeared in 2007 during an unauthorized CIA mission to Iran, as well as to secure a pardon for the younger Gaetz.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2021/03/31/tucker-carlson-matt-gaetz-17/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://decider.com/2020/08/04/the-swamp-matt-gaetz-truman-show-house/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a></sup> “He threw Levinson and the entire Levinson family under the bus,” said Robert Kent, a former Air Force intelligence officer who, along with Stephen Alford, a real estate developer who was convicted of fraud, had asked Gaetz’s father for the money in order to search for Levinson, despite the fact that Levinson was officially declared dead by the Trump Administration last year; Kent claimed that he mentioned the federal investigation “not to extort” but because “he might be interested in doing something good.”<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/01/us/politics/matt-gaetz-justice-department.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> Donald Trump, a former friend of the convicted sex trafficker Jeffrey Epstein, allegedly said the Gaetz scandal seemed “really bad.”<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/donald-trump-and-jeffrey-epstein-partied-together-then-an-oceanfront-palm-beach-mansion-came-between-them/2019/07/31/79f1d98c-aca0-11e9-a0c9-6d2d7818f3da_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/trump-isn-t-coming-matt-012713263.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a></sup></p>
<p>During the first week of Derek Chauvin’s murder trial, the head of the homicide division of the Minneapolis Police Department testified that Chauvin’s decision to press his knee onto George Floyd’s neck after handcuffing him was “totally unnecessary,” a firefighter and certified EMT who was walking past the scene testified that she was told by police officers not to administer aid or check Floyd’s pulse, and the lead prosecutor revealed that Chauvin knelt on Floyd’s neck for nine minutes and twenty-nine seconds, rather than the eight minutes and forty-six seconds that was recorded.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/03/us/george-floyd-derek-chauvin-trial-weekly-wrap/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/02/us/george-floyd-derek-chauvin-trial-day-5/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a></sup> “It’s fair to say that you grew angrier and angrier,” Chauvin’s attorney asked one witness.<sup><a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/tasneemnashrulla/derek-chavin-trial-george-floyd-bystanders-videos" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> In the United Kingdom, thousands protested against a proposed law that would give police officers greater power to curb demonstrations by imposing time and noise limits, and a man in South London was stabbed to death at a vigil for a man who was stabbed to death.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-britain-politics-protests/scuffles-in-london-as-thousands-join-kill-the-bill-rallies-across-britain-idUSKBN2BQ007" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/apr/01/man-stabbed-death-vigil-knife-attack-victim-croydon" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> The Assistance Association for Political Prisoners reported that since the coup in Myanmar began, security forces have killed 550 people, 46 of whom were children, and Burmese authorities announced 20 warrants for social media influencers, models, and other celebrities who have spoken out against the military junta.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-myanmar-politics/myanmar-protesters-defy-crackdown-five-killed-junta-hunts-critics-idUSKBN2BQ031" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> </sup>Following criticism by Western fashion brands and social media influencers over the ongoing genocide in Xinjiang, the Chinese province that produces a fifth of the world’s cotton, the Chinese company Tencent removed custom Burberry skins from its video game <em>Honor of Kings.</em><sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/29/style/china-cotton-uyghur-hm-nike.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup></p>
<p>In Ohio, a 57-year-old manufacturing plant employee was arrested after she texted her sister that a man who had been fired the day before had returned with a gun, which was an April Fools’ Day joke.<sup><a href="https://www.10tv.com/article/news/local/ohio/ohio-worker-charged-in-april-fools-day-text-about-active-shooter/530-91c9e6fa-ad0a-4a21-aeb0-1d231fa8edca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> Fifteen million Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccines were ruined after a facility in Baltimore accidentally mixed them with ingredients for the AstraZeneca vaccine.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/31/us/politics/johnson-johnson-coronavirus-vaccine.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></sup> It was reported that New York governor Andrew Cuomo negotiated a $4 million book advance while his aides were covering up COVID-19 death tolls in nursing homes, and that Hunter Biden’s memoir begins with his recollection of watching Matt Gaetz mockingly read an account of his drug abuse into the record of the House Judiciary Committee’s first impeachment trial of Donald Trump.<sup><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/cuomo-new-york-nursing-home-death-toll-book-covid-coronavirus-2021-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/03/opinion/matt-gaetz-hunter-biden-memoir.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup>—<em>Jensen Davis</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-gaetzgate-derek-chauvin-trial-honor-of-kings/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Possessed]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/philip-roth-joshua-cohen-blake-bailey-biography/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/philip-roth-joshua-cohen-blake-bailey-biography/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 14:12:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">This month will see the release of Blake Bailey’s <em>Philip Roth: The Biography</em>—the authorized biography of the famous novelist, who died in 2018. Roth himself selected Bailey to write his life story. In addition to many long conversations, Roth granted Bailey complete access to his personal archives and helped set up interviews with many of his friends, lovers, and colleagues.</p>
<p>In the March issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine,</em> the novelist and <em>Harper’s </em>contributing editor Joshua Cohen imagines how Bailey’s book might be received by Roth himself. From the comfort of his writing studio beyond the grave, Cohen’s Roth ruminates on the strange, perhaps self-destructive decision to commission his own biography, and proceeds to lament the result, which, he argues, downplays the literary production that made up most of his days (“MY BIOGRAPHER HAS NO INTEREST IN MY WRITING!!!!”) in favor of “interminable chapters and decades of reputation management, alternating with, if not relieved by, sexual transgressions.” Cohen’s ventriloquism of Roth is a gambit one has to think the author would have admired. As Cohen points out in this interview, Roth, too, had a penchant for throwing his voice.</p>
<p>In this episode of the podcast, Violet Lucca talks with Cohen about Philip Roth’s long career and his unclear legacy. Among other things, they discuss Roth’s late decree that “the book can’t compete with the screen”; his often unacknowledged influence on today’s American immigrant writers, as well as writers of autofiction; and an afterlife—or do we find ourselves there now?—in which everything will be as it is, just a little different.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe title="The Possessed by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1020351658&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/philip-roth-joshua-cohen-blake-bailey-biography/" target="_blank">The Possessed</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-ever-given-suez-canal-myanmar-election-integrity-act/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-ever-given-suez-canal-myanmar-election-integrity-act/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 20:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The <em>Ever Given,</em> a Taiwanese-operated, Japanese-owned, Panamanian-flagged container ship headed from China to the Netherlands, became wedged across the Suez Canal, blocking an artery that accounts for about 12 percent of world trade and causing an hourly loss of $400 million.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/03/27/africa/suez-canal-ship-refloat-attempt-intl/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/cargo-ship-stuck-suez-canal-egypt-d8b6696716ab45794cba583ecf0e4001" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/25/suez-canal-blockage-is-delaying-an-estimated-400-million-an-hour-in-goods.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> The ship, which is widely speculated to include boxes of Hideous Abomination, a Kickstarter-funded board game in which players compete to construct surprising monsters, was freed after six days, thanks in large part to the sun and moon.<sup><a href="https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2021/03/ever-given-suez-canal-board-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/29/world/suez-canal-ship.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> On Myanmar’s Armed Forces Day, military generals attended a red-carpet gala, and that night members of the military shot and killed a women’s-rights activist, a snack vendor, a futsal goalkeeper, and more than 110 others, including many young children, in the most brutal episode of violence since the military junta deposed the National League for Democracy in early February; victims’ families were told that they would have to sign a letter affirming that the military was not responsible for the deaths in order to retrieve the bodies of their loved ones.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-56547381" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/3/27/myanmar-coup-leaders-put-on-show-of-force" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-56557683" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/w172x2z86grdfbg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a></sup> “There is no influx of refugees yet. We asked those who crossed to Thailand if they have any problem in their area. When they say no problem, we just asked them to return to their land first. We asked, we did not use any force,” said the Thai prime minister, Prayuth Chan-ocha, after people from Myanmar fleeing government bombs were sent back.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/world-news-myanmar-coronavirus-pandemic-prayuth-chan-ocha-thailand-5d9648cbe0009571b8ac80ca1790959f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> A Canadian professor tried to deny a student living in Myanmar an extension on a statistics midterm despite the country’s communications blackout.<sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/professor-rejects-exam-delay-student-182443410.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a></sup> “Even the Internet came down with COVID-19?” the professor wrote in an email.</p>
<p>Sitting beneath a painting of a slave plantation, Georgia governor Brian Kemp signed the Election Integrity Act as officers arrested the state representative Park Cannon, who is black, for knocking on the door to Kemp’s office; provisions in the act add new ID requirements for absentee ballots and criminalize the distribution of free food and water to citizens standing in line to vote.<sup><a href="https://www.inquirer.com/opinion/georgia-governor-brian-kemp-painting-slave-plantation-20210326.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2021/03/disturbing-black-georgia-lawmakers-react-to-arrest-of-colleague-park-cannon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://www.gpb.org/news/2021/03/26/what-does-georgias-new-voting-law-sb-202-do" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a></sup> The Florida House approved a bill that would punish nonviolent protesters, allow anti-protester vigilantes to dodge civil liability, outlaw police divestment, and make damaging or destroying memorials, including Confederate flags, felonious.<sup><a href="https://www.wtxl.com/news/local-news/florida-house-approves-hb-1-anti-riot-bill" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a> <a href="https://www.aclufl.org/en/written-testimony-oppose-hb-1-and-sb-484-anti-protest-bill" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> A South Carolina senator inaccurately argued that the District of Columbia does not deserve statehood in part because of a lack of car dealerships, of which it has 91, and a South Carolina state senator proposed that all adult South Carolinians form a militia.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/03/22/politics/fact-check-jody-hice-car-dealerships-dc-statehood/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a> <a href="https://dmv.dc.gov/publication/dmv-active-dealers-list" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/sc-state-senator-tom-corbin-everyone-militia-member-b24c74c587b75cb57ff78bb8f5ec8120" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> “Y’all, this country is crazy,” a South Carolina state congressman said in response. After triggering two fire alarms, an illegally installed communal popcorn machine was removed from the North Dakota State Capitol.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/popcorn-machine-triggers-alarms-north-dakota-capitol-42495811d5abfc332671e33f41a00e20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> The state’s House majority leader said, “Popcorn cheers people up for a reason. And now it’s gone, and that’s the way it goes.” The United States fell 11 places below its 2010 position, to just below Argentina and Mongolia, on a watchdog’s annual ranking of countries according to political rights and civil liberties; worldwide, freedom declined for the fifteenth consecutive year.<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/mar/24/us-world-democracy-rankings-freedom-house-new-low" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></p>
<p>A San Francisco consulting startup hired Prince Harry as its chief impact officer, and a Turkish cosmetic-surgery company determined that Prince William had been described online as sexy more often than any other bald man.<sup><a href="https://www.sfgate.com/news/article/Prince-Harry-takes-a-job-at-Silicon-Valley-startup-16046307.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> <a href="https://www.indy100.com/people/prince-william-sexiest-bald-google-b1823326?utm_content=Echobox&amp;utm_medium=Social&amp;utm_source=Twitter#Echobox=1616846648" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> A former chairman of Goldman Sachs bought a $51 million Upper East Side mansion formerly owned by Jeffrey Epstein, and Goldman Sachs employees will no longer be allowed to work between Friday evenings and Sunday mornings “except in certain circumstances.”<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/22/realestate/jeffrey-epstein-nyc-mansion.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> </sup><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jackkelly/2021/03/23/after-complaints-of-100-hour-workweeks-goldman-sachs-is-allowing-bankers-to-take-off-on-saturdays/?sh=281f93c56af6" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>25</sup></a> “You don’t really believe the peeing in bottles thing, do you?” tweeted an Amazon spokesperson as the company’s workers voted to unionize in Alabama, went on strike in Italy, and planned strikes in Germany and India.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/media/544867-amazon-responds-to-dem-lawmaker-you-dont-really-believe-the-peeing-in-bottles" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a> <a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/we-are-getting-less-money-after-working-more-why-amazon-drivers-are-going-on-strike-in-india/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-germany-strike-idUSKBN2BK0GU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a> </sup>Texas revised its winter-storm death toll upward by nearly 50 percent; Mexico revised its COVID-19 death toll upward by 60 percent.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/03/26/981594093/texas-death-toll-in-februarys-winter-storm-nearly-doubles-to-111" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-56558059" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a></sup> In New South Wales, Australia, the worst flooding in decades forced tens of thousands to evacuate, and at least three hospital patients were bitten in the largest mice plague in decades.<sup><a href="https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/images/148093/historic-floods-in-new-south-wales" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a> <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/worst-mice-plague-in-decades-swarms-across-new-south-wales-as-three-hospital-patients-are-bitten-12250474" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a></sup> After being hoisted out of a drain, a Florida woman claimed to have survived for three weeks while lost in the sewers on nothing more than a can of ginger ale.<sup><a href="https://weartv.com/news/local/florida-woman-says-she-lived-off-ginger-ale-while-stuck-in-sewer-system-for-3-weeks" target="_blank" rel="noopener">33</a></sup> NASA announced that an asteroid previously feared to be on a collision course with Earth will miss<em>.</em><sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/science-asteroids-4ebc6f2807a4c59f859b1292875ae1d4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">34</a></sup><em>—Jordan Cutler-Tietjen</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-ever-given-suez-canal-myanmar-election-integrity-act/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pafko at the Wall]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/pafko-at-the-wall-don-delillo-jennifer-egan-rowan-ricardo-phillips/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/pafko-at-the-wall-don-delillo-jennifer-egan-rowan-ricardo-phillips/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 04:01:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">“Sometime in late 1991,” Don DeLillo told a <em>Paris Review</em> interviewer in 1993, “I started writing something new and didn’t know what it would be—a novel, a short story, a long story. It was simply a piece of writing, and it gave me more pleasure than any other writing I’ve done.” The result was the novella “Pafko at the Wall,” first published as a <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/1992/10/pafko-at-the-wall/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Folio</a> in the October 1992 issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine,</em> making up a third of the issue’s length. “Wherein the Giants clinch the pennant, Bruegel descends, a bomb explodes, Sinatra sulks, and a Harlem boy plays his own game,” read that month’s cover. A slightly revised version would later become the prologue to <em>Underworld,</em> a novel often described as DeLillo’s masterpiece.</p>
<p>The story takes place during the National League playoff game of October 3, 1951, when Bobby Thomson of the New York Giants hit a pennant-winning home run over the head of Brooklyn Dodgers left fielder Andy Pafko—an event known to baseball fans as the “Shot Heard ’Round the World.” Here, though, the famous game serves mostly as background, its action serving to repeatedly bounce the reader’s attention back into the stands. DeLillo, a writer who has always been fascinated by the mechanics of spectacle, wants us to watch the watchers—some of whom, such as Frank Sinatra, the radio announcer Russ Hodges, and FBI director J. Edgar Hoover, are spectacle makers (and manipulators) themselves. Hovering over the proceedings, meanwhile, are suggestions of darker energy: the secret knowledge, possessed by only the paranoid Hoover, that the Soviets have just performed a successful nuclear-weapons test, and racial tensions, briefly transcended by fandom, that are unloosed in the scramble over a suddenly famous ball.</p>
<p>In this episode of the podcast, we bring you excerpts of “Pafko at the Wall,” which was performed live at the 92nd Street Y by Billy Crudup, Zachary Levi, and Tony Shalhoub, interspersed with commentary by the novelist Jennifer Egan and the poet Rowan Ricardo Phillips. The full recording of the performance will be released on March 30 by Simon &amp; Schuster Audio. A video of the performance will be available for two days at <a href="https://92y.org/pafko"><u>92y.org/pafko</u></a> beginning on Sunday, March 28, in anticipation of the audiobook’s release.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe title="Pafko at the Wall by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1016380741&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/pafko-at-the-wall-don-delillo-jennifer-egan-rowan-ricardo-phillips/" target="_blank">Pafko at the Wall</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>