<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Harper's Magazine</title>
        <link>https://harpers.org/</link>
        <description>null</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 19:52:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/ruicosta042/rssconv-action</generator>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-cash-bail-biden-syria-ted-cruz/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-cash-bail-biden-syria-ted-cruz/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 19:52:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Illinois governor J. B. Pritzker signed a law ending cash bail and requiring police officers across the state to wear body cameras; the bill will take effect in 2023.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/23/us/illinois-cash-bail-pritzker.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a></sup> In Rochester, New York, a grand jury declined to charge any of the seven officers who were on the scene last March when they handcuffed Daniel Prude, placed a mesh bag over his head, and pressed him into the pavement until he lost consciousness; Prude, who was black, was experiencing a suspected psychotic episode and died a week after the incident.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/23/nyregion/daniel-prude-rochester-police.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> “We certainly do not want people to misinterpret the officers’ actions and conflate this incident with any recent killings of unarmed Black men by law enforcement nationally,” wrote a Rochester deputy police chief who advised against releasing body-cam footage of the incident. An American soldier who was indicted for conspiring with neo-Nazis to ambush his unit during a planned deployment to Turkey asked for the case to be dismissed because the grand jury didn’t include enough black and Hispanic members.<sup><a href="https://www.stripes.com/news/us/soldier-indicted-for-conspiring-with-neo-nazi-group-seeks-dismissal-because-grand-jury-wasn-t-racially-diverse-1.663177" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a></sup> The U.S. government released a four-page report concluding that Mohammed bin Salman, the crown prince of Saudi Arabia, had personally authorized the dismemberment of Jamal Khashoggi inside the Saudi Consulate in Istanbul, and announced sanctions against the Saudis involved in the killing except for the crown prince.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/26/us/politics/jamal-khashoggi-killing-cia-report.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a></sup> Russian diplomats escaped from North Korea on a hand-pushed railcar, and after a refugee set herself on fire, Greek officials charged her with arson.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/feb/26/russian-diplomats-leave-north-korea-on-hand-powered-rail-trolley-video" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://lenexweb.com/refugee-who-set-herself-on-fire-in-greece-is-charged-with-arson/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a> </sup>The Chinese government planned to restrict political candidates in Hong Kong to those it deems “patriots.”<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/23/world/asia/china-hong-kong-elections.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a></sup></p>
<p>In the first known use of military force by the Biden Administration, seven 500-pound bombs were dropped in Syria to retaliate against rocket attacks from an Iran-backed Iraqi militia; the attack killed 22 people, though international monitoring groups dispute how many of the dead belonged to the group being targeted.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/feb/25/us-airstrike-syria-iran-militia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a></sup> The U.S. Senate parliamentarian judged that a federal minimum-wage hike could not be passed under budget-reconciliation rules because it does not affect the national debt; the White House chose not to challenge the ruling.<sup><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/27/stimulus-update-house-passes-bidens-1point9-trillion-covid-bill-heres-whats-next.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a></sup> A new poll found that 20 percent of Americans would dump their partner in exchange for the ability to travel immediately.<sup><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/travel/news/2021/02/23/trivago-poll-38-percent-of-americans-would-give-up-sex-to-travel-again/4553545001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10</a></sup> The U.S. Food and Drug Administration approved a new one-shot COVID-19 vaccine from Johnson and Johnson, which announced that it would begin testing the efficacy of its vaccine on, among other age groups, newborns, and an elementary school student with COVID-like symptoms was placed in isolation inside a storage closet because of spacing limitations.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/02/28/world/covid-19-coronavirus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11</a> <a href="https://www.fox32chicago.com/news/symptomatic-south-carolina-elementary-student-who-visited-school-nurse-was-held-in-storage-closet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a></sup> Boston Dynamics, a company originally funded by the military but now attempting to expand into the civilian market, condemned a performance-art piece in which attendees will be able to remotely drive Spot, one of the company’s quadruped robots, around an art gallery while it is outfitted with a paintball gun on its back.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56182268" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a></sup> “They said they would give us another two Spots for free if we took the gun off. That just made us want to do this even more,” wrote one of the artists, who referred to the robots as “war dogs.” In India, a man died after being stabbed in the groin by his rooster after he had attached a knife to the bird for an illegal cockfight, and a university exam was postponed after it was revealed that the curriculum attributed special abilities to Indian cows as compared with foreign ones, such as that they have deeper emotions and that their dung can reduce radiation.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-56224144" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14</a> <a href="https://bdnews24.com/neighbours/2021/02/23/do-indias-cows-have-special-powers-government-curriculum-is-ridiculed" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a></sup></p>
<p>During Ted Cruz’s speech at the Conservative Political Action Conference in Orlando, Florida, where two men pushed a golden statue of Donald Trump down the halls of the Hyatt Regency hotel, the Texas senator promoted his podcast, criticized government public-health advisories regarding COVID-19, assured the crowd that the actress Gina Carano was “standing with us,” claimed that 60 percent of women named Karen had definitely voted for Joe Biden, and said that “Orlando is awesome. It’s not as nice as Cancún—but it’s nice!”<sup><a href="https://rev.com/blog/transcripts/ted-cruz-2021-cpac-speech-transcript-february-26" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/feb/26/trump-golden-statue-cpac-conference" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>17</sup></a> A plastic surgeon in California joined his traffic-court hearing via Zoom from the operating room, at one point showing a patient on the operating table.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/28/us/california-surgeon-zoom-traffic-violation-court.html?action=click&amp;module=Latest&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a></sup> “Yes, I’m in an operating room right now,” said the surgeon. “I’m available for trial. Go right ahead.” The University of Michigan closed and then reopened one of its libraries after discovering three venomous Mediterranean recluse spiders in the basement.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/venomous-spiders-michigan-library-636de89af9fc0dcafe7f040292083664" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a></sup>—<em>Cameron French</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-cash-bail-biden-syria-ted-cruz/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The New McCarthyism]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/the-new-mccarthyism-2/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/the-new-mccarthyism-2/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 22:52:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<div style="width: 200px; border: 1px solid black; background-color: white; margin-left: 30px; padding: 30px; padding-bottom: 30px; float: right; font-size: 90%;">A <a href="https://www.ledevoir.com/opinion/chroniques/596074/chronique-le-nouveau-maccarthysme" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">version</a> of this column originally ran in <em>Le Devoir</em> on March 1, 2021. Translated from the French by John Cullen.</div>
<p class="drop-cap">The escalating lunacy of what is considered the politically correct code of conduct, temporarily suspended during the American presidential campaign, firmly reinstated itself last month in the messy “McNeil–<em>New York Times</em> affair,” and everyone who’s concerned for the future of free speech in the United States should take note of this.</p>
<p>Regrettably, the <em>Times</em>’s dismissal of the journalist Donald McNeil Jr.—for the crime of having uttered the word “nigger” in front of some high school students more than a year ago, during a trip to Peru organized by the newspaper—isn’t a scandal glamorous enough to arouse a level of interest equivalent to the persecution of Émile Zola in the late nineteenth-century for defending Captain Alfred Dreyfus. According to my sources, McNeil is simply a good journalist with a difficult personality (one of his former colleagues described him to me as “a porcupine”). Despite his alleged antisocial behavior, McNeil has won numerous prizes over the course of his long career; more recently he has specialized in subjects related to health and science, including the AIDS virus, Zika, and COVID-19. In the summer of 2019, invited to serve as a guide for the students on their Peruvian journey, he became involved in a discussion about presumed racism in a student video. McNeil insists on the fact that he used “the N-word” in the discussion as information and not as a slur. The students, all of them white, apparently failed to appreciate McNeil’s incorrect choice of words. In late January 2021, the <em>Daily Beast</em> published an article that revealed how angry some of the students were at McNeil for his use of the word as well as for other remarks of his that they considered insensitive. The revelations caused outrage among many <em>Times </em>staffers, and pressure mounted until McNeil “resigned.” (For a fuller account of the dispute between McNeil and the <em>Times, </em>see McNeil’s <a href="https://donaldgmcneiljr1954.medium.com/">Medium posts</a>.)</p>
<p>And there we have it, McCarthyism and mob rule firmly in place at the newspaper of record. McNeil has now been branded a “racist,” in much the same way as in the 1950s Joseph McCarthy and his allies branded people “reds,” even though a great number of them had renounced Marxist ideology and had quit the Communist Party. It mattered little that the <em>Times</em>’s editor-in-chief, Dean Baquet, was obliged to take back an earlier public statement in which he foolishly declared, “We do not tolerate racist language regardless of intent.” After having thought about this statement for a few days, Baquet admitted his error and noted that “Of course intent matters when we are talking about language in journalism.” During Baquet’s period of reflection, though, <em>Times</em> columnist Bret Stephens had written a piece critical of Baquet that included this assertion: “Every serious moral philosophy, every decent legal system and every ethical organization cares deeply about intention.” It was out of the question that such a heretical idea would be published in the <em>Times</em>. But you can read <a href="https://nypost.com/2021/02/11/read-the-column-the-new-york-times-didnt-want-you-read/">Stephens’s article</a> in Rupert Murdoch’s <em>New York Post</em><em>,</em> to which the piece was leaked. We have reached the height of irony when the plutocratic ogre Murdoch and his tabloid newspaper have become the keepers of the liberal flame.</p>
<p>The McNeil affair serves to underline an accelerating tendency in the media, as in the society at large, to conduct moral witch hunts based on identity politics. Instead of communists, the hunters pursue racists and sexual predators. There’s no proof that McNeil is in fact a racist, but the accusation will stick to him for a long time, and like the leftist Hollywood screenwriters of the 1950s who were blacklisted for their support of communism, he’ll have trouble finding new employment. His denunciation by young students also recalls the China of Mao Zedong and his fanatical Red Guards, who tormented their insufficiently revolutionary elders. What’s even worse is McNeil’s pathetic “confession,” which is very 1930s Moscow. I’ll quote part of it: “To understand what was in the video, I . . . used the slur itself. I should not have done that. Originally, I thought the context in which I used this ugly word could be defended . . . The fact that I even thought I could defend it itself showed extraordinarily bad judgment.” Really? Since the year 2000, the <em>Times</em> has published “the N-word” 247 times.</p>
<p>Obviously, this is not to say that a New Stalinism is on the rise. Nevertheless, the normally healthy call for racial justice and equality has been contorted by incessant appeals to “diversity,” a word that has been drained of any meaning these days. Will establishing quotas for such and such a number of Blacks, Latinos, Asians, and women improve the sorry state of American journalism? Does an excellent journalist who happens to be white and male deserve to be sacrificed for the advancement of minorities? While the mainstream media scramble to augment their “diversity,” our industry is sinking dramatically in the face of the real danger: GAFAM’s massive theft of our content and our advertising revenue.</p>
<p>The underlying context of this crisis is the timidity and conformism of our intellectual culture. At the present moment, what’s missing from our media is a diversity of viewpoints. Tocqueville noticed this tendency to uniformity at the time of his tour of the United States in 1831–1832: “In America, the majority draws an intimidating circle around thought. Within those limits, a writer is free; but woe to him if he dares to step over the line. It’s not that he must live in terror of an auto-da-fé, but he is subjected to every sort of vileness and to daily persecutions . . . At length he yields, bent under the effort each day requires, and subsides into silence, as if feeling remorse for having spoken the truth.”</p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/the-new-mccarthyism-2/" target="_blank">The New McCarthyism</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-texas-blackout-ted-cruz-facebook-vaccine/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-texas-blackout-ted-cruz-facebook-vaccine/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 18:35:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The United States surpassed 500,000 COVID-19 deaths, and nearly every state experienced freezing temperatures.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-usa/bells-toll-for-lives-lost-as-u-s-reaches-500000-covid-deaths-idUSKBN2AM1Y4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/02/15/us/winter-storm-weather-live" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>2</sup></a> In Texas, the cold weather caused pipes to freeze and burst, and the increase in electricity usage overwhelmed the state’s power grid, leaving millions of Texans without power and potable water and driving a 27-year-old father to burn a baby gate for warmth.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2021/02/16/winter-storm-live-updates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/snowy-bbqs-burning-baby-gates-texas-tiktokers-capture-historic-storm-n1258383" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a> </sup>Senator Ted Cruz traveled to Cancún with his wife and daughters to meet his college roommate David Panton because, as Cruz later explained, he wanted to “be a good dad”; following widespread criticism, Cruz returned to Texas, apologized while wearing a state-flag face mask, and posted photographs of himself handing out bottled water to Texans.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/18/us/politics/ted-cruz-storm-cancun.html?auth=link-dismiss-google1tap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://www.axios.com/ted-cruz-cancun-college-roommate-birthday-ef53416b-9fec-4a71-912c-7c6dd83397f4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a> <a href="https://people.com/politics/ted-cruz-hands-out-water-in-texas-after-mexico-trip-backlash/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ted-cruz-mexico-vacation-amid-storm-b0cdc326db95bf25d93de9e877e05862" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a> </sup>“I didn’t want all the screaming and yelling about this trip to distract even one moment from the real issues that I think Texans care about, which is keeping all of our families safe,” the senator said. During an interview on the invite-only app Clubhouse, an Instagram influencer—whom opposition leader Alexei Navalny alleges is a daughter of Vladimir Putin—said that she believes the Kremlin has the right to poison people because the Illuminati created COVID-19.<sup><a href="https://www.znak.com/2021-02-17/predpolagaemaya_dochka_putina_poobchalas_s_avtorom_rassledovaniya_o_ney_v_clubhouse" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a> </sup><a href="https://twitter.com/maxseddon/status/1361939143379533827?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>10</sup></a> Navalny’s appeal of his prison sentence was denied, and he was fined for slander.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-russia-politics-navalny/kremlin-critic-navalny-loses-appeal-against-jail-term-idUSKBN2AK08Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11</a></sup></p>
<p>A man at a quarantine hotel in Thailand was threatened with a defamation suit after he posted photographs of cockroach legs he had found in his macaroni.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/19/world/worst-14-days-of-my-life-complaints-about-a-thai-hotel-quarantine-lead-to-a-defamation-threat.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a></sup> The Cambodian government, which in December jailed a woman for wearing a revealing outfit while livestreaming a clothing-and-makeup sale on Facebook, announced plans to implement a national internet gateway that, in addition to restricting access to certain websites, will require users to complete identification forms before going online.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-women-cambodia-facebook-trfn-idUSKCN226240?edition-redirect=uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a> </sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cambodia-internet/cambodias-new-china-style-internet-gateway-decried-as-repression-tool-idUSKBN2AI140" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>14</sup></a> Facebook, which has been blocking pro-vaccine advertisements as part of its attempts to stop the spread of anti-vaccine content, prohibited the sharing of all news articles in Australia after the lower house of its Parliament passed legislation that would require the company to pay media companies for links to their coverage.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/feb/18/prime-minister-scott-morrison-attacks-facebook-for-arrogant-move-to-unfriend-australia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/feb/16/google-and-facebook-the-landmark-australian-law-that-will-make-them-pay-for-news-content" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/02/21/facebook-ad-pro-vaccine-ban-470304" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a></sup> Google fired a second prominent AI ethicist for “exfiltration of confidential business-sensitive documents and private data of other employees.”<sup><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/4fbebc3a-d714-4d79-9805-613303a29420" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a></sup> “It gives me the evil eye every time I leave home,” said Yevgenia Kvasova of the House of Soviets building in Kaliningrad, Russia, that has been scheduled for demolition because of structural defects.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/16/world/europe/kaliningrad-russia-soviet-union-house-of-soviets.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a></sup> A drug-sniffing dog discovered 44 pounds of cornflakes coated with sugar and cocaine that were en route to Hong Kong.<sup><a href="https://www.cincinnati.com/story/news/local/hamiltoncounty/2021/02/19/frosting-cereal-flakes-cocaine-say-federal-agents-cincinnati/4512513001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a></sup></p>
<p>The Miss India 2020 runner-up rode to a victory rally at her alma mater in her father’s auto rickshaw.<sup><a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/miss-india-runner-up-manya-singh-goes-on-a-victory-rally-in-her-fathers-autorickshaw/article33868497.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21</a></sup> The luxury fashion brand Proenza Schouler cast Kamala Harris’s stepdaughter in its runway show, held in the Hamptons, because she represents “a whole new chapter” in American life; Hermès reported a 43 percent increase in sales in Asia; and a shopping-mall baron predicted that housebound consumers will soon begin “revenge shopping.”<sup><a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/story/2021-02-19/ella-emhoff-proenza-schouler-nyfw-fashion-show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a> <a href="https://www.pymnts.com/news/retail/2021/hermes-q4-results-outpace-luxury-rivals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/business-news/revenge-spending-vaccinations-could-bring-millions-shoppers-back-mall-will-n1257993" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24</a></sup> San Francisco plastic surgeons reported an increasing demand for smaller breast sizes, and the American Society for Dermatologic Surgery released a statement warning those who have had their lips injected with filler to exercise caution with the COVID-19 vaccine because it can cause temporary lip swelling.<sup><a href="https://sanfrancisco.cbslocal.com/2021/02/18/explant-expansion-plastic-surgeons-see-growing-demand-to-shrink-breast-size/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a> <a href="https://www.dermatologytimes.com/view/guidelines-address-covid-19-vaccine-concerns-related-to-dermal-fillers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">26</a></sup> “This [vaccine] is the hottest commodity that is out there right now,” said a health official in Orange County, Florida, where young women were caught attempting to receive shots while “dressed up as grannies,” and in Manatee County, Florida, a pop-up vaccination site with a “VIP list” was constructed for people living in its two richest zip codes.<sup><a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/nation-world/two-young-women-in-florida-dressed-up-as-grannies-to-get-vaccinated-health-official-says/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">27</a> </sup><a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2021/02/18/politics/manatee-county-vaccine/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>28</sup></a> Mercedes-Benz recalled 1,292,258 cars in the United States because the eCall feature sent inaccurate vehicle locations to emergency responders.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56071108" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">29</a></sup> A butane tank exploded inside a Texas Walmart and forced shoppers to evacuate the store; customers were permitted to reenter one hour later.<sup><a href="https://www.krgv.com/news/fiery-shopping-cart-prompts-evacuation-at-palmhurst-walmart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">30</a></sup>—<em>Jensen Davis</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-texas-blackout-ted-cruz-facebook-vaccine/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-second-impeachment-star-spangled-banner-act/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-second-impeachment-star-spangled-banner-act/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:55:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Former president Donald Trump was acquitted at the conclusion of his second impeachment trial; falling short of a two-thirds majority, the Senate voted by a 57–43 margin to convict him of inciting an insurrection on January 6 at the U.S. Capitol.<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/trump-acquitted-impeachment-riot/2021/02/13/dbf6b172-6e12-11eb-ba56-d7e2c8defa31_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>1</sup></a> “There’s no question—none—that President Trump is practically and morally responsible for provoking the events of the day,” said the Senate minority leader, Mitch McConnell, several minutes after voting to acquit Trump.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/13/us/mcconnell-trump-impeachment-acquittal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> The majority leader of the Michigan Senate—who had called the Capitol riot a “hoax from day one” and described it as “staged”—apologized and then was captured on a hot mic saying, “I frankly don’t take back any of the points I was trying to make.”<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/10/politics/mike-shirkey-hot-mic/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>3</sup></a> Tennessee lawmakers introduced legislation that would allow men to prevent women they impregnate from receiving abortions; an Iowa state legislator put forward a bill permitting disabled Iowans to hunt from motorized scooters; and the Texas lieutenant governor, Dan Patrick, after learning that the NBA’s Dallas Mavericks had gone 13 games without playing the national anthem, announced that he would prioritize passage of the Star Spangled Banner Protection Act, which would require the song to be played before “all events that receive public funding.”<sup><a href="https://lawandcrime.com/abortion/tennessee-legislator-who-suggested-white-people-may-become-slaves-one-day-introduces-bill-allowing-men-to-stop-abortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a> <a href="https://iowacapitaldispatch.com/2021/02/11/bill-would-allow-disabled-iowans-to-hunt-from-motorized-scooters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2021/02/10/dallas-mavericks-texas-national-anthem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a></sup> “We ARE the land of free [<em>sic</em>],” Patrick noted on Twitter.</p>
<p>It was reported that Trump had been on the verge of being put on a ventilator when he was infected with COVID-19 in October; Representative Ron White of Texas became the first sitting congressman to die of the disease; and scientists identified seven different variants of the virus around the United States.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/11/us/politics/trump-coronavirus.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-rep-ron-wright-dies-of-covid-19-11612803373?mod=itp_wsj&amp;ru=yahoo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/02/14/world/covid-19-coronavirus/a-new-study-identifies-seven-us-virus-variants-with-the-same-worrying-mutation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a></sup> The city of Seoul began offering free COVID-19 tests to cats and dogs. Daniel Kritenbrink, the U.S. ambassador to Vietnam, released a rap song in which he refers to himself as “the boy from Hanoi” and professes fondness for the city’s “hot spots and hot pots,” as well as <em>cà phê s&#7919;a &#273;á,</em> a traditional iced coffee drink.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-55991097" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/feb/09/boy-from-hanoi-us-ambassador-to-vietnam-releases-his-own-lunar-new-year-rap">11</a></sup> The Philadelphia police union demanded a 5 percent “accountability pay” salary increase in exchange for agreeing to wear body cameras, and a Beverly Hills police officer was accused of playing music by the Nineties ska-punk band Sublime while being filmed by a civilian so that the video would be subject to copyright infringement charges if it were posted on social media.<sup><a href="https://www.inquirer.com/news/philadelphia-police-contract-discipline-reform-accountability-20210209.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a> <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/bvxb94/is-this-beverly-hills-cop-playing-sublimes-santeria-to-avoid-being-livestreamed" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a></sup> New Zealand’s Parliament amended its dress code after the co-leader of the M&#257;ori Party likened neckties to “a colonial noose.”<sup><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/new-zealands-parliament-drops-tie-rule-after-maori-lawmaker-rawiri-waititi-ejected-11612963959?mod=itp_wsj&amp;ru=yahoo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14</a></sup></p>
<p>A mathematics professor at the National University of Singapore delivered a nearly two-hour online lecture while on mute, a Minnesota congressman entered an online meeting of the House Financial Services Committee upside down, and a Texas prosecutor partook in a Zoom hearing while equipped with a filter that made him appear to be a kitten.<sup><a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/singapore-professor-takes-class-for-two-hours-only-to-realise-it-was-on-mute-whole-time-7181499/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/10/politics/congress-tom-emmer-upside-down/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/desktop-source-zoom-cat-filter-lawyer-3281ef443178a8f8ed889be7dcbeee75" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a></sup> A survey of graves at the nation’s oldest continuously operating pet cemetery found that the most popular pet name of the last century was Princess.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/12/style/pet-names-most-popular.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a></sup> A Tennessee border collie named Lulu inherited $5 million, and Yorkshire and Panepinto micropigs learned how to play video games, though researchers noted that their ability fell short of “full mastery.”<sup><a href="https://www.newschannel5.com/news/8-year-old-border-collie-named-lulu-inherits-5-million-in-owners-will" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a> <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/scientists-teach-pigs-how-to-play-a-video-game-and-pigs-are-good-at-it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a></sup> The video-game publisher Victura announced the development of a previously canceled “tactical shooter” called <em>Six Days in Fallujah,</em> reassuring customers that it was not a U.S. Army recruitment tool, and the arms manufacturer Kalashnikov announced production of a “gadget” shotgun with a built-in computer that would be marketed to “hipsters.”<sup><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/six-days-in-fallujah-publisher-insists-the-game-is-not-a-us-army-recruiting-tool" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21</a> <a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2021/02/09/kalashnikov-maker-targets-hipsters-with-gadget-gun-a72874" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a></sup> Scientists determined that the songs of fin whales could be used to map the ocean floor, and a musician managed to play C, C-sharp, and D notes on a 17,000-year-old wind instrument made from a conch shell that was discovered in a French cave.<sup><a href="https://www.upi.com/Science_News/2021/02/11/Fin-whale-songs-could-help-map-the-ocean-floor/6431613070586/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-56017967" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24</a> <a href="https://myfox8.com/news/offbeat/90-year-old-man-spends-10k-on-ads-to-tell-att-ceo-about-his-slow-internet-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a></sup></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-second-impeachment-star-spangled-banner-act/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-marjorie-taylor-green-trump-sag-david-hogg-mypillow-mike-lindell/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-marjorie-taylor-green-trump-sag-david-hogg-mypillow-mike-lindell/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">­­In a 230–199 vote, the House of Representatives stripped Republican congresswoman Marjorie Taylor Greene of her committee assignments after statements she had made years earlier on social media about QAnon, 9/11, mass shootings, and anti-Semitic conspiracy theories drew newfound attention.<sup><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2021/02/04/live-updates-house-to-vote-on-marjorie-taylor-greene-committee-seats/4383759001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a> <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/marjorie-taylor-greene-qanon-wildfires-space-laser-rothschild-execute.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> “I want to tell you: any source of information that is a mix of truth and a mix of lies is dangerous, no matter what it is saying,” said Greene, a former blogger for AmericanTruthSeekers.com.<sup><a href="https://youtu.be/V6qXE1q3Nv4?t=300" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/georgia-congressional-candidate-s-writings-highlight-qanon-support-n1236724" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a></sup> The day after the vote, Greene, who inherited her father’s multimillion-dollar construction company, tweeted that “the Democrats (+11)” are “morons” for “giving some one [<em>sic</em>] like me free time,” adding, “This is going to be fun!”<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/mtgreenee/status/1357675098887577601" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://variety.com/2020/politics/news/marjorie-taylor-greene-qanon-wins-election-1234822723/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a></sup> MyPillow CEO Mike Lindell’s <em>Absolute Proof</em>, a three-hour documentary about fraud in the 2020 presidential election, aired on One America News Network with a disclaimer that it was “opinion only.”<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/news/537530-oan-to-air-three-hour-mypillow-ceo-movie" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a></sup> Parkland activist David Hogg, whom Greene was recorded harassing on the street in 2019, announced plans to found a pillow company to rival Lindell’s.<sup><a href="https://www.fox4now.com/news/national-politics/parkland-survivor-david-hogg-plans-to-start-pillow-company-to-rival-mypillow-founder-mike-lindell" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a></sup> Jeff Bezos, whose net worth is estimated to have increased by 79.8 percent during the pandemic, announced that he will step down as chief executive officer of Amazon, citing a desire to focus on “other passions” such as Blue Origin, a company that aims to make space travel cheaper by reusing rockets.<sup><a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/company-news/email-from-jeff-bezos-to-employees" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a> <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2020/12/01/american-billionaires-that-got-richer-during-covid/43205617/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10</a></sup> GameStop’s stock price fell by nearly $165, and one television show and four movies, including one based on a book that has not yet been written, have been optioned about r/WallStreetBets and the stock’s impact on Wall Street.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/04/investing/gamestop-wallstreetbets-reddit/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22268952/gamestop-stock-stonks-reddit-wallstreetbets-movies-tv-shows-hbo-netflix" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a></sup> Super Bowl LV, held in Tampa Bay, Florida, was attended by 25,000 fans who were separated by 30,000 cardboard cutouts.<sup><a href="https://www.nfl.com/news/official-attendance-expected-for-super-bowl-lv-25-000-fans-30-000-cutouts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a></sup> “They are pretty cool looking,” an NFL spokesperson tweeted about the cutouts.</p>
<p>In Myanmar, tens of thousands of protesters, some of whom made a three-fingered salute like that from the Hunger Games series, rallied against the military coup and the detainment of de facto leader Aung San Suu Kyi.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/02/07/965097259/tens-of-thousands-rally-in-myanmar-protesting-military-coup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14</a> <a href="https://gizmodo.com/why-are-protestors-in-myanmar-doing-the-hunger-games-th-1846186981" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a></sup> “Protest against the coup,” Suu Kyi urged in a letter published on the Facebook page of the country’s pro-democracy party.<sup><a href="https://gizmodo.com/why-are-protestors-in-myanmar-doing-the-hunger-games-th-1846186981" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-55882489" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a></sup> At least 23 people were arrested in Haiti after an attempt to overthrow President Jovenel Moïse, who has held office for five years and whose administration has been accused of employing gangs to violently suppress the opposition.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-55975442" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/07/world/americas/haiti-protests-President-Jovenel-Mois.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>19</sup></a> The United Poland Party has proposed the creation of hospices that would include a separate room dedicated to crying for the use of women who, under the country’s abortion ban, will be forced to give birth to fetuses with fatal defects; according to the spokeswoman for the Polish justice ministry, the women would also be given “advice on what to do next.”<sup><a href="https://notesfrompoland.com/2021/02/03/polish-ministry-proposes-room-to-cry-in-for-women-forced-to-give-birth-by-abortion-ban/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a></sup> The Turkish government has been accused of rounding up Uighurs living in Turkey and deporting them to China in exchange for COVID-19 vaccines, and South Africa has suspended its rollout of the AstraZeneca vaccine after a study revealed “disappointing” results against the South African variant.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/turkey-beijing-coronavirus-pandemic-ankara-china-c8b714974552c484c501a5784efc117a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-55975052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a></sup> A new study showed that human activities such as surfing and drilling have caused baby clown fish get lost on their way home, condemning some fish to forever wander the seas alone.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/04/science/ocean-marine-noise-pollution.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a></sup></p>
<p>“While I’m not familiar with your work, I’m very proud of my work on movies such as <em>Home Alone 2</em>, <em>Zoolander,</em> and <em>Wall Street: Money Never Sleeps</em>,” Donald Trump wrote in his resignation letter from the Screen Actors’ Guild.<sup><a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/files/SAG-AFTRAResignationLetterfromPresidentDonaldJTrump.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24</a></sup> The Texas Department of Public Safety has apologized after sending three Amber alerts about Chucky, the possessed doll from the Child’s Play horror film franchise.<sup><a href="https://nytimes.com/2021/02/03/us/department-public-safety-amber-alert-malfunction.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a></sup> A police commander in Bellwood, Illinois, was charged with three counts of possession of child pornography, and police officers in Rochester, New York, were suspended after pepper-spraying a nine-year-old girl.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcchicago.com/news/local/bellwood-police-commander-charged-with-possession-of-child-pornography/2431545/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">26</a> <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/02/01/962813494/rochester-releases-video-of-police-pepper-spraying-9-year-old-girl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">27</a></sup> An Ontario couple were caught playing <em>Pokémon GO</em> in their van by police and fined $880 for nonessential travel.<sup><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/windsor/couple-pokemon-fined-covid-order-1.5901388" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">28</a></sup> The chair of New Hampshire’s House Commerce and Consumer Affairs Committee requested via an intermediary that Representative Anita Burroughs keep her pet cats out of the room during committee Zoom meetings.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/new-hampshire-cats-animals-fca206House%20Commerce%20and%20Consumer%20Affairs%20Committee02aab19f84fd98ff6a08989479" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">29</a></sup> The chair later explained, “I simply asked the ranking Democrat, ‘Do we really want to have cats parading in front of the legislator’s computer? Let alone stopping and getting petted so that someone may assume the cat is sitting in for the legislator?’”—<em>Annie Geng</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-marjorie-taylor-green-trump-sag-david-hogg-mypillow-mike-lindell/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Reconciliation]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/the-reconciliation/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/the-reconciliation/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 22:22:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<div style="width: 200px; border: 1px solid black; background-color: white; margin-left: 30px; padding: 30px; padding-bottom: 30px; float: right; font-size: 90%;">A <a href="https://www.ledevoir.com/opinion/chroniques/594355/la-reconciliation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">version</a> of this column originally ran in <em>Le Devoir</em> on February 1, 2021. Translated from the French by John Cullen.</div>
<p class="drop-cap">In Don DeLillo’s new novel, <em>The Silence</em>, the power grid and the internet completely fail on Super Bowl Sunday, the day a majority of Americans are glued to their screens, causing Diane, one of the main characters, to wonder during the shutdown: <em>What happens to people who live inside their phones?</em></p>
<p>It’s a good question to ask after the January 6 Capitol riot, yet another astonishing event in an age that constantly stuns us. When I recall the images of that invasion—the crazy, the clueless, and the rabid parading around the Capitol rotunda—what strikes me are the people taking selfies with their cell phones, as if they were tourists rather than vandals, with no existence outside the frame of their phone’s display screen. This recklessness, at once innocent, weird, and idiotic, bespeaks a crisis as well as a national challenge: How have these people been so thoroughly marginalized from traditional society, and how can they be brought back?</p>
<p class="drop-cap">Sorry, but I don’t subscribe to the theory about the evil genius Donald Trump organizing a failed fascist coup d’état. Trump does have a major jones for his own phone, but he lacks both the attention span and the intellectual capacity required to concoct a complex plot. A wild beast that acts instinctively—sometimes relying on deception, other times on animal intuition—the former president chiefly produces theater, with the intention of exciting and amusing the crowd instead of achieving concrete political goals. Having no considered plan or coherent organization, the January 6 rioters constitute no genuine threat to the government; they represent an impulse triggered by emotion, not based on ideology. Despite his considerable limitations, Trump the actor should have realized that words can have great power, and that to some people feelings can be as real as ideas and actions. Unfortunately, his imagination didn’t have the range to envision the death of two of his supporters: Roseanne Boyland, trampled to death by the crowd, and Ashli Babbitt, fatally shot by a policeman. But when all is said and done, the real danger remains that of individual, random violence, and it’s what President Biden must be wary of. The actor John Wilkes Booth, who assassinated Abraham Lincoln, was also a self-created player on the national political stage.</p>
<p>So what is to be done about our 74 million fellow citizens who voted for a crook, and about the boisterous minority among them who would be willing to follow Trump’s banner to the bitter end? A friend of mine, whom precarious health and COVID-19 had kept confined to his New York apartment since last March, told me a story: Not long ago, he and his partner rented a house on the west coast of Florida so that they could breathe some fresh air. At first, their next-door neighbor seemed friendly—he even invited them to swim in his pool. But then they ran into him outside when they were wearing their masks, a practice that’s nearly universal in New York City. According to my friend, “The guy recoiled as if we’d insulted him. He insisted that the virus was a hoax; all you had to do to avoid it was to take hydroxychloroquine.” And so on. For the time being, they’re dodging all contact with their neighbor. But in the future, they’ll have to find some way of reconciling the gap between them.</p>
<p>If President Biden is really in favor of reconciliation, he could do a lot to help achieve it. A good opportunity will soon present itself: his first public address to a joint session of Congress is scheduled for February 23. This address would be the ideal occasion for the president to admit that the endless wars in Iraq and Afghanistan are mistakes comparable to the fiasco of the war in Vietnam, and that working- and middle-class people have borne most of the burden in deaths, injuries, and taxes. That the rich have been getting disproportionately richer ever since the Reagan years, including through two Democratic administrations, thanks to the deregulation of the financial markets and the banks and to inadequate capital-gains taxation, which favors stockholders and property owners. That the touted benefits of “free trade” and globalization actually harmed ordinary people by giving away their jobs, and that the Democratic Party, together with its Republican allies, took a wrong turn with the enactment of the North American Free Trade Agreement in 1994 and the signing of a trade-normalization treaty with China in 2000—and that the destruction of unions by free trade has removed a crucial safeguard against the current working-class rage so prevalent during the Trump era. That immigration is a social blessing as long as the most vulnerable U.S. workers are protected by a decent minimum wage, and that the the arrival of hundreds of thousands of undocumented immigrants willing to work for less than the minimum wage may cause the most vulnerable citizens to lose their jobs.</p>
<p>The president should similarly tackle the degraded culture of the Internet and Twitter. Rather than encouraging Big Tech to censor Trump and his supporters—a hypocritical and tactically stupid policy, since it might make Trump a martyr—Biden and the Democrats could regulate and tax digital platforms in order to maintain a system of public education that would serve as a powerful counterweight to the fatuousness and mendacious cacophony of the social networks.</p>
<p>And if not? Faced with technological catastrophe, DeLillo’s character Diane thinks about escaping the chaos in her kitchen “to go for a walk, alone.” Similarly, in reaction to the social collapse displayed on January 6 in Washington, D.C., one can likewise choose, as the novel suggests, solitude and silence—can, in other words, say good-bye to the Republic.</p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/the-reconciliation/" target="_blank">The Reconciliation</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Playing the Flute]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/playing-the-flute-machuca-colombia-oil-spill-explosion/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/playing-the-flute-machuca-colombia-oil-spill-explosion/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:27:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">María Cecilia Mosquera doesn’t hide her scars. A survivor of Colombia’s decades-long conflict, she was wearing a bright-yellow short-sleeved top when I met her in Medellín. The T-shirt, which bore the French word for love in white across the chest, revealed burn wounds that had healed into resin-like whorls on her hands and forearms. One night in 1998, a few National Liberation Army (ELN) guerrilla fighters carried out what should have been a routine bombing on the Ocensa pipeline near Mosquera’s small village, located more than one hundred miles outside Medellín. By then the ELN had been conducting its pipeline-bombing campaign for more than a decade. But that night the crude that poured into a nearby river, along with its abundant fumes, erupted in flames, barreling into an inferno that engulfed the town and killed eighty-four people. Mosquera survived.</p>
<p>The village, called Machuca, is an isolated hamlet of fishermen and artisanal miners, called <em>barequeros,</em> who pan the river for small amounts of gold. It was mid-October, after midnight, when members of the ELN set off dynamite to rupture the pipeline. Although pipeline attacks were not an uncommon occurrence in the area, it quickly became clear that this one was different. The pipeline was on a slope across the river from Machuca, and when it cracked, it sent as much as 21,000 gallons of oil down into the water that coursed toward town. It also released a cocktail of gases and volatile liquids that included ethane, propane, and butane. The smell drifted through the streets, and then a few minutes later, an unknown spark blew the town apart.</p>
<p>Mosquera told me that she woke up and opened her door to see a column of flame rising toward the sky and burning with such blinding intensity that the houses lit up as though it were midday. “It’s the end of the world!” she screamed at her children, telling them to flee. She ran toward her husband, Arturo, and shouted at him to get up, but he didn’t respond. She had to push her way through the burning house to escape. Later, Mosquera learned that her family was gone—her infant daughter perished alongside Arturo in the conflagration, and her two older children died from their injuries a few weeks later in a hospital in Medellín. After months of therapy for her own burns, Mosquera returned to Machuca, where she looked out the window of her rebuilt house one morning and saw, sitting in the sunshine across the way, one of the men she had heard blew up the pipeline. She was filled with rage.</p>
<div id="attachment_281646" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Machuca_edited01.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-281646" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-281646 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Machuca_edited01.png" alt="" width="1000" height="667" srcset="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Machuca_edited01.png 1000w, https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Machuca_edited01-300x200.png 300w, https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Machuca_edited01-768x512.png 768w, https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Machuca_edited01-180x120.png 180w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-281646" class="wp-caption-text">Aerial photograph of La Pesquera by Hanna Wallis</p></div>
<p class="drop-cap">A few weeks after I met Mosquera, in late 2019, I traveled to the eastern department of Arauca; pipeline attacks continue to be a regular occurrence in Colombia, and Ecopetrol, the state oil company, had agreed to fly me in one of its chartered helicopters to see the latest spill sites. From above, the pools of oil looked like a mistake, etched into lime-colored fields cleaved by a cord of river. Black isn’t a color you usually encounter in the grasslands. Distortion from the chopper blades gave the view a shimmering patina, and a band of cumulus edged toward the horizon. Four days had passed since the last pipeline bombing, and a lake of glistening crude stagnated in the savanna. We were flying low, around 3,000 feet. Lazaro Castillo, speaking into his headset, asked the pilot to circle around, and the helicopter dropped down and angled back.</p>
<p>It was a clear day in October. There had already been nearly three dozen oil spills in Colombia since the beginning of the year, and Castillo, an Ecopetrol employee, was showing me the damage. For more than three decades, blowing up Colombia’s oil pipelines has been a key combat strategy of guerrilla groups. Even though the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) signed a cease-fire, which came into effect in 2016, and the country has committed itself to a sputtering if impassioned peace process, a group of dissident FARC members declared that they were rearming last year. The lesser-known but apparently more truculent ELN, which had been in stilted peace talks of its own with the government until conservative President Iván Duque took office in 2018, continues operating, often from neighboring Venezuela.</p>
<p>By the time we flew over, the pipeline that runs from the nearby oil fields in Caño-Limon to the coastal town of Coveñas had been out of operation more days than not since the start of the year. Ecopetrol’s subsidiaries manage the pipeline, and until last year the Texas petroleum company Occidental, or Oxy, operated the oil fields. An ELN commander told me that, sensitive to the poor publicity some of the larger spills have caused, the guerrillas tried to shift to denting the pipes rather than puncturing them, but there were still 107 pipeline attacks during 2018, some 89 of which targeted the Caño-Limon-Coveñas conduit. Since it started operating, in 1986, the pipeline has been attacked 1,495 times. It has been punctured so frequently that locals jokingly call it “the flute.”</p>
<p>Colombia’s oil industry is relatively small, accounting for less than 1 percent of global production. Still, it yields considerable profit, and the emergence of Ecopetrol’s operations at the Caño-Limón oil field, one of the country’s largest, fostered the rise of the ELN back in the 1980s. The foreign firms that were brought in were ripe for extortion. “The oil companies were pragmatic, obviously. You arrive and say, ‘Who’s in charge here if the state isn’t?’” Sergio Lopera, a petroleum researcher at the National University of Colombia, explained. “If a guy shows up with a gun and says he’s in charge, it’s no problem, you just have to pay up. That’s how this country works.”</p>
<p>Colombian magazine <em>Semana</em> reported that four engineers who worked for the German company Mannesmann were kidnapped in 1983 and ransomed for a rumored $8 million, a sum that saved the ELN from the brink of collapse after a series of bad operational defeats in the country’s interior. Whether because of that success or the relative ease of targeting pipelines that were nearly impossible to fully secure, bombing the country’s oil-transport network became one of the ELN’s preferred tactics. The goal is to disrupt the country’s economic life, particularly a sector of it that so directly enriches the government against which the guerrillas have pitted themselves. In communiqués, the ELN insists that it believes in protecting the environment, but considers disrupting natural resources extraction to be an important tool in the fight against capitalism. “To the oligarchy, imperialism or corporations, the only thing that matters is profit,” a commander of the ELN’s western forces, who went by the alias Uriel, told me. “They are only affected by this kind of pillage.” The guerrillas also demand benefits to communities affected by environmentally damaging industries, but this has mostly been a chimera. (Uriel was killed by the military in October.)</p>
<p>From afar, the oil below the helicopter looked like the shadow of a cloud on the vast green plains. As we drew nearer, it was possible to make out a trough that ran along one side of the pools, collecting syrupy crude in a bulwark against its spread. Adjacent to the oil sat a neat town of corrugated-roof houses arranged along gridded dirt streets. Castillo told me that the town was called La Pesquera. One of the peanut-hued rivers that snaked through the landscape just a few miles beyond it marked the border with Venezuela; four miles up the pipeline were the oil fields.</p>
<p>If La Pesquera seemed unfavorably located, it didn’t have a long history to look back on to search for blame. Many of the 300 or so families who live there were displaced by the armed struggle among guerrilla groups like the ELN, right-wing paramilitaries, and the Colombian military. Populated by people who fled the Caribbean coast or other parts of the department—Arauca was and continues to be an ELN stronghold—the village itself is an artifact of the conflict, just like the 3.7 million barrels of oil that have been spilled from the Caño-Limon pipeline since the 1980s.</p>
<p>That amount of oil is the equivalent of nearly fourteen <em>Exxon</em> <em>Valdez</em> spills, and yet, since it has spewed across the soils and rivers of a land riven by conflict in small if constant amounts, it has gone largely unexamined. Colombia’s scientists haven’t devoted much in the way of resources to studying the long-term impact of these spills, which often take place in remote areas. Instead, Ecopetrol has become sentinel, cleanup crew, and spill archivist all in one.</p>
<p>When we flew over the spill site next to La Pesquera, Ecopetrol had had pipeline repair teams ready to go for days, but they were lounging in an air-conditioned airport hangar waiting for the Colombian military to secure the area and give them the go-ahead. Instead of flying to a rupture site, another repair crew boarded our helicopter and accompanied us to a pump station, where they unloaded their backpacks and rubber boots under the watch of armed soldiers. From there they would make their way to the pipeline by land. Just the previous week, a soldier was killed and an Ecopetrol subcontractor injured in a firefight with ELN combatants. After we dropped off the crew, the helicopter circled briefly over the oil pools that encroached on La Pesquera, but we couldn’t land. Castillo told the pilot to fly on to the next spill site, just a few miles away.</p>
<p>Battalions from Colombia’s infrastructure-protection company, Plan Meteoro, patrol the pipeline in Arauca to minimize bombings, casting the Colombian military in the incongruous role of environmental advocate. The ELN “is one of the greatest perpetrators of ecocide on the planet,” a Colombian Army general named Luis Felipe Montoya told me, before suggesting that if the guerrillas were held to the same standard as Exxon after the 1989 spill, they would owe the Colombian state $57 billion. Just one report from 2003, produced by the Strategic Studies Institute, the U.S. Army’s research think tank, estimated that the ELN and FARC pipeline bombings on Caño-Limón-Coveñas were responsible for $450 million in lost revenue in a single year, “plus significant ecological damage.”</p>
<p>One afternoon in Medellín, I asked the army’s former second-in-command, Major General Mario Augusto Valencia Valencia, about the support he receives from the U.S. to protect the pipelines. He demurred from specifics, saying that the U.S. military contributes training and logistics to help fight terrorists—the ELN is considered a terrorist group by both the U.S. and Colombia governments—but isn’t directly involved with securing the pipeline. At the height of the country’s drug war, the U.S. was pouring millions of dollars into protecting the country’s oil infrastructure. In 2003 and 2004, according to the Council on Hemispheric Affairs, the U.S. spent more than $200 million protecting the Caño-Limón-Coveñas pipeline alone, a decision that was likely facilitated, at least in part, by Occidental Petroleum’s outlay of $8.6 million in lobbying expenditures between 1996 and 2000, part of which was to persuade the U.S. Congress to support military assistance for Colombia. Last year, Congress appropriated $418 million in assistance to Colombia.</p>
<p>Although the military’s presence in Arauca probably does prevent some spills from occurring, what happens to the crude once it’s released is almost entirely up to Ecopetrol. More than one observer told me, with no apparent irony, that Ecopetrol leads the world in oil spill remediation technology. Along the Caño-Limón-Coveñas, the company maintains ninety-seven control points on the waterways that skirt the pipeline, including half a dozen diversion sites that are constantly staffed and equipped with booms and skimmers. If the oil seeps into the soil, the company’s cleanup crews make boreholes to pool the crude in dark puddles and pump it out, then add commercially produced bacteria to break it down. The process can take months. An Ecopetrol biologist who led the cleanup efforts told me that the company is extremely effective at removing the oil, but that the afterlife of the spill wasn’t the company’s responsibility. In effect it’s no one’s. “Of course, there’s a long-term impact,” Colombia’s former environment minister Manuel Rodríguez Becerra told me. “But there have been so many attacks that the country doesn’t have the resources to evaluate the damage. That’s the truth.”</p>
<p class="drop-cap">A year after the pipeline explosion, Mosquera’s friend Maribel Agualimpia helped start a small radio station where they could talk about what happened. At night, Agualimpia hosted a program called <em>Buenas Noches, Corazón</em>, playing love songs and ballads to lift people’s spirits. Beyond the town’s borders, the pipeline explosion faded from the news and into the fabric of atrocities that shroud everyday life. No one had a monopoly on murder. The Colombian Air Force dropped a cluster bomb on a town near the Caño-Limón-Coveñas pipeline, killing seventeen villagers, and Occidental Petroleum, along with a U.S.-based surveillance company, allegedly helped identify the target (a case brought against them in the U.S. by a survivor was eventually dismissed, and Occidental denied responsibility or wrongdoing). Mosquera met a woman named Diana Sofía Giraldo, who started an organization for victims and persuaded her to start telling her story. “She didn’t speak for a long time,” Giraldo told me, “because she was convinced her grief didn’t matter to anybody.” Once Mosquera began talking, though, people listened. She has an unaffected air and a raw directness that has withstood increasing attention from media and politicians. When she met the Pope during his visit to Colombia in 2017, she asked him to pray for her to find forgiveness.</p>
<p>Mosquera has traveled to multiple meetings with former ELN fighters since the bombing that took her family, but though the guerrillas say they have asked for absolution from survivors, they have never made the gesture publicly in Machuca. On one occasion, Mosquera met an ex-combatant of the ELN who seemed genuinely repentant, and she held his grandchild in her arms and was reminded of holding her own son when he was small and chubby. But she still believes that her town and its tragedy have been forgotten, that the eddies of conflict have swept things like pipeline blasts into the purgatory of memory without expiation. Giraldo played me a WhatsApp message that Mosquera recorded for the president after he visited Machuca for the twentieth-anniversary memorial service. “Nobody does anything,” she told him. After she had given me the account of her story, in Medellín, we went out to lunch and she showed me old photos of her children that she kept on her phone. She smiled as she looked at them. Then we made our way back, threading through busy streets and the honking commotion of afternoon traffic.</p>
<p><em>The reporting for this story was supported by the International Women’s Media Foundation as part of its Adelante Latin American Reporting Initiative.</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/playing-the-flute-machuca-colombia-oil-spill-explosion/" target="_blank">Playing the Flute</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-gamestop-robinhood-amlo-covid/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-gamestop-robinhood-amlo-covid/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:50:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Millions of people bought stock in GameStop, pushing the company’s value up 1,100 percent and leading to billions of dollars in losses for hedge funds that had bet against it.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/article/gamestop-hedge-funds.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a> <a href="https://popular.info/p/the-merry-adventures-of-robinhood" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> The surge in value began after a post on the subreddit r/WallStreetBets, whose members refer to earnings as “tendies” and often celebrate investing success by eating chicken tenders, revealed that Melvin Capital had taken a short position on the retailer.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/29/technology/stock-traders-reddit-tiktok-youtube.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a> </sup>“There’s a catharsis to actually making money off their pain a little bit,” said Justin Speak, an evangelical pastor in California.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/27/business/gamestop-wall-street-bets.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a></sup> Trading in the stock was later restricted by TD Ameritrade, Charles Schwab, and Robinhood, amateur-trading platforms that have been paid tens of millions of dollars by the hedge-fund manager Ken Griffin, who in 2019 purchased the most expensive home in the United States and lost billions of dollars during the GameStop surge.<sup><a href="https://popular.info/p/the-merry-adventures-of-robinhood" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a></sup> Multiple billionaires blamed the situation on the stimulus checks that the federal government had sent Americans to help them through the coronavirus pandemic.<sup><a href="https://www.tmz.com/2021/01/31/plane-flies-over-robinhood-hq-with-suck-my-nuts-banner-san-francisco/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a></sup> “In this case, thanks to primarily government policy, there’s wherewithal among investors, if you want to call them that, with government money being sprayed all over the place,” said “Bond King” Jeffrey Gundlach. An airplane flew over Robinhood’s San Francisco office carrying a banner reading <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">suck my nuts robinhood</span>.<sup><a href="https://www.tmz.com/2021/01/31/plane-flies-over-robinhood-hq-with-suck-my-nuts-banner-san-francisco/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a></sup> The United States’ position on the global corruption index fell, and members of Scotland’s Parliament announced a vote on an unexplained wealth order, also known as a “McMafia” order, that would require Donald Trump to reveal the sources of his Scottish finances.<sup><a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/united-states-drops-global-corruption-080445915.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a> </sup><a href="https://www.scotsman.com/news/politics/scottish-parliament-hold-vote-unexplained-wealth-order-donald-trumps-finances-3118810" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>9</sup></a></p>
<p>On the 72nd anniversary of the Indian constitution, tens of thousands of farmers protested new agricultural laws that benefit corporations by marching in Delhi, pulling apart barricades with tractors and storming the Red Fort, the erstwhile seat of the Mughal Empire; security forces responded with tear gas and cut internet service in parts of the capital.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/25/world/asia/india-farmers-protests-delhi.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10</a></sup> The military of Myanmar deposed the country’s civilian government, declared a one-year state of emergency, and detained Daw Aung San Suu Kyi, who in 1999 was named by <em>Time </em>magazine as “one of the children of Gandhi” and later ignored the Rohingya genocide.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/31/world/asia/myanmar-coup-aung-san-suu-kyi.html?action=click&amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11</a> </sup><a href="http://content.time.com/time/subscriber/article/0,33009,993026,00.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>12</sup></a> Facing accusations that he had mismanaged the pandemic, Italy’s prime minister resigned, and the country’s government collapsed for the 65th time in the past seven decades.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/25/world/europe/italy-government-conte.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/26/world/europe/italy-government-collapse.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>14</sup></a> Poland’s top court upheld a near-total ban on abortions, and the National Assembly of Thailand legalized abortions during the first trimester of pregnancy.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/poland-enforce-near-total-abortion-ban-triggering-protests-n1255938" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/28/world/asia/thailand-abortion-rights.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a></sup> The president of Mexico, Andrés Manuel López Obrador, who claimed that religious amulets would ward off the coronavirus, tested positive for COVID-19.<sup><a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/mexican-president-tests-positive-covid-19-symptoms-mild-75464289" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a></sup> In Oregon, medics caught in a snowstorm vaccinated other people trapped in vehicles, preventing the doses from going to waste, and a man accused of attacking a woman with a hammer was released from custody after he invoked the right to see his accuser face-to-face; the woman, who cares for her elderly parents, refused to appear in court without a face mask.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/28/us/oregon-vaccine-stuck-in-the-snow-drivers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a> <a href="https://www.wfmynews2.com/article/news/local/assault-trial-dismissed-after-alleged-victim-didnt-show-up-to-court-court-had-ordered-her-to-testify-while-not-wearing-a-mask/283-6353fa4b-77d7-41ef-9519-be6935b7abfe" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a></sup> Twelve days after being named paramedic of the year, a Florida man named Joshua Colon was arrested for stealing doses of the vaccine; protesters carrying signs with messages such as <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">save your soul turn back now</span> temporarily shut down the vaccination center at Dodger Stadium in Los Angeles; and the attorney general of Oklahoma was tasked with trying to return $2 million worth of hydroxychloroquine that had been ordered by the state’s governor in April, days after President Trump had endorsed it.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/26/us/emergency-responder-arrested-vaccine-florida.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a> <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2021-01-30/dodger-stadiums-covid-19-vaccination-site-shutdown-after-dozens-of-protesters-gather-at-entrance" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21</a> <a href="https://www.readfrontier.org/stories/oklahoma-trying-to-return-its-2m-stockpile-of-hydroxychloroquine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a></sup> “Who cares?” asked New York governor Andrew Cuomo after his attorney general released findings demonstrating that the number of COVID-19 deaths attributable to nursing homes had been undercounted.<sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/cuomo-won-t-apologize-nursing-184229572.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAALZNz4HxoQrTAAVOaIt79ENMg5X6TmZCDAQEjy7tUNPBqAFWeBkFhKaawoVjS5gAjSgP6yP-WVhooyPv9ytjxsdK4Nfk6F9dJ7g09m2ITHsSw6tWtv9Juu06WLabFosr-zPJnDsxAHwaHdnpP9dF7Ae13Vr6wa3Xc0Vp1AaDIufp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a></sup> Cuomo also announced that in-person weddings, with attendance of up to 150 people, could resume on the Ides of March.<a href="https://gothamist.com/news/cuomo-announces-weddings-150-people-maximum-can-resume-march" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>24</sup></a></p>
<p>It was reported that at least a dozen in-flight errors since May were made by pilots who were rusty because they had been flying less.<sup><a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2021-01-29/airline-pilots-flight-errors-pandemic" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a></sup> “I felt that my recollection was strong enough,” said one pilot, “but in reality I should have taken some time to review.” Owners of a farm in Lancashire, England, said that they had earned as much as $50,000 by booking goats as guests for Zoom calls, including Lisa, who specializes in “passive-aggressive bleating.”<sup><a href="https://www.lancs.live/news/lancashire-news/lancashire-farm-makes-50000-pandemic-19720511" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">26</a></sup> A man in Derbent, Russia, was arrested for cooking barbecue over an eternal flame memorializing soldiers who died in World War II.<sup><a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/europe/russia-eternal-flame-soldier-bbq-world-war-two-b1794630.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">27</a></sup> A Canadian man killed another man by pushing him in front of an oncoming subway car because he thought the stranger was his landlord, and friends of Mike and Karen Pence believe that the couple, who after leaving the official vice-presidential residence no longer have a permanent address, is couch surfing with various Indiana officials.<sup><a href="https://globalnews.ca/news/7604664/toronto-subway-pusher-john-reszetnik/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">28</a> </sup><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/mike-pence-homeless-couch-surfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>29</sup></a>—<em>Cameron French</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-gamestop-robinhood-amlo-covid/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/01/weekly-review-trump-pardons-biden-executive-orders/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/01/weekly-review-trump-pardons-biden-executive-orders/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 18:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">On his first day in office, President Joe Biden signed 17 executive orders, including provisions for the United States to rejoin the Paris climate accord and restore ties with the World Health Organization; end construction of the U.S.-Mexico border wall; and require executive-branch appointees to sign an ethics pledge committing them to act “without regard to private gain or personal benefit.”<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/20/us/biden-executive-orders.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a> <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-ethics-commitments-by-executive-branch-personnel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> Trump’s final acts as president included revoking his own lobbying-reform pledge and issuing 143 pardons and sentence commutations, recipients of which included the rapper Lil Wayne; a co-founder of Death Row Records, Michael “Harry-O” Harris; the Fox News host Jeanine Pirro’s ex-husband, Albert; and “Sloppy Steve” Bannon.<sup><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-20/trump-revokes-lobbying-ban-after-promising-to-drain-the-swamp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/full-list-trump-s-last-minute-pardons-commuted-sentences-n1254806" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a> <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/trump-pardons-death-row-records-co-founder-michael-harry-o-harris" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/donald-trump-steve-bannon-new-nickname_n_5a4f4c7ee4b003133ec6f671" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a></sup> In anticipation of a pardon that never came, Joe Exotic, the subject of the documentary series <em>Tiger King, </em>had a limousine waiting outside the prison where he is currently incarcerated; Exotic attributed his failure to being “too innocent and too GAY.”<a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/tv/story/2021-01-20/tiger-king-joe-exotic-trump-pardon-snub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>7</sup></a> The Supreme Court dismissed a set of lawsuits against Trump that accused him of violating the emoluments clause of the Constitution, and it was reported that former Trump campaign aides had planned the rally that preceded the January 6 siege of the U.S. Capitol.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-ends-trump-lawsuits-df42ef0eec5fa57edf3e294234051d88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-2020-donald-trump-capitol-siege-campaigns-elections-d14c78d53b3a212658223252fec87e99" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a> <a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/news/2021/01/trump-tied-to-dc-protests-dark-money-and-shell-companies/?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=twitt_trump-ties-dcprot-012220" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10</a></sup> Hundreds of the 25,000 National Guard members deployed to Washington in response to the siege tested positive for COVID-19 after being quartered in hallways and garages without social-distancing measures; in one instance, 5,000 troops had to share a single bathroom.<a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/01/22/national-guard-coronavirus-461340" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>11</sup></a> New research indicated that the sincerity of a smile cannot be gauged through eye contact, and Melania Trump asked members of her staff to write thank-you notes “in her voice” to the rest of the White House staff.<sup><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s42761-020-00030-w#" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/20/politics/melania-trump-thank-you-notes/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a></sup></p>
<p>“I don’t plan to either hang myself on a window grill or cut my veins or throat open with a sharpened spoon,” the Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny wrote from prison on the night before protesters across the country began demanding his release.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-russia-politics-navalny-message-idUSKBN29R2BE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/vladimir-putin-moscow-arrests-europe-russia-56e06f50eab494213d09346a5d9b4e69" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a></sup> North Korea’s ambassador to the United Nations said that the country was “gravely concerned” about human-rights violations in Australia.<sup><a href="https://www.nknews.org/2021/01/north-korea-says-its-gravely-concerned-about-australian-human-rights-abuses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a></sup> The U.S. COVID-19 death toll surpassed the number of American soldiers killed in World War II, and GitHub, in an apology for firing a Jewish employee for warning co-workers about Nazism, announced that “employees are free to express concerns about Nazis.”<sup><a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/covid-19-has-killed-more-americans-than-world-war-ii" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55704932" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a></sup> Instacart fired a group of workers who had voted to unionize, and Twitter suspended the account of the Chinese embassy to the United States after it tweeted a derogatory comment about Uighur women.<sup><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/7k9deg/instacart-says-it-will-lay-off-all-of-its-unionized-workers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-twitter/twitter-locks-account-of-chinas-u-s-embassy-over-its-defense-of-xinjiang-policy-idUSKBN29Q03O" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a></sup> “We hope the rescue won’t stop,” read a note from Chinese miners who were trapped 2,000 feet underground for a week.<a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/1/20/trapped-china-miners-get-food-blankets-but-one-person-in" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>21</sup></a> <sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/china-accident-mine/update-6-china-rescues-11-miners-after-14-days-trapped-underground-cctv-idUSL1N2JZ025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a></sup> A man who had been living at Chicago’s O’Hare Airport for three months was arrested; a thief who discovered a toddler in the back seat of a car he had stolen returned to the scene of the crime in order to yell at the child’s mother; and an Atlanta teenager stole almost $1 million by fraudulently returning items to the supermarket chain Kroger.<sup><a href="https://www.chicagotribune.com/news/breaking/ct-man-living-airport-released-20210122-k2qaoyacmrgfvkn4cnmutqe7zq-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/thief-berates-mom-kid-in-stolen-car-29b28e4e64aa51978f7b7b91a163db35" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24</a> <a href="https://www.ajc.com/news/teen-accused-of-stealing-nearly-1-million-from-gwinnett-kroger/7FV4QYI2FFGFXA5LTTXHZABBVQ/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a></sup> After a two-year investigation, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police discovered the origin of cocaine-stuffed bananas that had been sent to grocers, and in Vancouver, British Columbia, a woman who had been arrested by the RCMP wrote a thank-you note to the officers, giving them a 4.5-star rating for their “care and kindness” during her detention.<sup><a href="https://www.yahoo.com/lifestyle/cocaine-stuffed-shipments-bananas-ended-224752670.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">26</a> <a href="https://globalnews.ca/news/7586244/west-shore-rcmp-thank-you-card/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">27</a></sup> The New Jersey Supreme Court overturned an armed-robbery conviction because the prosecutor had displayed a still from <em>The Shining </em>during closing arguments, and Leon Black, the CEO of Apollo Global Management, resigned after an investigation revealed that he had given $158 million between 2012 and 2017 to the deceased sex trafficker Jeffrey Epstein, who was the sole director of Black’s family’s foundation.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/news/local/after-prosecutor-uses-the-shining-photo-in-court-accused-bank-robber-gets-new-trial/2672986/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">28</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/25/business/leon-black-apollo-jeffrey-epstein.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">29</a> <a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/apollo-ceo-leon-black-resign-investigation-158-million-epstein-payments-2021-1-1030001157" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">30</a></sup> The broadcaster Larry King died at the age of 87, the baseball Hall of Famer and civil-rights activist Hank Aaron died at the age of 86, and the professional gamer Thomas “ZooMaa” Paparatto retired at the age of 25 because of a thumb injury.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/23/us/larry-king-dies-trnd/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">31</a> <a href="https://www.espn.com/mlb/story/_/id/30759123/long-home-run-king-hank-aaron-dies-86" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">32</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-55713305" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">33</a></sup></p>
<p>Microsoft patented technology that uses AI to mimic the voices and personalities of dead people.<a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/microsoft-patent-details-tech-that-could-turn-dead-people-into-ai-chatbots/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>34</sup></a> A woman in France who has been fighting for three years to be declared legally alive described her circumstances as “macabre.”<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/woman-declared-dead-2017-is-alive-2256556e1c682d8ca561cc14b58b0228" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">35</a></sup> Paleontologists discovered the “extraordinarily well-preserved male genitalia” of a 50-million-year-old insect as well as the excretory cavity of a dinosaur “shaped in its perfect, unique way.”<sup><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/spp2.1349" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">36</a></sup> <sup><a href="https://www.livescience.com/first-dinosaur-butthole-found.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">37</a></sup> The Senate minority leader, Mitch McConnell, stalled approval of the 50–50 Senate’s power-sharing agreement to demand a guarantee that Democrats will not eliminate the filibuster.<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-congress/filibuster-face-off-schumer-mcconnell-at-loggerheads-over-u-s-senate-power-sharing-idUSKBN29Q2VT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>38 </sup></a>“:-( I’m a nice guy you know,” texted the recently fired New York Mets general manager, Jared Porter, to a woman who had stopped replying to his messages after he sent her pictures of his penis.<sup><a href="https://www.espn.com/mlb/story/_/id/30737248/ny-mets-gm-jared-porter-acknowledges-sending-explicit-images-female-reporter-worked-chicago-cubs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">39</a></sup> “Please let me know if you ever need anything work wise,” Porter added.—<em>Clara Olshansky</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/01/weekly-review-trump-pardons-biden-executive-orders/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/01/weekly-review-second-impeachment-capitol-arrests/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/01/weekly-review-second-impeachment-capitol-arrests/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 17:46:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Donald Trump became the first American president to be impeached for a second time, after a majority of the House of Representatives voted to charge him with “inciting violence against the Government of the United States.”<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/13/us/politics/trump-impeached.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a> <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/trump-impeachment-effort-live-updates/2021/01/11/955631105/impeachment-resolution-cites-trumps-incitement-of-capitol-insurrection" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> Law-enforcement officials arrested more than 100 individuals in connection with the riot at the U.S. Capitol, including Jon Schaffer, a guitarist for the metal band Iced Earth; Thomas Robertson and Jacob Fracker, two Virginia police officers who had photographed themselves making obscene gestures in front of a statue of a Continental Army general; Klete Keller, an Olympic-gold-medal-winning swimmer who arrived at the Capitol wearing a Team USA jacket; Tim Gionet, a social-media personality known as Baked Alaska who once recorded a hip-hop song entitled “We Love Our Cops”; and Andrew Williams, a Florida firefighter who was captured on film in the Capitol saying, “They can’t arrest everybody.”<sup><a href="https://variety.com/2021/music/news/metal-guitarist-john-schaffer-surrenders-fbi-capitol-siege-1234887239/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a> <a href="https://www.wusa9.com/article/news/national/capitol-riots/off-duty-virginia-police-officers-charged-federally-storming-us-capitol/65-33ddad5f-56c7-444b-98ca-132cac14b2a5#:~:text=VIRGINIA%2C%20USA%20%E2%80%94%20Two%20off%2D,riots%20last%20week%2C%20officials%20said.&amp;text=for%20Washington%2C%20D.C.-,During%20the%20last%20week's%20riots%2C%20the%20men%20were%20allegedly%20photographed,of%20the%20John%20Stark%20statue." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a> <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/amberjamieson/klete-keller-olympian-charged-capitol" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/joe-biden-donald-trump-capitol-siege-alaska-crime-6666c735165a19a6ee019e412235bd8d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NxOltvOfLIM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a> <a href="https://www.wesh.com/article/andrew-williams-arrested-capitol-sanford/35194947#" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a></sup> It was reported that the Secret Service was spending $3,000 a month to rent a studio apartment adjacent to Jared Kushner and Ivanka Trump’s house in which agents could use the toilet because the couple had not allowed the agents to use any of their six bathrooms.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2021/01/14/secret-service-bathroom-ivanka-trump-jared-kushner/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a></sup> The Secret Service announced the creation of a “green zone” in Washington ahead of the presidential inauguration, and the western front of the Capitol was evacuated during a rehearsal because of a fire at a nearby encampment of unhoused persons.<sup><a href="https://wtop.com/inauguration/2021/01/unprecedented-major-inauguration-security-measures-go-into-effect-throughout-dc/">10</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/small-fire-prompts-temporary-shutdown-capitol-evacuation-inaguration-rehearsal-participants-n1254585" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11</a></sup> Some 20,000 National Guard troops were scheduled to be deployed to Washington, most of the bridges over the Potomac River were to be shut down, and a fence was to be constructed around the National Mall.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/14/us/politics/inauguration-security-capitol-riot-investigation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a></sup> “We want everybody to enjoy it,” said Washington mayor Muriel Bowser of the inauguration, “in their own states, in their own living rooms, and with their own families.”<sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/dc-mayor-public-not-come-212221183.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a></sup></p>
<p>The Center for Biological Diversity began offering a $5,000 reward for anyone with information about a manatee found in a Florida river with <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">trump</span> carved into its back.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/12/us/manatee-with-trump-on-its-back-trnd/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14</a></sup> “Manatees,” said the center’s Florida director, “aren’t billboards.” Prosecutors in Kenosha County, Wisconsin, requested that the bail conditions for Kyle Rittenhouse, who shot and killed two people at a Black Lives Matter protest last year, be modified to prohibit him from consuming alcohol, displaying “white power” signs, and consorting with white supremacists after he was seen making the “OK” gesture while drinking at a Wisconsin bar with a group of Proud Boys and his mother.<sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/prosecutors-looking-modify-kyle-rittenhouses-051048750.html?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a></sup> A woman in Quebec was fined for walking her husband on a leash outside after curfew, and a hacker remotely locked a number of internet-equipped chastity cages, which are designed to prevent wearers from achieving erections.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-55631198" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7apnn/your-cock-is-mine-now-hacker-locks-internet-connected-chastity-cage-demands-ransom" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a></sup> “Your cock is mine now,” the hacker, who demanded a ransom payment in bitcoin, wrote one of the victims. A San Francisco programmer was locked out of a digital wallet containing some $220 million worth of bitcoin after he forgot the password, and a Welsh IT worker unsuccessfully lobbied local authorities for permission to search a garbage dump for a hard drive containing a cryptographic key capable of unlocking $280 million of bitcoin that he had accidentally thrown in the trash.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/12/technology/bitcoin-passwords-wallets-fortunes.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/15/uk-man-makes-last-ditch-effort-to-recover-lost-bitcoin-hard-drive.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a></sup></p>
<p>Concerned that the steep prices for brides and weddings might lead to “corrupt and illegal practices,” the leader of the Taliban, who has two wives, issued a decree advising the organization’s leaders to refrain from polygamy, and an Indian man was arrested on charges of spying for Pakistan after allegedly leaking intelligence on troop movements in the Pokhran firing range in exchange for photos of nude women.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-55630097" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a> <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/isi-honeytrap-rajasthan-man-greed-nudes-leak-critical-information-indian-army-investigation-1757911-2021-01-11" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21</a></sup> A pigeon thought to have been in violation of biosecurity regulations after traveling from Oregon to Melbourne was condemned to death by the Australian government but was then granted a reprieve when its identification band was found to be counterfeit.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/15/world/australia/joe-pigeon.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a></sup> “Following an investigation,” announced the Department of Agriculture, Water, and the Environment, “the department has concluded that Joe the Pigeon is highly likely to be Australian.”<sup><a href="https://www.awe.gov.au/news/media-releases/protecting-aus-birdlife-biosecurity-risks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a></sup> Yellow mealworms, which are the larvae of the <i>Tenebrio </i><span class="s1"><i>molitor</i></span><i> </i>beetle, were approved for human consumption by the European Union’s food-safety agency, and Jacob Rees-Mogg, leader of the British House of Commons, defended new Brexit regulations that have disrupted the Scottish fishing industry.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jan/13/yellow-mealworm-safe-for-humans-to-eat-says-eu-food-safety-agency" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-politics-55706114" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a></sup> “The key thing is, we’ve got our fish back,” said Rees-Mogg. “They’re now British fish, and they’re better and happier fish for it.”<sup><a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/jacob-rees-mogg-fish-brexit-b1787271.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">26</a></sup></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/01/weekly-review-second-impeachment-capitol-arrests/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>