<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Harper's Magazine</title>
        <link>https://harpers.org/</link>
        <description>null</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 13:24:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/ruicosta042/rssconv-action</generator>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pafko at the Wall]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/pafko-at-the-wall-don-delillo-jennifer-egan-rowan-ricardo-phillips/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/pafko-at-the-wall-don-delillo-jennifer-egan-rowan-ricardo-phillips/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 04:01:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">“Sometime in late 1991,” Don DeLillo told a <em>Paris Review</em> interviewer in 1993, “I started writing something new and didn’t know what it would be—a novel, a short story, a long story. It was simply a piece of writing, and it gave me more pleasure than any other writing I’ve done.” The result was the novella “Pafko at the Wall,” first published as a <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/1992/10/pafko-at-the-wall/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Folio</a> in the October 1992 issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine,</em> making up a third of the issue’s length. “Wherein the Giants clinch the pennant, Bruegel descends, a bomb explodes, Sinatra sulks, and a Harlem boy plays his own game,” read that month’s cover. A slightly revised version would later become the prologue to <em>Underworld,</em> a novel often described as DeLillo’s masterpiece.</p>
<p>The story takes place during the National League playoff game of October 3, 1951, when Bobby Thomson of the New York Giants hit a pennant-winning home run over the head of Brooklyn Dodgers left fielder Andy Pafko—an event known to baseball fans as the “Shot Heard ’Round the World.” Here, though, the famous game serves mostly as background, its action serving to repeatedly bounce the reader’s attention back into the stands. DeLillo, a writer who has always been fascinated by the mechanics of spectacle, wants us to watch the watchers—some of whom, such as Frank Sinatra, the radio announcer Russ Hodges, and FBI director J. Edgar Hoover, are spectacle makers (and manipulators) themselves. Hovering over the proceedings, meanwhile, are suggestions of darker energy: the secret knowledge, possessed by only the paranoid Hoover, that the Soviets have just performed a successful nuclear-weapons test, and racial tensions, briefly transcended by fandom, that are unloosed in the scramble over a suddenly famous ball.</p>
<p>In this episode of the podcast, we bring you excerpts of “Pafko at the Wall,” which was performed live at the 92nd Street Y by Billy Crudup, Zachary Levi, and Tony Shalhoub, interspersed with commentary by the novelist Jennifer Egan and the poet Rowan Ricardo Phillips. The full recording of the performance will be released on March 30 by Simon &amp; Schuster Audio. A video of the performance will be available for two days at <a href="https://92y.org/pafko"><u>92y.org/pafko</u></a> beginning on Sunday, March 28, in anticipation of the audiobook’s release.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe title="Pafko at the Wall by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1016380741&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/pafko-at-the-wall-don-delillo-jennifer-egan-rowan-ricardo-phillips/" target="_blank">Pafko at the Wall</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-atlanta-shooting-boulder-shooting-donna-border-patrol/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-atlanta-shooting-boulder-shooting-donna-border-patrol/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 17:24:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Twenty-one-year-old Robert Aaron Long was arrested after he shot and killed eight people in three Asian spas in and around Atlanta, in what was the deadliest mass shooting in the United States since August 4, 2019, when Connor Betts shot 26 people in 32 seconds in Dayton, Ohio.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/georgia-massage-parlor-shootings-leave-8-dead-f3841a8e0215d3ab3d1f23d489b7af81" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/26-shot-32-seconds-details-videos-released-dayton/story?id=64953910" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> </sup>Long, who had also planned to drive to Florida to attack “some kind of porn industry,” told authorities that the massage parlors were “a temptation for him that he wanted to eliminate.”<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/race-and-ethnicity-shootings-georgia-crime-sex-addiction-ad7becb7a9691a794dc78579c21e66e4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> Crabapple First Baptist, the church that Long had attended since childhood, deleted all of its social-media accounts, which included photos of Long attending services and a video of the sermon its senior pastor, Jerry Dockery, gave on the Sunday before the shootings, arguing that Christ’s return was imminent and that he would lead a war “against all who rejected his name.”<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/religion/2021/03/17/atlanta-shooting-southern-baptist-pastors-wrestle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a></sup> “I don’t recall any sermons dealing specifically with racism, but the general tenor was to welcome and to be as inclusive as possible,” said Long’s former youth pastor. On Monday, it was reported that Mario González, husband of victim Delaina Yaun, had been handcuffed and detained but was not informed of his wife’s death for hours, and 21-year-old Ahmad Al Aliwi Alissa shot and killed 10 people in and around a supermarket in Boulder, Colorado, using an assault rifle 10 days after a judge blocked enforcement of a ban on such weapons.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/03/22/us/spa-shootings-officers-handcuffed-husband-of-victim-trndDelaina%20Yaun/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/03/23/us/boulder-colorado-shooting" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/colorado-supermarket-shooting-10-dead-3da92f0d3db65afdb373cc6bb534a711" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> Four people were shot and killed over the weekend in Chicago, as were five-year-old Mya Patel, by a stray bullet inside a motel in Shreveport, Louisiana; 28-year-old Alessia Mesquita, by the father of her one-year-old baby, in New Haven, Connecticut; 39-year-old Michael Anansingh, while waiting for his sister outside a bar he frequented, in Brooklyn, New York; 40-year-old Christopher Ray Martinez, who was targeted because he was romantically interested in the same woman as his shooter, in Austin, Texas; and 45-year-old street vendor Lorenzo Pérez, by someone pretending to be a customer, in Fresno, California.<sup><a href="https://chicago.suntimes.com/crime/2021/3/20/22341570/chicago-weekend-shootings-march-19-22-gun-violence-homicide" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://www.fox8live.com/2021/03/22/shooting-hotel-leaves-mother-child-injured-suspect-arrested/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://www.newhavenindependent.org/index.php/archives/entry/woman_shot_dead_in_the_heights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a> <a href="https://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/nyc-crime/ny-brooklyn-shooting-victim-shot-outside-bar-20210323-rbd5mpvyxvdkxnirwmgrlxtbnm-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://eldiariony.com/2021/03/23/lluvia-de-balas-un-muerto-y-un-herido-por-tiroteos-en-peleas-callejeras-en-nueva-york/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> <a href="https://www.kxan.com/news/local/one-person-dies-in-southeast-austin-shooting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://www.nbclosangeles.com/news/california-news/street-vendor-shot-killed-while-working-fresno/2556655/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a></sup> “I don’t apologize for thoughts or prayers!” Ted Cruz shouted during a speech in the Senate opposing new restrictions on firearms.<sup><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/ted-cruz-2651181596/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> “And the contempt of Democrats for prayers is an odd sociological thing!”</p>
<p>Representative Henry Cuellar, Democrat of Texas, released photographs of a Border Patrol detention center in Donna, Texas—the agency’s largest—because the Biden Administration has repeatedly refused access to reporters and external monitors.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/joe-biden-donald-trump-politics-immigration-border-patrols-73171bd6fd8494c16c8ca1f7f3f54130" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a> </sup>The Donna facility comprises a series of interconnected tents, and the thousands of minors being held there are rarely allowed outside and are forced to sleep on mats on the floor. “Children presenting at our border who are fleeing violence, or fleeing prosecution, who are fleeing terrible situations, is not a crisis,” the White House press secretary said during a press conference before Cuellar’s photographs were made public.<sup><a href="https://deadline.com/2021/03/jen-psaki-biden-administration-border-minors-migrant-children-1234719226/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> A fire at a camp for Rohingya refugees in Bangladesh displaced nearly 45,000 people; rescuers retrieved 15 corpses, and at least 400 people are still missing.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/bangladesh-united-nations-859aaf03e9478cfe412cf09356e5a570" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> “Can we call these peaceful protesters?” asked Zaw Min Tun, a spokesman for Myanmar’s military junta, as he showed footage of factories burning during a press conference about government crackdowns against demonstrators; he added that he was “sorry for their losses, as they are also our citizens.”<sup><a href="https://reuters.com/article/us-myanmar-politics/myanmar-junta-blames-protesters-as-eu-u-s-impose-sanctions-idUSKBN2BF07C" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a> </sup><a href="https://reuters.com/article/us-myanmar-politics-casualties/myanmar-military-spokesman-sorry-for-loss-of-lives-of-protesters-idUSKBN2BF0OL" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>20</sup></a> Narendra Modi sent a letter of goodwill to Pakistani prime minister Imran Khan; Australian prime minister Scott Morrison, who has blocked investigations into sexual misconduct by male parliamentary staffers, said that it was a “triumph of democracy” that rallies for women’s justice weren’t “met with bullets”; a Brazilian politician proposed spraying hand sanitizer over his town from helicopters and airplanes owned by “lots of businesspeople here”; and the screenwriter Jakub &#379;ulczyk announced that he had been indicted for calling Polish president Andrzej Duda a “moron” on social media, and now faces up to three years in prison.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-pakistan-india/indian-premier-modi-writes-goodwill-letter-to-pakistani-counterpart-minister-idUSKBN2BF2RM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/mar/15/scott-morrison-declares-it-a-triumph-that-march-4-justice-rallies-not-met-with-bullets">22</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-australia-politics/australian-pm-admits-public-anger-after-report-of-lewd-acts-in-parliament-idUSKBN2BF030" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/mar/16/brazil-covid-coronavirus-spray-hand-gel-from-planes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/joe-biden-donald-trump-media-poland-social-media-059e5db66925f01119c746625b9071e8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a></sup> The Kremlin announced that the identity of the COVID-19 vaccine administered to Vladimir Putin would remain a secret.<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-putin-vaccine/name-of-vaccine-russias-vladimir-putin-to-take-will-be-a-secret-says-kremlin-idUSKBN2BF149" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>26</sup></a></p>
<p>The Naked Cowboy was arrested for panhandling during Bike Week in Daytona Beach, Florida.<sup><a href="https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/york-city-performer-naked-cowboy-022805863.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a></sup> “I don’t need money—I’m already successful. I will never take their money again, I promise you,” said the entertainer, who regularly performs in Times Square. The first assistant district attorney of Bucks County, Pennsylvania, was demoted after it was revealed that he had been delivering DoorDash orders while on the clock.<sup><a href="https://philadelphia.cbslocal.com/2021/03/19/bucks-county-first-assistant-district-attorney-demoted-for-delivering-food-for-doordash-during-business-hours/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a></sup> After months of waiting, a Georgia man received his final paycheck from his ex-employer in the form of oil-covered pennies, which were dumped onto his driveway in the middle of the night.<sup><a href="https://whdh.com/news/man-waiting-on-final-paycheck-from-ex-employer-gets-500-pounds-of-oily-pennies-dumped-in-driveway/?fbclid=IwAR2G_mOmPgFOyiSiKBf4plHpur3pFDGzkkzTemn99qP1-d0MAwmGiomblCY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29</a></sup> “He got paid, that’s all that matters,” said his former boss. In the United Kingdom, the<em> Daily Telegraph </em>announced plans to tie journalists’ pay to the number of page views their articles garnered, and the highest court decided that caregivers who work overnight shifts would be paid only for hours when they are awake and working.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/mar/15/daily-telegraph-plans-link-journalists-pay-article-popularity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/mar/19/sleep-in-care-workers-not-entitled-minimum-wage-supreme-court?CMP=Share_iOSApp_Other" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>31</sup></a> Joseph Amato, a captain of the Colombo crime family, who, along with 20 other criminal associates, was arrested after he put a GPS tracker on his girlfriend’s car, pleaded guilty to racketeering and interstate stalking.<sup><a href="https://www.silive.com/crime-safety/2021/03/alleged-mob-capo-admits-si-shakedowns-planting-gps-his-son-cops-to-extortion-scheme.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a></sup> P&amp;O Cruises announced that it will offer “cruises to nowhere” for vaccinated travelers.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/travel/article/po-british-cruises-to-nowhere-vaccine/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">33</a></sup>—<em>Violet Lucca</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-atlanta-shooting-boulder-shooting-donna-border-patrol/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[False Prophets]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/false-prophets-dead-sea-scrolls/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/false-prophets-dead-sea-scrolls/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 17:34:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">In 2002, a new crop of Dead Sea Scroll fragments that were said to have come from the Swiss vault of the late antiquities dealer Khalil Iskander Shahin went up for sale. These fragments were bought by a number of evangelical institutions, including the Museum of the Bible, which was founded by the family that owns the Hobby Lobby chain of arts-and-crafts stores. In the March issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine,</em> <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/03/false-prophets-forged-dead-sea-scrolls/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Madeleine Schwartz</a> describes the odd provenance of the fragments and evaluates whether they could be forgeries.</p>
<p>In this episode, Schwartz and <em>Harper’s</em> web editor Violet Lucca discuss the tendency for self-delusion in the antiquities market, as well as the slow process by which counterfeit goods can be distinguished from genuine artifacts. They also consider the complex issue of ownership, given the colonial violence that has historically allowed Western countries to acquire relics. “[Knowing where objects came from] is hugely important for the ethical implications,” Schwartz says. “It’s also really important for the financial implications, because, in general, no one wants to think that what they own is either fake or going to lead them to having to deal with a lawsuit.”</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe title="False Prophets by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1010587384&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/false-prophets-dead-sea-scrolls/" target="_blank">False Prophets</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-covid-19-relief-bill-run-over-protesters-blockchain/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-covid-19-relief-bill-run-over-protesters-blockchain/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 15:21:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">On the one-year anniversary of the official declaration of the COVID-19 pandemic, President Joe Biden delivered a prime-time address to the nation in which he announced that all American adults will be eligible for vaccination by May 1, and expressed hope that Americans would be able to congregate, in small groups, for barbecues on the Fourth of July.<sup><a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/transcript-joe-biden-delivers-remarks-year-anniversary-pandemic/story?id=76403134" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a></sup> Biden signed into law the $1.9 trillion American Rescue Plan, which provides for a third round of stimulus checks; further funding for COVID-19 testing and vaccination; aid for struggling state and local governments, small businesses, and schools; and an expansion of the child tax credit, which was expected to cut child poverty by half and overall poverty by a third.<sup><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-10/what-s-in-the-1-9-trillion-stimulus-bill-biden-is-about-to-sign?sref=fMqly2w9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/child-tax-credit-stimulus-covid-relief-bill-2021-03-14/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/03/10/us/joe-biden-news" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>4</sup></a> The bill was compared by the Republican senator Mike Lee of Utah to a document “written in hell by the devil himself.”<sup><a href="https://www.deseret.com/utah/2021/3/10/22324379/mike-lee-says-devil-wrote-democrats-election-reform-plan-burgess-owens" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> Fellow Republican senator Lindsey Graham of South Carolina criticized a provision in the bill that provides aid to black farmers as “reparations,” and Florida’s Marco Rubio dismissed as “a joke” polling that suggested that three quarters of Americans, and some 60 percent of Republicans, supported the bill.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/senate/542483-graham-on-covid-19-relief-aid-to-black-farmers-thats-reparations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/senate-republicans-attack-bidens-stimulus-bill-polls-that-support-it-1575973" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> </sup>It was reported that President Biden’s dogs will be temporarily relocated to Delaware after one of them, Major, bit a Secret Service agent.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/white-house/biden-s-german-shepherd-major-involved-white-house-incident-resulting-n1260169" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a></sup></p>
<p>A district judge in Texas, where nearly 200 people are dying each day from COVID-19, ruled that the state attorney general could not force the city of Austin to repeal its mask mandate; the Canadian grocery chain Sobeys faced criticism for forcing people trying to sign up for COVID-19 vaccinations to allow their personal information to be used “for marketing purposes”; and the Philippine National Police, in an attempt to prevent the spread of COVID-19, announced a countrywide ban on public displays of affection, including kissing, hugging, and holding hands.<sup><a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2021/03/12/austin-mask-mandate-texas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://globalnews.ca/news/7688465/covid-19-vaccine-privacy-concerns/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a> </sup><a href="https://cnnphilippines.com/news/2021/3/10/PNP-prohibits-public-display-of-affection.html?" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>11</sup></a> The Kentucky Senate passed a bill that would criminalize the taunting or insulting of police officers, and the Oklahoma House of Representatives passed a bill that would provide legal cover to motorists who run over protesters.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/542284-kentucky-lawmakers-advance-bill-to-criminalize-insulting-police?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> <a href="https://www.koco.com/article/oklahoma-house-passes-bill-that-would-protect-drivers-who-hit-protestors/35796445#" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a></sup> “I simply want to make sure people on both sides of any issue are kept safe,” said Republican state representative Kevin McDugle, one of the bill’s co-authors. A nine-year-old burglary was solved by German police who matched DNA from a prisoner in France to a partially consumed sausage found at the crime scene.<a href="https://apnews.com/article/burglar-caught-over-german-sausage-bite-9d1386976208e91b98913bcc2c02d97a" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>14</sup></a></p>
<p>A JPEG file created by the digital artist known as Beeple called <em>Everydays—The First 5000 Days,</em> a collage including all the art that Beeple has posted online since 2007, sold for $69.3 million; another Beeple work, <em>Crossroad</em>—a 10-second animated video of people strolling around a massive, nude Donald Trump collapsed in a field—sold for $6.6 million.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/11/arts/design/nft-auction-christies-beeple.html?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> A blockchain company called Injective Protocol burned a 2006 Banksy screen print entitled <em>Morons,</em> which was intended to satirize the art market, and then sold the work for $380,000 as a digital token.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56335948?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> “We view this burning event,” said a company spokesperson, “as an expression of art itself.” Netflix was exploring new measures to prevent password sharing; a man in St. Louis was stabbed in the face by his nephew for refusing to divulge his Netflix password; and the government-funded Canadian Energy Centre mounted a campaign against the 2020 animated Netflix film <em>Bigfoot Family</em><em>,</em> alleging that the film, in which the eponymous cryptids lead an effort to stop an oil company from destroying the creatures’ native valley with a bomb, was “full of lies and misinformation.”<sup><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/netflix-password-sharing-crackdown/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a> <a href="https://www.kmov.com/news/man-stabbed-by-nephew-after-refusing-to-give-up-netflix-password/article_d208d144-8420-11eb-8684-572b7230cfe4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/calgary/canadian-energy-centre-bigfoot-1.5948163" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a> </sup>A group of scientists proposed that sperm, egg, seed, and spore samples from some 6.7 million species be sent to the moon aboard a lunar ark, after which they would be stored within a network of lava tubes, as a “modern global insurance policy” in the event of the complete collapse of Earth’s ecosystems.<sup><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/scientists-335-million-seed-sperm-egg-samples-moon-noahs-ark/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> The first walrus spotted in Ireland was suspected of having been carried across the Atlantic Ocean after falling asleep on an ice floe, and animal-rights groups protested the opening of a hotel at China’s Harbin Polarland theme park, where rooms face a pen housing several captive polar bears; the hotel was fully booked for the duration of the initial trial period.<sup><a href="https://www.independent.ie/news/first-ever-sighting-of-a-walrus-in-ireland-after-it-is-thought-to-have-drifted-across-atlantic-after-falling-asleep-on-iceberg-40195874.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/china-polar-hotel/chinese-polar-bear-hotel-opens-to-full-bookings-criticism-idUSL1N2LB04Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-covid-19-relief-bill-run-over-protesters-blockchain/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-covid-19-relief-package-dolly-parton-international-womens-day/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-covid-19-relief-package-dolly-parton-international-womens-day/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 20:52:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The Senate approved President Joe Biden’s $1.9 trillion COVID-19 relief package after the 628-page bill was read aloud in its entirety at the request of Wisconsin senator Ron Johnson.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/04/us/politics/stimulus-senate.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a></sup> “Good thing we have time during a national emergency to do this,” said Vermont senator Bernie Sanders.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/senate/541695-ron-johnson-forces-reading-of-senate-coronavirus-bill-on-floor" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a></sup> Kyrsten Sinema of Arizona, a former social worker and one of eight Democratic senators who voted against Sanders’s bill to increase the minimum wage, brought a large chocolate cake into the chamber for staff who had been forced to work through the night.<sup><a href="https://www.azcentral.com/story/opinion/op-ed/elviadiaz/2021/03/05/sen-kyrsten-sinema-brings-cake-kills-minimum-wage/4595660001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> Shaun Bailey, the Conservative candidate in London’s mayoral election, decried the concept of a universal basic income because recipients would spend it on “lots of drugs.”<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/mar/02/tory-london-mayor-hopeful-says-basic-income-would-be-used-for-lots-of-drugs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a></sup> “I’ve been a youth worker for over 20 years,” said Bailey. “I know some people would absolutely fly if you gave them a lump sum to deal with every week.” “We’re also going to work in heaven,” said the megachurch pastor Robert Jeffress on <em>The Jim Bakker Show.</em><sup><a href="https://twitter.com/ChristnNitemare/status/1368628774502273028" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> “God created us to be workers.” A Dutch entrepreneur created a new method to test for the coronavirus in which subjects enter a soundproof cabin and scream.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-netherlands-scream-idUSKBN2AW1VS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a></sup> The country music star Dolly Parton, who helped fund research for the Moderna COVID-19 vaccine, got vaccinated.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/02/world/dolly-parton-moderna-vaccine-covid.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> “Vaccine, vaccine, vaccine, vaccine,” she sang to the tune of “Jolene.” “Because once you’re dead, then that’s a bit too late.”</p>
<p>President Jair Bolsonaro of Brazil, which has the second-highest death toll from COVID-19 after the United States, told his constituents to stop “fussing and whining” about the pandemic.<sup><a href="https://www.france24.com/en/americas/20210305-bolsonaro-tells-brazilians-to-stop-whining-after-record-covid-19-deaths" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a></sup> In Myanmar, soldiers and police have sent hundreds of death threats via TikTok to protesters of last month’s coup.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-myanmar-tiktok/i-will-shoot-whoever-i-see-myanmar-soldiers-use-tiktok-to-threaten-protesters-idUSKBN2AW17X" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a></sup> The Department of Homeland Security deported hundreds of Haitian asylum-seekers, acknowledging that they “may face harm” upon their return.<sup><a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/hamedaleaziz/us-deporting-haitian-immigrants-despite-dangers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> The U.S. House of Representatives passed a bill that makes it illegal for federal law-enforcement officers to have sex with detainees, and a judge in India advised an accused rapist to marry his school-age victim or else be jailed.<sup><a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/house-passes-bill-making-it-illegal-for-federal-officers-to-engage-in-sex-acts-with-detainees_n_60410890c5b6ff75ac4212e9?9el" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/mar/04/indias-top-judge-tells-accused-rapist-to-marry-victim-to-avoid-jail" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a></sup> An Idaho state representative voted against funding for early education because he disapproved of “any bill that makes it easier or more convenient for mothers to come out of the home and let others raise their child.”<sup><a href="https://www.ktvb.com/article/news/local/208/idaho-republican-votes-against-education-funds-convenient-for-mothers-to-come-out-of-the-home/277-645ae7a7-601e-4557-9d7c-f8df5c22949c?utm_campaign=snd-autopilot" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a></sup> In Texas, a high school assignment about chivalry instructed girls to “dress in a feminine manner” to please men, and in Missouri, a Baptist pastor stepped down after delivering a sermon that pilloried women who gain weight after marriage and described Melania Trump as “the epic trophy wife of all time.”<sup><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/texas-schools-chivalry-assignment-told-girls-to-dress-to-please-men/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-56312443" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> A California man was accused of killing his wife, propping her up on a living room couch, and telling their children that she was hungover as they opened presents in front of her on Christmas Day.<sup><a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2021/03/09/anaheim-man-propped-dead-wife-on-couch-for-kids-opening-christmas-presents-prosecutor-says/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> “You will hear about a relationship that was full of arguing and yelling, but also a lot of love,” said his attorney, Heather Moorhead, who argued that the deceased got drunk and fell onto a glass table.</p>
<p>In Mexico, 81 people were injured during International Women’s Day protests against femicide and violence against women.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-womens-day-mexico/womens-day-clashes-in-mexico-leave-over-80-police-protesters-injured-idUSKBN2B12DD" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> It was reported that structural problems that led to worker injuries during the construction of the bridge named after Andrew Cuomo’s father were concealed; it remains unclear whether the bridge has been properly repaired.<sup><a href="https://www.timesunion.com/news/article/mario-cuomo-bridge-structural-problems-covered-up-15594755.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> The man who put his feet up on Nancy Pelosi’s desk during the January 6 Capitol riot interrupted his virtual hearing by screaming that it wasn’t fair that he was still in jail.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/news/541661-rioter-who-broke-into-pelosis-office-not-fair-im-still-in-jail" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> A man was arrested for carving <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">wwg1wga</span>, an abbreviation of the QAnon slogan “Where We Go One, We Go All,” and <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">iammark</span>, his Twitter handle, into a large stone table at an archeological site called America’s Stonehenge.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/541594-police-say-man-vandalized-americas-stonehenge-with-qanon-hashtag?fbclid=IwAR0fQNyIk6Bnea95hDIkRXCMx9yb4SM13lP7Nbkf9k5XHDw3WU9WulKDMjg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> The Queen of England said that she was sad.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-britain-royals-meghan/queen-elizabeth-says-saddened-by-harry-and-meghans-experiences-idUSKBN2B10TO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></sup>—<em>Annie Geng</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-covid-19-relief-package-dolly-parton-international-womens-day/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-cash-bail-biden-syria-ted-cruz/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-cash-bail-biden-syria-ted-cruz/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 19:52:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Illinois governor J. B. Pritzker signed a law ending cash bail and requiring police officers across the state to wear body cameras; the bill will take effect in 2023.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/23/us/illinois-cash-bail-pritzker.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a></sup> In Rochester, New York, a grand jury declined to charge any of the seven officers who were on the scene last March when they handcuffed Daniel Prude, placed a mesh bag over his head, and pressed him into the pavement until he lost consciousness; Prude, who was black, was experiencing a suspected psychotic episode and died a week after the incident.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/23/nyregion/daniel-prude-rochester-police.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> “We certainly do not want people to misinterpret the officers’ actions and conflate this incident with any recent killings of unarmed Black men by law enforcement nationally,” wrote a Rochester deputy police chief who advised against releasing body-cam footage of the incident. An American soldier who was indicted for conspiring with neo-Nazis to ambush his unit during a planned deployment to Turkey asked for the case to be dismissed because the grand jury didn’t include enough black and Hispanic members.<sup><a href="https://www.stripes.com/news/us/soldier-indicted-for-conspiring-with-neo-nazi-group-seeks-dismissal-because-grand-jury-wasn-t-racially-diverse-1.663177" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a></sup> The U.S. government released a four-page report concluding that Mohammed bin Salman, the crown prince of Saudi Arabia, had personally authorized the dismemberment of Jamal Khashoggi inside the Saudi Consulate in Istanbul, and announced sanctions against the Saudis involved in the killing except for the crown prince.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/26/us/politics/jamal-khashoggi-killing-cia-report.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a></sup> Russian diplomats escaped from North Korea on a hand-pushed railcar, and after a refugee set herself on fire, Greek officials charged her with arson.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/feb/26/russian-diplomats-leave-north-korea-on-hand-powered-rail-trolley-video" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://lenexweb.com/refugee-who-set-herself-on-fire-in-greece-is-charged-with-arson/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a> </sup>The Chinese government planned to restrict political candidates in Hong Kong to those it deems “patriots.”<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/23/world/asia/china-hong-kong-elections.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a></sup></p>
<p>In the first known use of military force by the Biden Administration, seven 500-pound bombs were dropped in Syria to retaliate against rocket attacks from an Iran-backed Iraqi militia; the attack killed 22 people, though international monitoring groups dispute how many of the dead belonged to the group being targeted.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/feb/25/us-airstrike-syria-iran-militia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a></sup> The U.S. Senate parliamentarian judged that a federal minimum-wage hike could not be passed under budget-reconciliation rules because it does not affect the national debt; the White House chose not to challenge the ruling.<sup><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/27/stimulus-update-house-passes-bidens-1point9-trillion-covid-bill-heres-whats-next.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a></sup> A new poll found that 20 percent of Americans would dump their partner in exchange for the ability to travel immediately.<sup><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/travel/news/2021/02/23/trivago-poll-38-percent-of-americans-would-give-up-sex-to-travel-again/4553545001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10</a></sup> The U.S. Food and Drug Administration approved a new one-shot COVID-19 vaccine from Johnson and Johnson, which announced that it would begin testing the efficacy of its vaccine on, among other age groups, newborns, and an elementary school student with COVID-like symptoms was placed in isolation inside a storage closet because of spacing limitations.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/02/28/world/covid-19-coronavirus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11</a> <a href="https://www.fox32chicago.com/news/symptomatic-south-carolina-elementary-student-who-visited-school-nurse-was-held-in-storage-closet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a></sup> Boston Dynamics, a company originally funded by the military but now attempting to expand into the civilian market, condemned a performance-art piece in which attendees will be able to remotely drive Spot, one of the company’s quadruped robots, around an art gallery while it is outfitted with a paintball gun on its back.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56182268" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a></sup> “They said they would give us another two Spots for free if we took the gun off. That just made us want to do this even more,” wrote one of the artists, who referred to the robots as “war dogs.” In India, a man died after being stabbed in the groin by his rooster after he had attached a knife to the bird for an illegal cockfight, and a university exam was postponed after it was revealed that the curriculum attributed special abilities to Indian cows as compared with foreign ones, such as that they have deeper emotions and that their dung can reduce radiation.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-56224144" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14</a> <a href="https://bdnews24.com/neighbours/2021/02/23/do-indias-cows-have-special-powers-government-curriculum-is-ridiculed" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a></sup></p>
<p>During Ted Cruz’s speech at the Conservative Political Action Conference in Orlando, Florida, where two men pushed a golden statue of Donald Trump down the halls of the Hyatt Regency hotel, the Texas senator promoted his podcast, criticized government public-health advisories regarding COVID-19, assured the crowd that the actress Gina Carano was “standing with us,” claimed that 60 percent of women named Karen had definitely voted for Joe Biden, and said that “Orlando is awesome. It’s not as nice as Cancún—but it’s nice!”<sup><a href="https://rev.com/blog/transcripts/ted-cruz-2021-cpac-speech-transcript-february-26" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/feb/26/trump-golden-statue-cpac-conference" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>17</sup></a> A plastic surgeon in California joined his traffic-court hearing via Zoom from the operating room, at one point showing a patient on the operating table.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/28/us/california-surgeon-zoom-traffic-violation-court.html?action=click&amp;module=Latest&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a></sup> “Yes, I’m in an operating room right now,” said the surgeon. “I’m available for trial. Go right ahead.” The University of Michigan closed and then reopened one of its libraries after discovering three venomous Mediterranean recluse spiders in the basement.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/venomous-spiders-michigan-library-636de89af9fc0dcafe7f040292083664" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a></sup>—<em>Cameron French</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/weekly-review-cash-bail-biden-syria-ted-cruz/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The New McCarthyism]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/03/the-new-mccarthyism-2/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/03/the-new-mccarthyism-2/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 22:52:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<div style="width: 200px; border: 1px solid black; background-color: white; margin-left: 30px; padding: 30px; padding-bottom: 30px; float: right; font-size: 90%;">A <a href="https://www.ledevoir.com/opinion/chroniques/596074/chronique-le-nouveau-maccarthysme" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">version</a> of this column originally ran in <em>Le Devoir</em> on March 1, 2021. Translated from the French by John Cullen.</div>
<p class="drop-cap">The escalating lunacy of what is considered the politically correct code of conduct, temporarily suspended during the American presidential campaign, firmly reinstated itself last month in the messy “McNeil–<em>New York Times</em> affair,” and everyone who’s concerned for the future of free speech in the United States should take note of this.</p>
<p>Regrettably, the <em>Times</em>’s dismissal of the journalist Donald McNeil Jr.—for the crime of having uttered the word “nigger” in front of some high school students more than a year ago, during a trip to Peru organized by the newspaper—isn’t a scandal glamorous enough to arouse a level of interest equivalent to the persecution of Émile Zola in the late nineteenth-century for defending Captain Alfred Dreyfus. According to my sources, McNeil is simply a good journalist with a difficult personality (one of his former colleagues described him to me as “a porcupine”). Despite his alleged antisocial behavior, McNeil has won numerous prizes over the course of his long career; more recently he has specialized in subjects related to health and science, including the AIDS virus, Zika, and COVID-19. In the summer of 2019, invited to serve as a guide for the students on their Peruvian journey, he became involved in a discussion about presumed racism in a student video. McNeil insists on the fact that he used “the N-word” in the discussion as information and not as a slur. The students, all of them white, apparently failed to appreciate McNeil’s incorrect choice of words. In late January 2021, the <em>Daily Beast</em> published an article that revealed how angry some of the students were at McNeil for his use of the word as well as for other remarks of his that they considered insensitive. The revelations caused outrage among many <em>Times </em>staffers, and pressure mounted until McNeil “resigned.” (For a fuller account of the dispute between McNeil and the <em>Times, </em>see McNeil’s <a href="https://donaldgmcneiljr1954.medium.com/">Medium posts</a>.)</p>
<p>And there we have it, McCarthyism and mob rule firmly in place at the newspaper of record. McNeil has now been branded a “racist,” in much the same way as in the 1950s Joseph McCarthy and his allies branded people “reds,” even though a great number of them had renounced Marxist ideology and had quit the Communist Party. It mattered little that the <em>Times</em>’s editor-in-chief, Dean Baquet, was obliged to take back an earlier public statement in which he foolishly declared, “We do not tolerate racist language regardless of intent.” After having thought about this statement for a few days, Baquet admitted his error and noted that “Of course intent matters when we are talking about language in journalism.” During Baquet’s period of reflection, though, <em>Times</em> columnist Bret Stephens had written a piece critical of Baquet that included this assertion: “Every serious moral philosophy, every decent legal system and every ethical organization cares deeply about intention.” It was out of the question that such a heretical idea would be published in the <em>Times</em>. But you can read <a href="https://nypost.com/2021/02/11/read-the-column-the-new-york-times-didnt-want-you-read/">Stephens’s article</a> in Rupert Murdoch’s <em>New York Post</em><em>,</em> to which the piece was leaked. We have reached the height of irony when the plutocratic ogre Murdoch and his tabloid newspaper have become the keepers of the liberal flame.</p>
<p>The McNeil affair serves to underline an accelerating tendency in the media, as in the society at large, to conduct moral witch hunts based on identity politics. Instead of communists, the hunters pursue racists and sexual predators. There’s no proof that McNeil is in fact a racist, but the accusation will stick to him for a long time, and like the leftist Hollywood screenwriters of the 1950s who were blacklisted for their support of communism, he’ll have trouble finding new employment. His denunciation by young students also recalls the China of Mao Zedong and his fanatical Red Guards, who tormented their insufficiently revolutionary elders. What’s even worse is McNeil’s pathetic “confession,” which is very 1930s Moscow. I’ll quote part of it: “To understand what was in the video, I . . . used the slur itself. I should not have done that. Originally, I thought the context in which I used this ugly word could be defended . . . The fact that I even thought I could defend it itself showed extraordinarily bad judgment.” Really? Since the year 2000, the <em>Times</em> has published “the N-word” 247 times.</p>
<p>Obviously, this is not to say that a New Stalinism is on the rise. Nevertheless, the normally healthy call for racial justice and equality has been contorted by incessant appeals to “diversity,” a word that has been drained of any meaning these days. Will establishing quotas for such and such a number of Blacks, Latinos, Asians, and women improve the sorry state of American journalism? Does an excellent journalist who happens to be white and male deserve to be sacrificed for the advancement of minorities? While the mainstream media scramble to augment their “diversity,” our industry is sinking dramatically in the face of the real danger: GAFAM’s massive theft of our content and our advertising revenue.</p>
<p>The underlying context of this crisis is the timidity and conformism of our intellectual culture. At the present moment, what’s missing from our media is a diversity of viewpoints. Tocqueville noticed this tendency to uniformity at the time of his tour of the United States in 1831–1832: “In America, the majority draws an intimidating circle around thought. Within those limits, a writer is free; but woe to him if he dares to step over the line. It’s not that he must live in terror of an auto-da-fé, but he is subjected to every sort of vileness and to daily persecutions . . . At length he yields, bent under the effort each day requires, and subsides into silence, as if feeling remorse for having spoken the truth.”</p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/03/the-new-mccarthyism-2/" target="_blank">The New McCarthyism</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-texas-blackout-ted-cruz-facebook-vaccine/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-texas-blackout-ted-cruz-facebook-vaccine/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 18:35:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The United States surpassed 500,000 COVID-19 deaths, and nearly every state experienced freezing temperatures.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-usa/bells-toll-for-lives-lost-as-u-s-reaches-500000-covid-deaths-idUSKBN2AM1Y4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/02/15/us/winter-storm-weather-live" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>2</sup></a> In Texas, the cold weather caused pipes to freeze and burst, and the increase in electricity usage overwhelmed the state’s power grid, leaving millions of Texans without power and potable water and driving a 27-year-old father to burn a baby gate for warmth.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2021/02/16/winter-storm-live-updates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/snowy-bbqs-burning-baby-gates-texas-tiktokers-capture-historic-storm-n1258383" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a> </sup>Senator Ted Cruz traveled to Cancún with his wife and daughters to meet his college roommate David Panton because, as Cruz later explained, he wanted to “be a good dad”; following widespread criticism, Cruz returned to Texas, apologized while wearing a state-flag face mask, and posted photographs of himself handing out bottled water to Texans.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/18/us/politics/ted-cruz-storm-cancun.html?auth=link-dismiss-google1tap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://www.axios.com/ted-cruz-cancun-college-roommate-birthday-ef53416b-9fec-4a71-912c-7c6dd83397f4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a> <a href="https://people.com/politics/ted-cruz-hands-out-water-in-texas-after-mexico-trip-backlash/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ted-cruz-mexico-vacation-amid-storm-b0cdc326db95bf25d93de9e877e05862" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a> </sup>“I didn’t want all the screaming and yelling about this trip to distract even one moment from the real issues that I think Texans care about, which is keeping all of our families safe,” the senator said. During an interview on the invite-only app Clubhouse, an Instagram influencer—whom opposition leader Alexei Navalny alleges is a daughter of Vladimir Putin—said that she believes the Kremlin has the right to poison people because the Illuminati created COVID-19.<sup><a href="https://www.znak.com/2021-02-17/predpolagaemaya_dochka_putina_poobchalas_s_avtorom_rassledovaniya_o_ney_v_clubhouse" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a> </sup><a href="https://twitter.com/maxseddon/status/1361939143379533827?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>10</sup></a> Navalny’s appeal of his prison sentence was denied, and he was fined for slander.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-russia-politics-navalny/kremlin-critic-navalny-loses-appeal-against-jail-term-idUSKBN2AK08Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11</a></sup></p>
<p>A man at a quarantine hotel in Thailand was threatened with a defamation suit after he posted photographs of cockroach legs he had found in his macaroni.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/19/world/worst-14-days-of-my-life-complaints-about-a-thai-hotel-quarantine-lead-to-a-defamation-threat.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a></sup> The Cambodian government, which in December jailed a woman for wearing a revealing outfit while livestreaming a clothing-and-makeup sale on Facebook, announced plans to implement a national internet gateway that, in addition to restricting access to certain websites, will require users to complete identification forms before going online.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-women-cambodia-facebook-trfn-idUSKCN226240?edition-redirect=uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a> </sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-cambodia-internet/cambodias-new-china-style-internet-gateway-decried-as-repression-tool-idUSKBN2AI140" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>14</sup></a> Facebook, which has been blocking pro-vaccine advertisements as part of its attempts to stop the spread of anti-vaccine content, prohibited the sharing of all news articles in Australia after the lower house of its Parliament passed legislation that would require the company to pay media companies for links to their coverage.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/feb/18/prime-minister-scott-morrison-attacks-facebook-for-arrogant-move-to-unfriend-australia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/feb/16/google-and-facebook-the-landmark-australian-law-that-will-make-them-pay-for-news-content" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/02/21/facebook-ad-pro-vaccine-ban-470304" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a></sup> Google fired a second prominent AI ethicist for “exfiltration of confidential business-sensitive documents and private data of other employees.”<sup><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/4fbebc3a-d714-4d79-9805-613303a29420" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a></sup> “It gives me the evil eye every time I leave home,” said Yevgenia Kvasova of the House of Soviets building in Kaliningrad, Russia, that has been scheduled for demolition because of structural defects.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/16/world/europe/kaliningrad-russia-soviet-union-house-of-soviets.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a></sup> A drug-sniffing dog discovered 44 pounds of cornflakes coated with sugar and cocaine that were en route to Hong Kong.<sup><a href="https://www.cincinnati.com/story/news/local/hamiltoncounty/2021/02/19/frosting-cereal-flakes-cocaine-say-federal-agents-cincinnati/4512513001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a></sup></p>
<p>The Miss India 2020 runner-up rode to a victory rally at her alma mater in her father’s auto rickshaw.<sup><a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/miss-india-runner-up-manya-singh-goes-on-a-victory-rally-in-her-fathers-autorickshaw/article33868497.ece" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21</a></sup> The luxury fashion brand Proenza Schouler cast Kamala Harris’s stepdaughter in its runway show, held in the Hamptons, because she represents “a whole new chapter” in American life; Hermès reported a 43 percent increase in sales in Asia; and a shopping-mall baron predicted that housebound consumers will soon begin “revenge shopping.”<sup><a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/story/2021-02-19/ella-emhoff-proenza-schouler-nyfw-fashion-show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a> <a href="https://www.pymnts.com/news/retail/2021/hermes-q4-results-outpace-luxury-rivals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/business-news/revenge-spending-vaccinations-could-bring-millions-shoppers-back-mall-will-n1257993" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24</a></sup> San Francisco plastic surgeons reported an increasing demand for smaller breast sizes, and the American Society for Dermatologic Surgery released a statement warning those who have had their lips injected with filler to exercise caution with the COVID-19 vaccine because it can cause temporary lip swelling.<sup><a href="https://sanfrancisco.cbslocal.com/2021/02/18/explant-expansion-plastic-surgeons-see-growing-demand-to-shrink-breast-size/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a> <a href="https://www.dermatologytimes.com/view/guidelines-address-covid-19-vaccine-concerns-related-to-dermal-fillers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">26</a></sup> “This [vaccine] is the hottest commodity that is out there right now,” said a health official in Orange County, Florida, where young women were caught attempting to receive shots while “dressed up as grannies,” and in Manatee County, Florida, a pop-up vaccination site with a “VIP list” was constructed for people living in its two richest zip codes.<sup><a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/nation-world/two-young-women-in-florida-dressed-up-as-grannies-to-get-vaccinated-health-official-says/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">27</a> </sup><a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2021/02/18/politics/manatee-county-vaccine/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>28</sup></a> Mercedes-Benz recalled 1,292,258 cars in the United States because the eCall feature sent inaccurate vehicle locations to emergency responders.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56071108" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">29</a></sup> A butane tank exploded inside a Texas Walmart and forced shoppers to evacuate the store; customers were permitted to reenter one hour later.<sup><a href="https://www.krgv.com/news/fiery-shopping-cart-prompts-evacuation-at-palmhurst-walmart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">30</a></sup>—<em>Jensen Davis</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-texas-blackout-ted-cruz-facebook-vaccine/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-second-impeachment-star-spangled-banner-act/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-second-impeachment-star-spangled-banner-act/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:55:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Former president Donald Trump was acquitted at the conclusion of his second impeachment trial; falling short of a two-thirds majority, the Senate voted by a 57–43 margin to convict him of inciting an insurrection on January 6 at the U.S. Capitol.<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/trump-acquitted-impeachment-riot/2021/02/13/dbf6b172-6e12-11eb-ba56-d7e2c8defa31_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>1</sup></a> “There’s no question—none—that President Trump is practically and morally responsible for provoking the events of the day,” said the Senate minority leader, Mitch McConnell, several minutes after voting to acquit Trump.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/13/us/mcconnell-trump-impeachment-acquittal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> The majority leader of the Michigan Senate—who had called the Capitol riot a “hoax from day one” and described it as “staged”—apologized and then was captured on a hot mic saying, “I frankly don’t take back any of the points I was trying to make.”<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/10/politics/mike-shirkey-hot-mic/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>3</sup></a> Tennessee lawmakers introduced legislation that would allow men to prevent women they impregnate from receiving abortions; an Iowa state legislator put forward a bill permitting disabled Iowans to hunt from motorized scooters; and the Texas lieutenant governor, Dan Patrick, after learning that the NBA’s Dallas Mavericks had gone 13 games without playing the national anthem, announced that he would prioritize passage of the Star Spangled Banner Protection Act, which would require the song to be played before “all events that receive public funding.”<sup><a href="https://lawandcrime.com/abortion/tennessee-legislator-who-suggested-white-people-may-become-slaves-one-day-introduces-bill-allowing-men-to-stop-abortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a> <a href="https://iowacapitaldispatch.com/2021/02/11/bill-would-allow-disabled-iowans-to-hunt-from-motorized-scooters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2021/02/10/dallas-mavericks-texas-national-anthem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a></sup> “We ARE the land of free [<em>sic</em>],” Patrick noted on Twitter.</p>
<p>It was reported that Trump had been on the verge of being put on a ventilator when he was infected with COVID-19 in October; Representative Ron White of Texas became the first sitting congressman to die of the disease; and scientists identified seven different variants of the virus around the United States.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/11/us/politics/trump-coronavirus.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-rep-ron-wright-dies-of-covid-19-11612803373?mod=itp_wsj&amp;ru=yahoo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/02/14/world/covid-19-coronavirus/a-new-study-identifies-seven-us-virus-variants-with-the-same-worrying-mutation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a></sup> The city of Seoul began offering free COVID-19 tests to cats and dogs. Daniel Kritenbrink, the U.S. ambassador to Vietnam, released a rap song in which he refers to himself as “the boy from Hanoi” and professes fondness for the city’s “hot spots and hot pots,” as well as <em>cà phê s&#7919;a &#273;á,</em> a traditional iced coffee drink.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-55991097" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/feb/09/boy-from-hanoi-us-ambassador-to-vietnam-releases-his-own-lunar-new-year-rap">11</a></sup> The Philadelphia police union demanded a 5 percent “accountability pay” salary increase in exchange for agreeing to wear body cameras, and a Beverly Hills police officer was accused of playing music by the Nineties ska-punk band Sublime while being filmed by a civilian so that the video would be subject to copyright infringement charges if it were posted on social media.<sup><a href="https://www.inquirer.com/news/philadelphia-police-contract-discipline-reform-accountability-20210209.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a> <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/bvxb94/is-this-beverly-hills-cop-playing-sublimes-santeria-to-avoid-being-livestreamed" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a></sup> New Zealand’s Parliament amended its dress code after the co-leader of the M&#257;ori Party likened neckties to “a colonial noose.”<sup><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/new-zealands-parliament-drops-tie-rule-after-maori-lawmaker-rawiri-waititi-ejected-11612963959?mod=itp_wsj&amp;ru=yahoo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14</a></sup></p>
<p>A mathematics professor at the National University of Singapore delivered a nearly two-hour online lecture while on mute, a Minnesota congressman entered an online meeting of the House Financial Services Committee upside down, and a Texas prosecutor partook in a Zoom hearing while equipped with a filter that made him appear to be a kitten.<sup><a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/singapore-professor-takes-class-for-two-hours-only-to-realise-it-was-on-mute-whole-time-7181499/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/10/politics/congress-tom-emmer-upside-down/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/desktop-source-zoom-cat-filter-lawyer-3281ef443178a8f8ed889be7dcbeee75" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a></sup> A survey of graves at the nation’s oldest continuously operating pet cemetery found that the most popular pet name of the last century was Princess.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/12/style/pet-names-most-popular.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a></sup> A Tennessee border collie named Lulu inherited $5 million, and Yorkshire and Panepinto micropigs learned how to play video games, though researchers noted that their ability fell short of “full mastery.”<sup><a href="https://www.newschannel5.com/news/8-year-old-border-collie-named-lulu-inherits-5-million-in-owners-will" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">19</a> <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/scientists-teach-pigs-how-to-play-a-video-game-and-pigs-are-good-at-it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a></sup> The video-game publisher Victura announced the development of a previously canceled “tactical shooter” called <em>Six Days in Fallujah,</em> reassuring customers that it was not a U.S. Army recruitment tool, and the arms manufacturer Kalashnikov announced production of a “gadget” shotgun with a built-in computer that would be marketed to “hipsters.”<sup><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/six-days-in-fallujah-publisher-insists-the-game-is-not-a-us-army-recruiting-tool" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21</a> <a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2021/02/09/kalashnikov-maker-targets-hipsters-with-gadget-gun-a72874" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a></sup> Scientists determined that the songs of fin whales could be used to map the ocean floor, and a musician managed to play C, C-sharp, and D notes on a 17,000-year-old wind instrument made from a conch shell that was discovered in a French cave.<sup><a href="https://www.upi.com/Science_News/2021/02/11/Fin-whale-songs-could-help-map-the-ocean-floor/6431613070586/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-56017967" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24</a> <a href="https://myfox8.com/news/offbeat/90-year-old-man-spends-10k-on-ads-to-tell-att-ceo-about-his-slow-internet-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a></sup></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-second-impeachment-star-spangled-banner-act/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-marjorie-taylor-green-trump-sag-david-hogg-mypillow-mike-lindell/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-marjorie-taylor-green-trump-sag-david-hogg-mypillow-mike-lindell/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">­­In a 230–199 vote, the House of Representatives stripped Republican congresswoman Marjorie Taylor Greene of her committee assignments after statements she had made years earlier on social media about QAnon, 9/11, mass shootings, and anti-Semitic conspiracy theories drew newfound attention.<sup><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2021/02/04/live-updates-house-to-vote-on-marjorie-taylor-greene-committee-seats/4383759001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1</a> <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/marjorie-taylor-greene-qanon-wildfires-space-laser-rothschild-execute.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2</a></sup> “I want to tell you: any source of information that is a mix of truth and a mix of lies is dangerous, no matter what it is saying,” said Greene, a former blogger for AmericanTruthSeekers.com.<sup><a href="https://youtu.be/V6qXE1q3Nv4?t=300" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/georgia-congressional-candidate-s-writings-highlight-qanon-support-n1236724" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">4</a></sup> The day after the vote, Greene, who inherited her father’s multimillion-dollar construction company, tweeted that “the Democrats (+11)” are “morons” for “giving some one [<em>sic</em>] like me free time,” adding, “This is going to be fun!”<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/mtgreenee/status/1357675098887577601" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5</a> <a href="https://variety.com/2020/politics/news/marjorie-taylor-greene-qanon-wins-election-1234822723/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">6</a></sup> MyPillow CEO Mike Lindell’s <em>Absolute Proof</em>, a three-hour documentary about fraud in the 2020 presidential election, aired on One America News Network with a disclaimer that it was “opinion only.”<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/news/537530-oan-to-air-three-hour-mypillow-ceo-movie" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">7</a></sup> Parkland activist David Hogg, whom Greene was recorded harassing on the street in 2019, announced plans to found a pillow company to rival Lindell’s.<sup><a href="https://www.fox4now.com/news/national-politics/parkland-survivor-david-hogg-plans-to-start-pillow-company-to-rival-mypillow-founder-mike-lindell" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8</a></sup> Jeff Bezos, whose net worth is estimated to have increased by 79.8 percent during the pandemic, announced that he will step down as chief executive officer of Amazon, citing a desire to focus on “other passions” such as Blue Origin, a company that aims to make space travel cheaper by reusing rockets.<sup><a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/company-news/email-from-jeff-bezos-to-employees" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">9</a> <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2020/12/01/american-billionaires-that-got-richer-during-covid/43205617/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">10</a></sup> GameStop’s stock price fell by nearly $165, and one television show and four movies, including one based on a book that has not yet been written, have been optioned about r/WallStreetBets and the stock’s impact on Wall Street.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/04/investing/gamestop-wallstreetbets-reddit/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22268952/gamestop-stock-stonks-reddit-wallstreetbets-movies-tv-shows-hbo-netflix" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">12</a></sup> Super Bowl LV, held in Tampa Bay, Florida, was attended by 25,000 fans who were separated by 30,000 cardboard cutouts.<sup><a href="https://www.nfl.com/news/official-attendance-expected-for-super-bowl-lv-25-000-fans-30-000-cutouts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">13</a></sup> “They are pretty cool looking,” an NFL spokesperson tweeted about the cutouts.</p>
<p>In Myanmar, tens of thousands of protesters, some of whom made a three-fingered salute like that from the Hunger Games series, rallied against the military coup and the detainment of de facto leader Aung San Suu Kyi.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/02/07/965097259/tens-of-thousands-rally-in-myanmar-protesting-military-coup" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">14</a> <a href="https://gizmodo.com/why-are-protestors-in-myanmar-doing-the-hunger-games-th-1846186981" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">15</a></sup> “Protest against the coup,” Suu Kyi urged in a letter published on the Facebook page of the country’s pro-democracy party.<sup><a href="https://gizmodo.com/why-are-protestors-in-myanmar-doing-the-hunger-games-th-1846186981" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">16</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-55882489" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17</a></sup> At least 23 people were arrested in Haiti after an attempt to overthrow President Jovenel Moïse, who has held office for five years and whose administration has been accused of employing gangs to violently suppress the opposition.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-55975442" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/07/world/americas/haiti-protests-President-Jovenel-Mois.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><sup>19</sup></a> The United Poland Party has proposed the creation of hospices that would include a separate room dedicated to crying for the use of women who, under the country’s abortion ban, will be forced to give birth to fetuses with fatal defects; according to the spokeswoman for the Polish justice ministry, the women would also be given “advice on what to do next.”<sup><a href="https://notesfrompoland.com/2021/02/03/polish-ministry-proposes-room-to-cry-in-for-women-forced-to-give-birth-by-abortion-ban/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20</a></sup> The Turkish government has been accused of rounding up Uighurs living in Turkey and deporting them to China in exchange for COVID-19 vaccines, and South Africa has suspended its rollout of the AstraZeneca vaccine after a study revealed “disappointing” results against the South African variant.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/turkey-beijing-coronavirus-pandemic-ankara-china-c8b714974552c484c501a5784efc117a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">21</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-55975052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">22</a></sup> A new study showed that human activities such as surfing and drilling have caused baby clown fish get lost on their way home, condemning some fish to forever wander the seas alone.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/04/science/ocean-marine-noise-pollution.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23</a></sup></p>
<p>“While I’m not familiar with your work, I’m very proud of my work on movies such as <em>Home Alone 2</em>, <em>Zoolander,</em> and <em>Wall Street: Money Never Sleeps</em>,” Donald Trump wrote in his resignation letter from the Screen Actors’ Guild.<sup><a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/files/SAG-AFTRAResignationLetterfromPresidentDonaldJTrump.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24</a></sup> The Texas Department of Public Safety has apologized after sending three Amber alerts about Chucky, the possessed doll from the Child’s Play horror film franchise.<sup><a href="https://nytimes.com/2021/02/03/us/department-public-safety-amber-alert-malfunction.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">25</a></sup> A police commander in Bellwood, Illinois, was charged with three counts of possession of child pornography, and police officers in Rochester, New York, were suspended after pepper-spraying a nine-year-old girl.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcchicago.com/news/local/bellwood-police-commander-charged-with-possession-of-child-pornography/2431545/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">26</a> <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/02/01/962813494/rochester-releases-video-of-police-pepper-spraying-9-year-old-girl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">27</a></sup> An Ontario couple were caught playing <em>Pokémon GO</em> in their van by police and fined $880 for nonessential travel.<sup><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/windsor/couple-pokemon-fined-covid-order-1.5901388" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">28</a></sup> The chair of New Hampshire’s House Commerce and Consumer Affairs Committee requested via an intermediary that Representative Anita Burroughs keep her pet cats out of the room during committee Zoom meetings.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/new-hampshire-cats-animals-fca206House%20Commerce%20and%20Consumer%20Affairs%20Committee02aab19f84fd98ff6a08989479" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">29</a></sup> The chair later explained, “I simply asked the ranking Democrat, ‘Do we really want to have cats parading in front of the legislator’s computer? Let alone stopping and getting petted so that someone may assume the cat is sitting in for the legislator?’”—<em>Annie Geng</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/02/weekly-review-marjorie-taylor-green-trump-sag-david-hogg-mypillow-mike-lindell/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>