<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Harper's Magazine</title>
        <link>https://harpers.org/</link>
        <description>null</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 19:38:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/ruicosta042/rssconv-action</generator>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Man Who Loved Presidents]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/07/the-man-who-loved-presidents/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/07/the-man-who-loved-presidents/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 19:38:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Perhaps you’ve heard of Jon Meacham, a former editor in chief at <em>Newsweek </em>and author of many popular histories about the United States. His books are ubiquitous and regularly make bestseller lists. Yet the ideas in them are frequently reductive, incorrect, and strangely in thrall to a distinctly American version of the great man theory. Meacham is committed to fetishizing the role of the president and the men who have filled it, arguing that the office ennobles its occupants more than it corrupts them. Meanwhile, he conspicuously ignores the bottom-up social movements and profound economic tensions that historians have long recognized as crucial forces in American history.</p>
<p>That is how Thomas Frank sees it, anyway. In his combined <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/07/jon-meacham-thomas-frank-soul-of-america/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">review</a> of Meacham’s new book, <em>The Soul of America</em>, and the HBO documentary based on it, Frank skewers a centrist hero who has become expert at whetting the MSNBC crowd’s thirst for neoliberal platitudes. For Meacham, once a staunch Reaganite, the close alliance he enjoys with President Biden is only the latest evidence of a commitment to subordinating matters of policy to a nebulous politics of character and “soul.” This week, Frank explains to web editor Violet Lucca Meacham’s overly romantic approach to history and what it elides, his connections to President Biden, and how his popularity reflects a larger shift away from the projects that once defined American liberalism.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="The Man Who Loved Presidents by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1084723057&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/07/the-man-who-loved-presidents/" target="_blank">The Man Who Loved Presidents</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Regarding Michael Pollan’s New Book This is Your Mind on Plants]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/07/regarding-michael-pollans-new-book-this-is-your-mind-on-plants/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/07/regarding-michael-pollans-new-book-this-is-your-mind-on-plants/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 16:44:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Michael Pollan’s new collection of journalism, <em>This is Your Mind on Plants</em>, recounts for the first time publicly the story of his decision to leave out key passages of his essay “<a href="https://harpers.org/archive/1997/04/opium-made-easy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Opium, Made Easy</a>,” which was published in the April 1997 issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine</em>. While I’m delighted that Pollan has reversed his self-censorship and restored the missing material—about making opium tea from his home-grown poppies and drinking the tea—I take issue with parts of his narrative, especially concerning my efforts, as publisher of <em>Harper’s,</em> to persuade him not to give in to fear that the Drug Enforcement Administration would raid his house and seize his property if we published the “recipe” for the tea as well as Pollan’s experience after consuming it. I refer readers to the author’s explanatory text in his new book, but I urge them to be skeptical about his version of what happened.</p>
<p>Pollan suggests that he was acting largely on the advice of our lawyer, Victor A. Kovner, who still represents <em>Harper’s Magazine</em>: that by cutting the riskier passages he would “minimize” his risk of prosecution under the absurdly harsh drugs laws of the era. While it’s true that Kovner did discuss various tactical and legal options with Michael, my recollection is that Victor was strongly and consistently in favor of publishing the piece in its entirety, which was certainly what the editor, Lewis Lapham, and I preferred and were urging Michael to do. Both Victor and I believed Michael’s fear of prosecution and arrest were greatly exaggerated, being confident that as a reporter he was protected by First Amendment guarantees. Describing the making and consumption of the opium tea was clearly an act of journalistic research, not a gratuitous attempt to get high with a controlled substance in a way that could be viewed, in Pollan’s words, as “taunting the government.” Victor and I also felt that the federal government would never risk hauling a writer for a major national magazine into court on such a flimsy charge and thus invite ridicule and criticism. To buttress his version of Kovner’s legal analysis, Pollan claims that Kovner cited <em>United States v. Progressive Inc.,</em> “a 1979 case in which the government had sought to stop <em>The Progressive</em> magazine from publishing an article containing instructions for making a hydrogen bomb, even though the instructions were based entirely on publicly available information.” This statement is disingenuous and incorrect. The two cases are not comparable: the government had sought and won an injunction against <em>The Progressive</em> to prevent publication of the piece, so that the Constitutional issue at stake was whether the government backed by a judge could impose “prior restraint” against a magazine as it did with the <em>New York Times</em> when the newspaper wanted to publish the Pentagon Papers. The government eventually dropped its case against <em>The Progressive</em>, and the article was published. With the Pollan article, there was never any question of pre-publication censorship by the government, only a concern about criminal prosecution. If we ever discussed the so-called H-bomb case, it was to reassure Michael that even reporting about something as sensitive and dangerous as nuclear weapons was protected by the First Amendment. No one would have argued—and no sane judge would have made the case—that building a hydrogen bomb and making opium tea were in any way equivalent.</p>
<p>Finally, there is the indemnification contract I signed on behalf of <em>Harper’s</em> that Pollan describes “as one of the most unusual contracts ever given to any writer by a publisher.” True, we promised to pay for just about everything bad that hypothetically might have befallen Michael and his family, including the value of his house and his legal defense. But I offered it with the goal of bucking him up so that we might publish the entire essay, uncensored. Evidently it had the opposite effect, since, as Pollan writes, “It was also frightening to read: <em>All the contingencies could actually happen</em>.” I didn’t think <em>any of the contingencies would actually happen</em>, and neither did Victor Kovner. We were just trying to calm a frightened writer.</p>
<p>Once he had the contract, Michael insisted on withdrawing the passages about making and drinking the tea. It was a bitter blow to me, because I have always put the freedom to publish in the forefront of my work, and I lost some respect for Pollan after that. His recent remarks on a radio podcast during which he laughingly speculates about my motives were simply not true: “My guess is he was hoping something would happen. He was hoping I would get arrested. This would put <em>Harper’s</em> on the map. This would be a giant case; he would take it in front of the Supreme Court, and he would. You know he has bottomless pockets.” But these nasty jibes also revealed a lack of seriousness and commitment about the very points he wanted to make in his <em>Harper’s </em>piece. “Opium Made Easy” was an excellent exegesis of the madness and hypocrisy of U.S. drug laws and the gratuitous viciousness of the government’s war against drug-users caught in the act of what are mostly victimless crimes. Since then, the statute of limitations has expired on Michael’s potential crime. But back then, Pollan took the easy way out. I don’t blame him for having been afraid. He just now shouldn’t try to lay responsibility for his decision on anyone but himself.</p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/07/regarding-michael-pollans-new-book-this-is-your-mind-on-plants/" target="_blank">Regarding Michael Pollan’s New Book This is Your Mind on Plants</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/07/weekly-review-pacific-northwest-heat-dome-ccp-anniversary/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/07/weekly-review-pacific-northwest-heat-dome-ccp-anniversary/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 16:54:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A “heat dome” in the Pacific Northwest led to hundreds of deaths across the United States and Canada.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/07/02/1012467409/hundreds-are-believed-to-have-died-during-the-pacific-northwest-heat-wave" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a></sup> Portland, Oregon, set a new temperature record of 108 degrees Fahrenheit, then set another record the following day when the temperature reached 112 degrees.<sup><a href="https://www.oregonlive.com/weather/2021/06/oregon-heat-wave-portland-expected-to-record-new-all-time-high-temperature-sunday.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a></sup> A new all-time temperature record was also set in Canada, where it reached 115 degrees in the town of Lytton, 90 percent of which was subsequently destroyed in a wildfire.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/28/1010836214/all-time-records-fall-as-a-heat-wave-roasts-the-northwest-u-s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> </sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/07/01/lytton-canada-evacuated-wildfire-heatwave/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>4</sup></a> Streetcar cables in Portland melted, roads in Washington State warped and cracked, and cherry and pea harvests across the region were decimated.<sup><a href="https://gizmodo.com/dangerous-heat-wave-is-literally-melting-critical-infra-1847186624" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.sfgate.com/weather/article/washington-state-roads-buckling-heat-wave-weather-16279055.php?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/03/us/washington-state-heat-farmers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> The Gulf of Mexico burst into flames after an underwater pipeline leached gas into the ocean.<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/07/03/americas/gulf-of-mexico-fire-intl/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>8</sup></a> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The footage is pretty alarming,”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> said </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">an Ocean Conservancy employee. “It looks like the gates of hell are opening up.” The city of Miami performed a controlled demolition of the remaining part of the Champlain Towers South complex, a residential building in Surfside that collapsed in late June,  because of concerns about Tropical Storm Elsa.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/07/04/us/miami-dade-building-collapse-sunday/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a></sup> A planned detonation of illegal fireworks by the Los Angeles Police Department in the middle of a South Los Angeles street injured 17 people and caused damage on several city blocks.<sup><a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2021-07-02/how-did-the-lapd-blow-up-a-south-l-a-block-seizing-fireworks" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> “Why didn’t they do this somewhere else?” asked one local resident.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Former Secretary of Defense Donald Rumsfeld, a primary architect of the war in Afghanistan, in which some 241,000 people have been killed, and the war in Iraq, in which some 288,000 people have been killed, died at home in Taos.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/30/us/politics/donald-rumsfeld-dead.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://watson.brown.edu/costsofwar/costs/human/civilians/afghan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> </sup><a href="https://www.iraqbodycount.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>13</sup></a> Without informing the new commander, U.S. troops abandoned Bagram Air Base, their last military outpost in Afghanistan, and it was reported that Pok</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">é</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mon from the Pok</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">é</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mon Go mobile game were left behind.<sup><a href="https://www.stripes.com/theaters/middle_east/2021-07-02/pokemon-go-bagram-troop-withdrawal-2027917.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a> </sup><a href="https://www.stripes.com/theaters/middle_east/2021-07-02/pokemon-go-bagram-troop-withdrawal-2027917.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>15</sup></a> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I’m sure somewhere in Afghanistan, some kid is bragging about how he took control of an American Pok</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">é</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mon gym,” said one National Guardsman. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Louisiana man was arrested after he impersonated a police officer and pulled over an off-duty sheriff’s deputy who recognized the man from a domestic incident earlier this year; and a Colorado man who shot and killed a man who had shot and killed a police officer and was then subsequently shot and killed by police was hailed by police as a “hero.”<sup><a href="https://www.kiro7.com/news/trending/louisiana-man-accused-impersonating-cop-pulls-over-off-duty-deputy/YZYQZPMBLVFUDLGAMG62MEKT3E/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a> <a href="https://thehill.com/changing-america/respect/equality/560798-police-chief-hails-good-guy-with-a-gun-after-officer-kills" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> Massachusetts State Police arrested 11 men who identified themselves as part of an antigovernment group called Rise of the Moors after an armed standoff with law enforcement on the shoulder of I-95, and disoriented homing pigeons blocked an exit ramp on I-95 in Florida.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/07/03/1012924207/i-95-partially-closed-for-hours-after-police-standoff-with-armed-men" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a href="https://www.kob.com/news/homing-pigeons-that-cant-find-their-home-block-i-95-exit/6157897/?cat=648" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> “It’s the worst case scenario,” Volusia County officials said in a statement. “Homing pigeons that can’t find their home.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">China celebrated the 100th anniversary of the CCP with a mass wedding, a trivia contest, and a speech in which President Xi warned foreign governments that those who interfere in China’s affairs will have their “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">heads bashed bloody against a great wall of steel forged by over 1.4 billion Chinese people.”<sup><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/for-its-100th-birthday-chinas-communist-party-gets-a-bad-rap-11625149768?mod=itp_wsj&amp;ru=yahoo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> </sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/china-party-heads-bashed-xi/2021/07/01/277c8f0c-da3f-11eb-8c87-ad6f27918c78_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>21</sup></a> A</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">nalysts reported that China had begun construction on a vast field of missile silos in Gansu province.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/china-nuclear-missile-silos/2021/06/30/0fa8debc-d9c2-11eb-bb9e-70fda8c37057_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup> An 87-year-old Tokyo man who had been evicted during construction for the 1964 Olympics was once again evicted so that the city could build an Olympic stadium.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/sad-lonely-feeling-tokyo-man-evicted-twice-50-years-apart-olympic-construction-2021-07-01/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> A wunderkind from Belgium whose goal is to secure “immortality” received his bachelor’s degree in physics; scientists in the Netherlands advised those who test positive for COVID-19 to avoid contact with their cats or dogs; and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention warned Americans about the danger of swimming with diarrhea.<sup><a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/belgian-dutch-child-prodigy-gets-bachelors-degree-in-physics-at-age-11-immortality-is-my-goal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> <a href="https://theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/covid-common-pet-cats-dogs-owners-study-domestic-animals" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/CDCgov/status/1410677082435117059" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup></span></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/07/weekly-review-pacific-northwest-heat-dome-ccp-anniversary/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-iraq-syria-drones-john-mcafee/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-iraq-syria-drones-john-mcafee/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 13:33:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Derek Chauvin, who pressed his knee onto George Floyd’s neck for nine minutes and 29 seconds while arresting Floyd under suspicion of possessing a counterfeit $20 bill, was sentenced to 22 and a half years in prison for second-degree unintentional murder, third-degree murder, and second-degree manslaughter.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/25/us/derek-chauvin-22-and-a-half-years-george-floyd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/19/us/george-floyd-bill-counterfeit.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>2</sup></a> Motivated by the discovery of the remains of 215 indigenous children at the site of a residential school in British Columbia, members of the Cowessess First Nation announced that they had detected, with ground-penetrating radar, as many as 751 bodies, including both children and adults, at a residential school in Saskatchewan that closed in 1996.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/24/world/canada/indigenous-children-graves-saskatchewan-canada.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/28/world/canada/kamloops-mass-grave-residential-schools.html?searchResultPosition=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a></sup> The Ganges’s rising tides unearthed more bodies of COVID-19 victims in Uttar Pradesh, and Indian authorities announced that an Air Force station in Kashmir had been attacked by two drones, and that it would therefore need upgraded equipment to keep abreast of future strikes.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/swelling-ganges-opens-up-indias-riverside-graves-2021-06-25/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/kashmir-india-religion-5aa73efb693b3a6bda7739dbdba027a3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a></sup> “This action in self-defense to do what’s necessary to prevent further attacks, I think, sends a very important and strong message. And I hope very much that it is received by those who are intended to receive it,” said Secretary of State Antony Blinken regarding drone attacks in Iraq and Syria that were authorized by Joe Biden and that were immediately condemned by Iraq’s military as violations of national sovereignty and international conventions; before Biden’s meeting with Afghan president Ashraf Ghani, the U.S. military also drone-bombed parts of Afghanistan.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/joe-biden-syria-iran-middle-east-iraq-47774c2b5a6862353c8c6751738e7ba0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> <a href="https://it.usembassy.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-italian-foreign-minister-luigi-di-maio-at-a-joint-press-availability/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://www.stripes.com/theaters/middle_east/2021-06-28/Iraq-US-militias-airstrike-Syria-Iran-1870523.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/world/us-launches-drone-strikes-afghanistan-biden-ghani" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a> </sup>New polling showed that a majority of independents and one fifth of Republicans are at least somewhat approving of Biden.<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/06/25/fox-news-polling-shows-majority-approval-biden-not-that-youll-hear-about-it-much-fox-news/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>11</sup></a></p>
<p>John McAfee—the founder of the world’s first antivirus software company, who once faked a heart attack in a Guatemalan jail to avoid being extradited to Belize for questioning about the murder of his neighbor—was found dead in his prison cell after Spanish authorities agreed to extradite him to the United States on charges of tax evasion and cryptocurrency fraud.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/27/john-mcafee-obituary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2012/12/13/justice/florida-john-mcafee/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> </sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/videos/world/2012/12/10/savidge-guatemala-mcafee.cnn" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>14</sup></a> A Catalonian autopsy ruled that the former Libertarian candidate for U.S. president committed death by suicide, though his widow, Janice McAfee, has called for a second, independent autopsy.<sup><a href="https://reuters.com/world/autopsy-shows-john-mcafee-committed-suicide-spanish-prison-cell-el-pais-says-2021-06-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> “I blame the U.S. authorities for this tragedy. Because of these politically motivated charges against him, my husband is now dead,” said Janice.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/software-entrepreneur-john-mcafee-was-not-suicidal-widow-says-2021-06-25/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> “He would never quit this way.” It was reported that Hikvision, a surveillance company that is allegedly complicit in the ongoing genocide of the Uighurs, has hired former members of Congress as lobbyists to fight U.S. sanctions against the company; Governor Greg Abbott of Texas announced that jail employees would be enlisted to work with the Border Patrol “in the Biden Administration’s absence” two days after the administration fired the Trump-era Border Patrol chief Rodney S. Scott; and Boris Johnson’s government—whose married health minister, Matt Hancock, stepped down after he was photographed violating social-distancing rules by kissing his married adviser—announced that, despite the rise of Delta-variant cases in the United Kingdom, July 19 will be Freedom Day, when most COVID-19 restrictions in the country will be lifted, and encouraged children to sing an original celebratory song with the lyrics, “We are Britain and we have one dream / To unite all people in one great team / Strong Britain, great nation.”<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/06/25/china-hikvision-lobbying-fara-moffett-vitter-boxer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a> <a href="https://gov.texas.gov/news/post/governor-abbott-issues-statewide-call-for-jailers-to-assist-border-sheriffs-with-increased-arrests-related-to-border-crisis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a href="https://nytimes.com/2021/06/23/us/politics/rodney-scott-immigration-trump.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a> <a href="https://reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/uk-looks-set-ease-restrictions-july-19-sun-cites-pm-saying-2021-06-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/26/world/europe/matt-hancock-britain-resigns.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/uk-looks-set-ease-restrictions-july-19-sun-cites-pm-saying-2021-06-28/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> <a href="https://www.onebritainonenation.com/videos" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> Two 56-year-old Greek men were arrested for attempting to sell a Roman-era statue of Hecate.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/europe-business-global-trade-arrests-government-and-politics-2cc2de1cc7e95b17164fd618a2d77421" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a></sup></p>
<p>At least 5,000 birds disappeared during a British pigeon race.<sup><a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/pigeon-racing-vanishing-mystery-b1872623.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a></sup> “Most of the breeders I’m talking to are blaming the atmospheric conditions,” said one pigeon fan. “But no one really knows.” An Egyptian man was arrested in Kuwait for complaining on TikTok about bad weather.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/kuwait-middle-east-persian-gulf-tensions-arrests-weather-ae492e450fe4ab2c3f05107f270f9ad9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> A Tennessee woman who sent feces and a used menstrual pad to her husband’s ex-wife was charged with two counts of mailing biohazardous materials.<sup><a href="https://charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/national/article252305783.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a> </sup>Scientists found that—either because a composite of alternative ingredients had been used or because the tuna had been heavily processed—no tuna DNA was present in three randomly tested Subway tuna sandwiches.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/19/style/subway-tuna-sandwich-lawsuit.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a></sup> Olympics organizers cautioned athletes not to use their free condoms, and in California, Sacramento officials encouraged residents to add lemon juice to tap water that tasted like dirt.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/18/tokyo-2020-olympic-athletes-160000-free-condoms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/22/us/sacramento-water-taste-drought/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a></sup> Police officers in Lackawanna County, Pennsylvania, broke up an exorcism for lumber held inside a Home Depot.<sup><a href="https://www.pennlive.com/news/2021/06/police-break-up-exorcism-at-pa-home-depot.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a></sup> A silent disco in the Netherlands was shut down by the police following a noise complaint.<sup><a href="https://nltimes.nl/2021/06/25/silent-disco-ended-noise-complaints" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a></sup>—<em>Violet Lucca</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-iraq-syria-drones-john-mcafee/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hard Bargain]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/hard-bargain-bessemer-alabama-amazon-unionization/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/hard-bargain-bessemer-alabama-amazon-unionization/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:44:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Tales of the harrowing—and often degrading—working conditions at Amazon have spread far and wide. Yet the company has successfully circumvented attempts to change its ways. With the aid of extremely accommodating local, state, and national officials, America’s second-largest company (right after Walmart) has developed an elaborate system of workplace surveillance and anti-union propaganda to prevent its low-wage workers from organizing.</p>
<p>In the July issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine</em><em>,</em> <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/07/hard-bargain-amazon-unionization-bessemer-alabama/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Daniel Brook</a> relates the concerns of workers in and around the Amazon fulfillment center in Bessemer, Alabama. The warehouse attracted national attention this spring when it played host to a fierce battle over unionization. Pro-union workers lost by a margin of more than two to one, but Brook shows that the internal deliberations were far more complicated than the results suggest. Both pro- and anti-union workers in the area also struggle with the legacy of Reconstruction, when racist and socioeconomic controls on working class people were codified into law. On this week’s episode of the podcast, Brook unpacks the lessons of his trips to Bessemer with <em>Harper’s</em> web editor Violet Lucca. In their conversation, Lucca and Brook speculate on what lies ahead for the Amazon precariat—and for the consumers who depend on their labor.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Hard Bargain by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1075953100&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/hard-bargain-bessemer-alabama-amazon-unionization/" target="_blank">Hard Bargain</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[News You Can Use]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/news-you-can-use/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/news-you-can-use/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 18:38:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<div style="width: 200px; border: 1px solid black; background-color: white; margin-left: 30px; padding: 30px; padding-bottom: 30px; float: right; font-size: 90%;">A <a href="https://www.ledevoir.com/opinion/chroniques/608325/l-edition-du-samedi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">version</a> of this column originally ran in <em>Le Devoir</em> on June 7, 2021. Translated from the French by Elettra Pauletto.</div>
<p class="drop-cap">When I was a young reporter for a daily newspaper in Chicago, I soon learned that the Saturday edition could be used to “hide” articles that might risk attracting negative attention—even downright anger—from the top editors. They’d be too busy working on the Sunday edition—with its higher page count and circulation—to notice. So, if you wanted to pitch a dissident story and avoid editorial interference or offending the paper’s friends, the time to do so was toward the end of the day on a Friday afternoon.</p>
<p>That’s how I stumbled upon a buried treasure in the <em>New York Times</em>. It was published on May 15, a Saturday of course, and it talked about the long-term wage stagnation among the least educated people, those left out of the wealth boom of the techno-financial class that now dominates American society. At the bottom of the front page of the Business section was the headline, in the form of a question, “Is Washington at Fault for the Wage Gap?” The dominant thesis, often promoted by the <em>Times</em>, claims that the automation of labor has caused an inevitable, widening chasm between workers from the small top bracket of society and those from the large bottom bracket. But now, the <em>Times</em> was asking whether the authors of a new economic study were right to suggest that this gap actually was due to “intentional policy decisions.”</p>
<p>The study was conducted by the Economic Policy Institute (EPI), a think tank affiliated with the politically moderate left, and it is well worth a read. In fact, the authors of the study, Lawrence Mishel and Josh Bivens, are more candid than the <em>Times’</em> explanation of the study gives them credit for. “We refer in this analysis to wage <em>suppression</em><em> </em>rather than wage <em>stagnation</em><em> </em>because it was an actively sought outcome—engineered by policymakers who invited and enabled capital owners and business managers to assault the leverage and bargaining power of typical workers, with the inevitable result that those at the top claim a larger share of income.” The researchers state that between 1979 and 2017, pay for median workers lagged behind national productivity growth by 43 percent. In the 38 years analyzed in the study, the bottom 90 percent of workers suffered an anemic rise in salaries to the benefit of the top 10 percent, “mostly highly credentialed professionals and corporate managers.”</p>
<p>How did these clever policymakers in Congress—supported by hundreds of academic economists—achieve their ambitions? In many different ways: excessive austerity measures meant to increase unemployment and control inflation; the globalization of big business and of the work force, aimed at pitting American workers against cheap foreign labor; a brutal war on unions; the effective lowering of a minimum wage already eroded by inflation and weakening regulations, including on overtime; more numerous and more restrictive contracts; the deregulation of industry, the rise in mergers, and the outsourcing of production that led to an extraordinary concentration of power in purchasing and employment negotiations.</p>
<p>At times, the EPI’s analysis seems somewhat superficial—for example, when it references the effects of free trade on the labor market. However, it does take into account trade agreements such as NAFTA, which harm not just workers in the Rust Belt but also workers in occupations that aren’t directly affected by outsourcing: “While landscapers may not be displaced by imports, their wages suffer from having to compete with apparel (and auto, and steel) workers who have been displaced by imports.” Add to that number the eight million undocumented immigrants—the vast majority of whom work for lower wages than what is guaranteed by the law in all fifty states—and it’s easy to understand just how much workers suffer from an increasingly globalized market.</p>
<p>What is missing from this remarkable study is the “why.” As career economists, Mishel and Bivens rather naively explain how neoliberalism reached “great prominence, even in the Democratic Party,” as if they were unaware of the cynical transformation of the party into a corporate- friendly entity as far back as the 1970s. The “why” is that the neoliberal project promoted by the so-called New Democrats, and led by Bill Clinton, was conceived to fish in Republican waters and thus gather as much money as possible from Wall Street and big business in order to finance their electoral campaigns. The moral support they received from a neoliberal consensus in universities and in the mainstream media did not go unnoticed by the leadership of what had traditionally been known as the “party of labor.”</p>
<p>It’s clear that politicians from both the Republican and the Democratic sides have waged a four-decades-long war on the working and middle classes. What’s not so clear is why the <em>Times</em>, the quasi-official paper of the Democratic Party, would even report on this study. Why bother to mention it in a little-read Saturday edition after the war has more or less been won? Did the editors run it then on purpose? Or was it the work of a cunning journalist just taking advantage of a distracted boss one fine Friday evening?</p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/news-you-can-use/" target="_blank">News You Can Use</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-juneteenth-critical-race-theory-panic-storms/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-juneteenth-critical-race-theory-panic-storms/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 17:26:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Juneteenth—which commemorates when, two and a half years after the Emancipation Proclamation, formerly enslaved people on the Gulf Coast of Texas learned that they were free—became the United States’ 12th federal holiday.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/joe-biden-holidays-juneteenth-lifestyle-f8648a23f2f6bdb2db3d648458828651" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a></sup> Opal Lee, whose family home in Fort Worth, Texas, was burned to the ground by a white-supremacist mob exactly 82 years before, was given the pen the president used to sign the bill into law; celebrations took place across the United States as well as in Nacimiento, Mexico, where hundreds of slaves escaped via the Southern Underground Railroad; and the Ford Motor Company—whose founder pressured dealerships to carry copies of the <em>Dearborn</em> <em>Independent,</em> which ran his column “The International Jew: The World’s Problem” on its front page—ran a Juneteenth television commercial that concluded with the voice-over, “While all are created equal, it takes all to create equality.”<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/17/1007498876/how-juneteenth-became-national-holiday" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.galvnews.com/news/article_8c84c315-be7e-5274-9753-746d15c27c0d.html?block_id=531919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/article/across-the-border-this-mexican-community-also-celebrates-juneteenth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://www.ispot.tv/ad/OMNd/ford-juneteenth-t1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.thehenryford.org/collections-and-research/digital-resources/popular-topics/henry-ford-and-anti-semitism-a-complex-story" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a></sup> “How many holidays do we want?” asked a South Carolina representative, one of 14 congressmen who opposed federal observance of the holiday.<sup><a href="https://www.businessinsider.in/politics/world/news/gop-congressman-lashes-out-at-juneteenth-becoming-a-federal-holiday-are-we-going-to-do-one-for-the-native-american-indians/articleshow/83668510.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> “Do we want twenty? Are we gonna do one for the Native American Indians? I mean, where does it stop?” In response to the ongoing controversy over critical race theory, an academic approach to interrogating structural racism that Ted Cruz has described as “every bit as racist as Klansmen in white sheets,” the governor of Texas signed a bill that restricts how current events are discussed in K–12 classrooms; requires students to learn about “the civic accomplishments of marginalized populations” such as the 1924 Snyder Act, which granted Native Americans citizenship but not the right to vote; and proclaims that slavery is antithetical to the country’s “authentic founding principles.”<sup><a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2021/06/15/abbott-critical-race-theory-law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://capitol.texas.gov/tlodocs/87R/billtext/pdf/HB03979F.pdf#navpanes=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://www.kxan.com/news/political-news/texas-sen-ted-cruz-critical-race-theory-is-as-racist-as-klansmen-in-white-sheets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a> </sup><a href="https://www.loc.gov/classroom-materials/elections/right-to-vote/voting-rights-for-native-americans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>11</sup></a> Seventeen other states are considering similar laws, not including Alabama, where, after being asked to provide an example of the implementation of critical race theory, a state representative mentioned reading about a government reeducation camp for white men but, when pressed, couldn’t find the article.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/nbcblk/map-see-which-states-have-passed-critical-race-theory-bills-n1271215" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> </sup><a href="https://www.al.com/news/2021/06/whitmire-alabama-lawmaker-wants-to-ban-critical-race-theory-so-i-asked-him-what-it-is.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>13</sup></a> “Must have deleted the link,” he said. The San Jose Sharks tweeted and then deleted an illustration of the team’s mascot biting through a slave’s chains, and a robot ship using artificial intelligence to retrace the voyage of the <em>Mayflower</em> turned back toward England.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/media/558852-the-nhls-san-jose-sharks-ridiculed-for-juneteenth-twitter-post" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/science-oddities-lifestyle-technology-business-2c7bde56c626daa255e906e3423c8116" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup></p>
<p>In commemoration of the 1967 capture of Jerusalem, conservative Israelis marched across a plaza near the Damascus Gate that police had prevented Palestinians from accessing during much of Ramadan; Hamas retaliated with incendiary balloons; and Israel responded with bombs.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/15/world/middleeast/israel-coalition-hamas.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> The Palestinian Authority refused to accept more than a million COVID-19 vaccine doses offered by Israel because many of them had expired or would soon do so.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/18/world/middleeast/israel-palestine-vaccine-deal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> Joe Biden and Vladimir Putin met at a Geneva villa to discuss nuclear arms, cybersecurity, and human rights.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/06/16/world/biden-putin" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> Despite his criticism of Putin for interfering with foreign elections, which the United States has done at least 81 times, Biden described the summit as “positive,” and Putin said it was “quite constructive.”<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/thehill/status/1405219989712424966" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a> <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/noor-bin-ladin-trump-flag-outside-biden-putin-summit-video-2021-6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> On a motorboat outside the villa, a niece of Osama bin Laden raised a flag that read <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">trump won.</span> The Supreme Court upheld the Affordable Care Act; ruled that a Catholic social-services organization could not be excluded from a municipal foster-care program because of its refusal to work with same-sex couples; and rejected a lawsuit alleging that the corporations Nestlé and Cargill are complicit in West African child slavery.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-catholic-agency-same-sex-foster-care-004b978239e41675524859ae79a5333b" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-dismisses-obamacare-challenge-67cc2e9604a70b1b329c5f3b4177a688" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> </sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-catholic-agency-same-sex-foster-care-004b978239e41675524859ae79a5333b" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>23</sup></a> “Drink water,” Cristiano Ronaldo said at a press conference after moving two Coca-Cola bottles out of frame.<sup><a href="https://www.goal.com/en/news/drink-water-ronaldo-shuns-soda-sponsor-with-unexpected/1kj45nus81kut1szgy1gx7cmyo?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a></sup> Colorado issued its first-ever extreme-heat warnings along its Western Slope as the region’s worst drought in two decades continued, and Tropical Storm Claudette was downgraded to a depression, killed 13 Alabamians, including eight children, and was then upgraded to tropical storm again.<sup><a href="https://www.5280.com/2021/06/first-ever-excessive-heat-warnings-in-colorado-history-issued-for-parts-of-the-western-slope/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/hoover-dams-lake-mead-hits-lowest-water-level-1930s-180978022/#:~:text=The%20previous%20record%20its%20low,least%20the%20next%20two%20years." target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/16/climate/nyt-climate-newsletter-drought.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>27</sup></a> <sup><a href="https://www.post-gazette.com/news/environment/2021/06/21/Claudette-tropical-storm-strength-deaths-gulf-carolinas-hurricane-season/stories/202106210058" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a></sup> High Anxiety, a ride at a New Jersey water park, succumbed to flames.<a href="https://www.nbcnewyork.com/news/local/fire-tears-through-water-slide-at-popular-nj-amusement-park-days-before-opening/3110584/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>29</sup></a></p>
<p>French police officers spent seven hours attempting to break up an illegal rave held in honor of a man who died when a 2019 concert was broken up by the police.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/19/world/french-police-covid-rave.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a></sup> Some 500 Hong Kong police officers raided the newsroom of <em>Apple Daily,</em> a pro-democracy newspaper; froze its assets; and arrested five of its editors.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/hong-kong-arrests-business-97e0fbed611073be258763dcf80c4b7f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/w172xv54mb0307l" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a> </sup>It was reported that a West Virginia congressman used campaign funds for 53 purchases at Chick-fil-A.<sup><a href="https://www.wtrf.com/top-news/alex-mooney-allegedly-spent-1900-in-campaign-money-at-chick-fil-a-being-investigated/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">33</a></sup> The Girl Scouts had a surplus of 15 million boxes of Girl Scout cookies.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/14/1006373856/the-girl-scouts-have-unsold-cookies-left-15-million-boxes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">34</a></sup> Oregon legalized human composting, which generates about 200 gallons of nutrient-rich soil per body.<a href="https://www.kgw.com/article/news/local/oregon-will-allow-for-human-composting-as-a-final-resting-option/283-46a27f29-4b4e-41ca-a115-611db29da1c9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">35</a> A beautician and a car salesman in Ukraine broke up after spending 123 days handcuffed together.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/lifestyle/ukraines-inseparable-couple-ditches-handcuffs-parts-ways-2021-06-18/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">36</a></sup> “I did not receive any attention from Alexandr because we were constantly together,” she said. —<em>Jordan Cutler-Tietjen</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-juneteenth-critical-race-theory-panic-storms/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-naftali-bennett-g7-pikachu-washington-press-corps-cicadas/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-naftali-bennett-g7-pikachu-washington-press-corps-cicadas/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 19:28:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Israel’s Knesset moved by a single-vote margin to end the 12-year premiership of Benjamin Netanyahu, installing Naftali Bennett as the new prime minister at the head of a coalition including, among others, the right-wing party Yamina, the social-democratic party Meretz, and the conservative Islamist party Raam.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/06/13/world/israel-knesset-bennett-lapid-netanyahu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/lapid-inks-formal-coalition-deals-with-raam-yisrael-beytenu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a></sup> At the 47th annual G7 summit, in Cornwall, England, President Emmanuel Macron of France, who had earlier that week been slapped at a protest in the town of Tain-l’Hermitage by a medieval-weapons enthusiast, welcomed the United States back into the “club”; the leaders attended an “entirely COVID-secure” beachfront barbecue; Macron and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom quarreled over Northern Ireland and the trade in sausages and other chilled meats; a group of protesters dressed as Pikachu demanded that Japan stop burning coal; and Biden met Queen Elizabeth II, whom he likened to his mother.<sup><a href="https://www.axios.com/biden-macron-g7-leadership-f3b46672-ad60-4334-a720-de019fdfc33d.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/g7-summit-leaders-beach-bbq-covid-secure-and-stuck-to-social-distancing-rules-no-10-insists-12331562" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/frances-macron-sparred-with-uks-johnson-over-brexit-geography-2021-06-13/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/international/558226-pikachus-gather-at-g7-summit-call-on-japan-to-stop-burning-coal" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/world/live-news/biden-g7-summit-updates-06-13-2021/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> A White House press corps flight to the summit was delayed because one of the plane’s engines was filled with cicadas.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/09/politics/cicadas-white-house-press-charter-delayed/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a></sup> “We apologize to our charter customers,” read a statement from Delta, “for this rarest of entomological delays.” On her first trip to a foreign country as vice president, Kamala Harris, the daughter of two immigrants, addressed potential Guatemalan immigrants to the United States and told them, “Do not come.”<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-57387350" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/15/us/second-generation-immigrant-kamala-harris.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup></p>
<p>Alberto Fernández, the president of Argentina, apologized after relating a version of an apocryphal quotation while speaking with the Spanish prime minister: “The Mexicans came from the Indians, the Brazilians came from the jungle, but we Argentines came from boats, and they were boats that came from Europe.”<sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/argentine-president-sinks-himself-over-172007819.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a></sup> President Jair Bolsonaro of Brazil led a motorcycle procession of some 12,000 riders through São Paulo to a public park, where he sharply criticized rules requiring the vaccinated to wear masks; Bolsonaro was subsequently fined $110 for violating the city’s mask mandate.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/jair-bolsonaro-fined-for-not-wearing-mask-at-sao-paulo-biker-rally" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a></sup> In Russia, where 12 percent of the population has received only a single dose of the COVID-19 vaccine, the mayor of Moscow announced that the city would be raffling off new cars for those electing to get the shot, and Washington State launched a program that would provide free joints, but not edibles, to those who receive the vaccine at marijuana dispensaries.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/moscow-give-away-free-cars-spur-people-get-covid-vaccine-2021-06-13/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/07/us/washington-marijuana-covid-vaccine.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a> </sup>A nursing student delivered testimony to the Ohio state legislature in support of a proposed law limiting vaccine mandates in which she claimed that the shot had made her “magnetic,” and attempted to stick both a bobby pin and a key to her skin, neither of which adhered.<a href="https://www.cleveland19.com/2021/06/10/nurse-uses-key-hairpin-try-prove-she-is-magnetic-vaccine-during-ohio-house-hearing-video/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>15</sup></a></p>
<p>A report from ProPublica revealed that the 25 richest Americans paid an average income-tax rate of 15.8 percent from 2014 to 2018, lower than the average rate of an American making $45,000 a year.<a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/you-may-be-paying-a-higher-tax-rate-than-a-billionaire" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>16</sup></a> Jeff Bezos announced that he would be aboard the first human spaceflight of the <em>New Shepard,</em> a suborbital rocket produced by his company Blue Origin, along with his brother and an unnamed individual who paid $28 million for a ticket at auction.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/07/business/jeff-bezos-space.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> “The more you pay for it, the more you enjoy it,” said the auctioneer.<sup><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530907/blue-origin-auction-new-shepard-jeff-bezos-space-28-million" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> El Salvador, where 70 percent of people do not have a bank account, became the first country to recognize bitcoin as legal tender.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/06/12/el-salvador-bitcoin-volcano-faq/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> “This is going to evolve fast!” said the president regarding further plans to use geothermal energy from the country’s volcanoes to mine more bitcoin.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/11/1005231250/el-salvador-plans-to-use-electricity-generated-from-volcanoes-to-mine-bitcoin" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> Louie Gohmert, a Republican member of the House from Texas, asked a U.S. Forest Service official during a hearing whether the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management would be able to alter the orbit of the moon or the earth to help mitigate climate-change efforts; the official replied that he would “have to follow up with you.”<sup><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/lunar-new-deal-gop-rep-gohmert-suggests-altering-moon-s-n1270219" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></sup> Amid widespread drought, the state of Nevada enacted a ban on watering roughly one third of the grass in the Las Vegas metropolitan area.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/nevada-droughts-government-and-politics-environment-and-nature-3bc619e46f902b2ebb77245fcf54e22a" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup> A study of the oral traditions of the M&amacr;ori determined that they may have traveled to Antarctica as early as the seventh century; the National Geographic Society announced the existence of a fifth ocean; and a fisherman on Cape Cod claimed to have escaped from the mouth of a whale after being trapped for almost a full minute.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/new-zealands-maori-may-have-been-first-to-discover-antarctica-study-suggests" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/new-ocean-global-total-five-national-geographic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> <a href="https://www.bostonherald.com/2021/06/11/cape-cod-fisherman-ok-after-whale-gulps-him-down-spits-him-out/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a></sup> “I was lobster diving and a humpback whale tried to eat me,” the fisherman wrote of his experience. The results of a clinical trial suggested that laughing-gas therapy might be an effective treatment for depression.<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/health/mental-health/laughing-gas-shows-promise-treatment-resistant-depression-small-trial-finds-n1270204" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>26</sup></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-naftali-bennett-g7-pikachu-washington-press-corps-cicadas/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prayer for a Just War]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/prayer-for-a-just-war-climate-change/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/prayer-for-a-just-war-climate-change/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:59:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">What if we conceived of the fight against climate change as a “just war”—as both the biggest fight in human history and a global search for meaning? As fires rage, oceans rise, and pandemics ravage, the demands for international solidarity and world-scale deployments of resources are readily apparent. But in the face of ideological divisions wrought by centuries of capitalist and colonial destruction, it’s not always easy to envision what solidarity really is, or what it needs to be.</p>
<p>In “<a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/06/prayer-for-a-just-war-finding-meaning-in-the-climate-fight/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prayer for a Just War</a>,” published in the June issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine</em>, Greg Jackson urges us to see the “first comprehensive global challenge” as an opportunity to define our global character by our collective grit, humility, and trust. In addition to outlining the many counterattacks we must mount on political and technological fronts, Jackson imbues the mythic concept of the “existential threat” with historical and spiritual meaning. In this episode, Jackson delves into those ideas with web editor Violet Lucca, then gestures toward ways we might help each other step out of the deadly (and dull) alienation we all seem to share.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Prayer for a Just War by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1065897445&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/prayer-for-a-just-war-climate-change/" target="_blank">Prayer for a Just War</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-anti-vax-fda-liz-cheney/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-anti-vax-fda-liz-cheney/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 18:14:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The far-right, anti-immigrant Alternative for Germany party lost a state election by a significant margin to the Christian Democratic Union; socialist Pedro Castillo maintained a narrow lead over far-right conservative Keiko Fujimori in Peru’s presidential election; Democrat Melanie Stansbury won by a wide margin in New Mexico’s special House election to replace interior secretary Deb Haaland; and Likud leader Benjamin Netanyahu alleged that the coalition that intends to unseat him as prime minister was the result of the “greatest election fraud . . . in the history of any democracy.”<sup><a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/germany-christian-democrats-cdu-dominate-saxony-anhalt-election-reiner-haseloff/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/peru-awakes-uncertain-future-with-polarized-vote-knife-edge-2021-06-07/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/01/us/politics/melanie-stansbury-new-mexico-house.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> </sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-alleges-election-fraud-accuses-rival-duplicity-2021-06-06/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>4</sup></a> “Partisan voting legislation will destroy the already weakening binds of our democracy,” said Senator Joe Manchin, announcing that he would vote against his own party’s election reform bill, which would, among other reforms, expand early voting, limit gerrymandering, and create automatic voter registration.<sup><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/06/manchin-says-he-will-vote-against-democrats-voting-rights-bill-.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> Former national security adviser Michael Flynn, who stated a Myanmar-style coup “should happen here” during a livestreamed conference, denied his support for a Myanmar-style coup in the United States through his Parler account and his attorney Sidney Powell.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/31/politics/michael-flynn-qanon/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a></sup> Roxana Lizarraga, who was summoned to testify about the irregular purchase of tear gas following the U.S.-backed coup against Bolivian president Evo Morales, applied for political asylum while under arrest in Florida, and Nigeria’s telecoms firms blocked Twitter following the deletion of a tweet that seemed to threaten genocide written by President Muhammadu Buhari, who first ruled the country in 1983 after participating in a military coup against democratically elected president Shehu Shagari.<sup><a href="https://www.telesurenglish.net/news/Bolivias-Ex-Minister-Lizarraga-Seeks-Asylum-in-the-US-20210607-0007.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/04/1003506918/nigeria-suspends-twitter-after-it-deleted-a-tweet-by-the-president" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> </sup><a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2784104?seq=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>9</sup></a> “The only good thing that will come out of this is a lot of stupid people will be killed off,” an anti-vax talk show host said of current efforts to vaccinate shortly before he was hospitalized with COVID-19.<a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/covid-anti-vax-hospitalised-america-b1857838.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>10</sup></a></p>
<p>The FDA approved a drug intended to slow the decline of mental functioning and memory in Alzheimer’s patients even though the agency acknowledges its manufacturer’s studies do not support its efficacy, and Auschwitz survivors decried Arizona’s plan to execute death row inmates with Zyklon B.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/health/aging/fda-approves-controversial-alzheimer-s-drug-biogen-n1269645" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/02/us/arizona-zyklon-b-gas-chamber.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> </sup>Google’s head of diversity was removed for expressing anti-Semitic sentiments, and the company apologized for listing Kannada as the “ugliest language in India” in one of its fact boxes.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-57342967" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/04/world/asia/google-india-language-kannada.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>14</sup></a> Microsoft blamed the global disappearance of images of “Tank Man,” who participated in the Tiananmen Square protests of 1989, from its search engine on “accidental human error,” and Hong Kong police arrested the organizer and at least six participants of a vigil commemorating the protests.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/06/tech/tank-man-tiananmen-square-microsoft/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-police-try-stifle-any-commemoration-tiananmen-crackdown-2021-06-03/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> President Xi Jinping instructed diplomats and members of the press to project a “credible, lovable, and respectable image of China.”<a href="https://www.firstpost.com/world/present-credible-loving-and-respectable-image-of-china-president-xi-jinping-tells-state-media-and-diplomats-9679281.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>17</sup></a> “When you listen to Donald Trump talk now, when you hear the language he’s using now, it is essentially the same things that the Chinese Communist Party, for example, says about the United States and our democracy,” said Representative Liz Cheney, whose father, the former vice president, worked with Donald Rumsfeld to establish an alternative intelligence agency within the Pentagon in order to provide evidence to support the second Iraq War.<sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/cheney-trump-using-same-rhetoric-140636578.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a href="https://www.gq.com/story/richard-cheney-vice-president-impeachment?printable=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> “From the Desk of Donald J. Trump,” the former president’s blog, was permanently shuttered because of low readership, and an Ohio veterans’ group cut the microphone of its Memorial Day keynote speaker after he mentioned the contributions of formerly enslaved people to the holiday’s history.<sup><a href="https://www.axios.com/trump-blog-social-media-readership-703abeec-49d4-468b-90e3-7865d43e2486.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/race-and-ethnicity-memorial-day-american-legion-microphone-b3086dc908b8aeb053c39e3901a83cda" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></sup> On the first day of Pride Month, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis banned transgender girls and women from playing on school sports teams, and boaters in Washington reportedly shouted homophobic slurs at another vessel until their own boat burst into flames.<sup><a href="https://www.orlandosentinel.com/politics/os-ne-desantis-signs-transgender-bill-20210601-hwsueb3bi5anxkx7xswypmm2um-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/moses-lake-boaters-allegedly-harassed-another-group-over-gay-pride-flags-then-their-boat-burst-into-flames/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup></p>
<p>Pope Francis signed a law that will, among other reforms, remove clerics who sexually abuse minors from office.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/religion/pope-francis-issues-long-awaited-reform-of-vatican-penal-law/2021/06/01/fb957d84-c320-11eb-89a4-b7ae22aa193e_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a></sup> A father in Florida faced child abuse charges for throwing his infant at a deputy during a high-speed chase, and it was reported that a man who yelled, “You guys like protecting pedophiles?” at police through a megaphone during the January 6 riots had served jail time for raping a 14-year-old girl.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/05/us/florida-chase-baby-thrown-at-deputy/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/04/politics/capitol-rioter-rape-charge/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> It was reported that California prison guards did not notice when a “self-styled Satanist” convicted of murder beheaded and dissected his cellmate, and archaeologists discovered an “exceptionally high” number of decapitated bodies at a Roman burial site.<sup><a href="https://www.nbclosangeles.com/news/local/prison-guards-beheading-inmate-jaime-osuna-corcoran-luis-romero/2606052/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/31/europe/decapitated-roman-remains-scn-scli-intl/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a> </sup>“Do not push bears,” said a 17-year-old in California who was filmed protecting her dogs by pushing a bear off a wall. “Don’t do what I did. You might not have the same outcome.”<sup><a href="https://ktla.com/news/local-news/17-year-old-san-gabriel-valley-girl-shoves-away-bear-to-save-her-dogs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29</a></sup> Fifteen elephants in China were seen wandering through a city 300 miles from their nature reserve home, a migration that experts cannot explain.<a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/04/1003268230/elephants-wandered-hundreds-of-miles-into-a-chinese-city-nobody-knows-why" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>30</sup></a>—<em>Clara Olshansky</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-anti-vax-fda-liz-cheney/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>