<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Harper's Magazine</title>
        <link>https://harpers.org/</link>
        <description>null</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 18:15:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/ruicosta042/rssconv-action</generator>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-anti-vax-fda-liz-cheney/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-anti-vax-fda-liz-cheney/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 18:14:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The far-right, anti-immigrant Alternative for Germany party lost a state election by a significant margin to the Christian Democratic Union; socialist Pedro Castillo maintained a narrow lead over far-right conservative Keiko Fujimori in Peru’s presidential election; Democrat Melanie Stansbury won by a wide margin in New Mexico’s special House election to replace interior secretary Deb Haaland; and Likud leader Benjamin Netanyahu alleged that the coalition that intends to unseat him as prime minister was the result of the “greatest election fraud . . . in the history of any democracy.”<sup><a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/germany-christian-democrats-cdu-dominate-saxony-anhalt-election-reiner-haseloff/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/peru-awakes-uncertain-future-with-polarized-vote-knife-edge-2021-06-07/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/01/us/politics/melanie-stansbury-new-mexico-house.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> </sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-alleges-election-fraud-accuses-rival-duplicity-2021-06-06/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>4</sup></a> “Partisan voting legislation will destroy the already weakening binds of our democracy,” said Senator Joe Manchin, announcing that he would vote against his own party’s election reform bill, which would, among other reforms, expand early voting, limit gerrymandering, and create automatic voter registration.<sup><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/06/manchin-says-he-will-vote-against-democrats-voting-rights-bill-.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> Former national security adviser Michael Flynn, who stated a Myanmar-style coup “should happen here” during a livestreamed conference, denied his support for a Myanmar-style coup in the United States through his Parler account and his attorney Sidney Powell.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/31/politics/michael-flynn-qanon/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a></sup> Roxana Lizarraga, who was summoned to testify about the irregular purchase of tear gas following the U.S.-backed coup against Bolivian president Evo Morales, applied for political asylum while under arrest in Florida, and Nigeria’s telecoms firms blocked Twitter following the deletion of a tweet that seemed to threaten genocide written by President Muhammadu Buhari, who first ruled the country in 1983 after participating in a military coup against democratically elected president Shehu Shagari.<sup><a href="https://www.telesurenglish.net/news/Bolivias-Ex-Minister-Lizarraga-Seeks-Asylum-in-the-US-20210607-0007.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/04/1003506918/nigeria-suspends-twitter-after-it-deleted-a-tweet-by-the-president" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> </sup><a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2784104?seq=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>9</sup></a> “The only good thing that will come out of this is a lot of stupid people will be killed off,” an anti-vax talk show host said of current efforts to vaccinate shortly before he was hospitalized with COVID-19.<a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/covid-anti-vax-hospitalised-america-b1857838.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>10</sup></a></p>
<p>The FDA approved a drug intended to slow the decline of mental functioning and memory in Alzheimer’s patients even though the agency acknowledges its manufacturer’s studies do not support its efficacy, and Auschwitz survivors decried Arizona’s plan to execute death row inmates with Zyklon B.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/health/aging/fda-approves-controversial-alzheimer-s-drug-biogen-n1269645" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/02/us/arizona-zyklon-b-gas-chamber.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> </sup>Google’s head of diversity was removed for expressing anti-Semitic sentiments, and the company apologized for listing Kannada as the “ugliest language in India” in one of its fact boxes.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-57342967" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/04/world/asia/google-india-language-kannada.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>14</sup></a> Microsoft blamed the global disappearance of images of “Tank Man,” who participated in the Tiananmen Square protests of 1989, from its search engine on “accidental human error,” and Hong Kong police arrested the organizer and at least six participants of a vigil commemorating the protests.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/06/tech/tank-man-tiananmen-square-microsoft/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-police-try-stifle-any-commemoration-tiananmen-crackdown-2021-06-03/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> President Xi Jinping instructed diplomats and members of the press to project a “credible, lovable, and respectable image of China.”<a href="https://www.firstpost.com/world/present-credible-loving-and-respectable-image-of-china-president-xi-jinping-tells-state-media-and-diplomats-9679281.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>17</sup></a> “When you listen to Donald Trump talk now, when you hear the language he’s using now, it is essentially the same things that the Chinese Communist Party, for example, says about the United States and our democracy,” said Representative Liz Cheney, whose father, the former vice president, worked with Donald Rumsfeld to establish an alternative intelligence agency within the Pentagon in order to provide evidence to support the second Iraq War.<sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/cheney-trump-using-same-rhetoric-140636578.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a href="https://www.gq.com/story/richard-cheney-vice-president-impeachment?printable=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> “From the Desk of Donald J. Trump,” the former president’s blog, was permanently shuttered because of low readership, and an Ohio veterans’ group cut the microphone of its Memorial Day keynote speaker after he mentioned the contributions of formerly enslaved people to the holiday’s history.<sup><a href="https://www.axios.com/trump-blog-social-media-readership-703abeec-49d4-468b-90e3-7865d43e2486.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/race-and-ethnicity-memorial-day-american-legion-microphone-b3086dc908b8aeb053c39e3901a83cda" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></sup> On the first day of Pride Month, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis banned transgender girls and women from playing on school sports teams, and boaters in Washington reportedly shouted homophobic slurs at another vessel until their own boat burst into flames.<sup><a href="https://www.orlandosentinel.com/politics/os-ne-desantis-signs-transgender-bill-20210601-hwsueb3bi5anxkx7xswypmm2um-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/moses-lake-boaters-allegedly-harassed-another-group-over-gay-pride-flags-then-their-boat-burst-into-flames/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup></p>
<p>Pope Francis signed a law that will, among other reforms, remove clerics who sexually abuse minors from office.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/religion/pope-francis-issues-long-awaited-reform-of-vatican-penal-law/2021/06/01/fb957d84-c320-11eb-89a4-b7ae22aa193e_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a></sup> A father in Florida faced child abuse charges for throwing his infant at a deputy during a high-speed chase, and it was reported that a man who yelled, “You guys like protecting pedophiles?” at police through a megaphone during the January 6 riots had served jail time for raping a 14-year-old girl.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/05/us/florida-chase-baby-thrown-at-deputy/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/04/politics/capitol-rioter-rape-charge/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> It was reported that California prison guards did not notice when a “self-styled Satanist” convicted of murder beheaded and dissected his cellmate, and archaeologists discovered an “exceptionally high” number of decapitated bodies at a Roman burial site.<sup><a href="https://www.nbclosangeles.com/news/local/prison-guards-beheading-inmate-jaime-osuna-corcoran-luis-romero/2606052/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/31/europe/decapitated-roman-remains-scn-scli-intl/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a> </sup>“Do not push bears,” said a 17-year-old in California who was filmed protecting her dogs by pushing a bear off a wall. “Don’t do what I did. You might not have the same outcome.”<sup><a href="https://ktla.com/news/local-news/17-year-old-san-gabriel-valley-girl-shoves-away-bear-to-save-her-dogs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29</a></sup> Fifteen elephants in China were seen wandering through a city 300 miles from their nature reserve home, a migration that experts cannot explain.<a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/04/1003268230/elephants-wandered-hundreds-of-miles-into-a-chinese-city-nobody-knows-why" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>30</sup></a>—<em>Clara Olshansky</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-anti-vax-fda-liz-cheney/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-boris-johnson-covid-19-amazen-sherpa-dream/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-boris-johnson-covid-19-amazen-sherpa-dream/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 21:13:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Dominic Cummings, a former adviser to Boris Johnson who wrote a nearly 3,000-word blog post that called for “unusual software developers” and “weirdos and misfits with odd skills” to apply to civil service jobs at 10 Downing Street, testified before Parliament that the prime minister had once suggested that a doctor inject him with COVID-19 on live television to downplay the seriousness of the virus.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/26/world/europe/cummings-johnson-covid.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://dominiccummings.com/2020/01/02/two-hands-are-a-lot-were-hiring-data-scientists-project-managers-policy-experts-assorted-weirdos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/27/uk/boris-johnson-scandals-intl-gbr-cmd/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> Johnson, who was infected off-camera, denied this and other statements, including his preference to “let the bodies pile high in their thousands” rather than institute another lockdown.<sup><a href="https://www.itv.com/news/2021-04-26/robert-peston-boris-johnson-did-make-bodies-pile-high-in-their-thousands-comment" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a></sup> “Boris seems to have been able to do what Henry VIII couldn’t do,” said Christopher Lamb of Johnson’s secret marriage to his third wife, Carrie Symonds, which was recognized by the Catholic Church.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/01/world/europe/boris-johnson-married-catholic-church.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> An Indian couple were investigated for violating COVID-19 restrictions after they were married aboard a chartered SpiceJet flight with an estimated 160 unmasked guests, and the U.S. Supreme Court rejected an appeal by Johnson &amp; Johnson, which had aggressively marketed its baby powder to black and Hispanic communities while failing to disclose its carcinogenic ingredients, and ordered the company to pay $2 billion in damages to women who developed ovarian cancer from their talc products.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/25/world/india-wedding-spicejet-coronavirus.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/korihale/2020/10/14/johnson–johnsons-100-million-baby-powder-lawsuit-settlement-is-overdue-for-black–hispanic-women/?sh=7431344c63b3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/johnson-and-johnson-us-supreme-court-michael-brown-business-health-e31b4a561cf43461844db28b44c4194d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a></sup> Germany formally recognized its genocide of the Herero and the Nama peoples, and agreed to pay Namibia $1.35 billion for future development projects but nothing to the survivors’ descendants; Emmanuel Macron acknowledged but did not apologize for France’s role in the Rwandan genocide; a mass grave of 215 indigenous children was found in British Columbia on the grounds of a former residential school, which was run by the Catholic Church and dedicated to assimilating the children into white Canadian society; and Hatwrks, a hat shop in Nashville, Tennessee, announced via an Instagram post that it was selling $5 Star of David patches that read <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">not vaccinated.</span><sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-57279008" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/africa-rwanda-europe-france-4a085eaa8f771913ac75758ca288762f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/28/world/canada/kamloops-mass-grave-residential-schools.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/29/world/covid-vaccine-passport-nashville-stetson.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a></sup></p>
<p>Facebook released a report that Russia still produces the largest amount of fake news, and issued a statement that it will not remove content that claims COVID-19 is man-made “in light of ongoing investigations into the origin of COVID-19 and in consultation with public health experts.”<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/05/26/facebook-disinformation-russia-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> </sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/health-coronavirus-pandemic-business-eeb25b2131ea6f043d337ab127921ab1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>14</sup></a> OSHA reported that Amazon, the second-largest private employer in the United States, has the highest amount of workplace accidents in its warehouses, nearly double the rate of non-Amazon warehouse workers; the company faced criticism when it posted a video of AmaZen, an interactive kiosk the size of a telephone booth where warehouse employees can watch, among other mental health content, videos on mindfulness practices.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/06/01/amazon-osha-injury-rate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/27/amazons-mental-health-kiosk-mocked-on-social-media-as-a-despair-closet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>16</sup></a> “We don’t set unreasonable performance goals,” said Amazon founder Jeff Bezos, whose company will turn every Echo speaker and Ring security camera into a shared wireless network, a move decried by security experts, unless owners manually opt out within the next five days.<sup><a href="https://theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/01/amazon-us-customers-given-one-week-to-opt-out-of-mass-wireless-sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> Harvard researchers called the U.S. Census Bureau’s privacy controls used for redistricting data unreliable, and watchdog groups filed legal complaints against Clearview AI, which provides advanced facial recognition technology to an unknown number of private institutions and law enforcement agencies, for violating E.U. privacy laws.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-census-2020-technology-e701e313e841674be6396321343b7e49" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/europe-data-privacy-technology-government-and-politics-busiEuropean%20Union%E2%80%99s%20General%20Data%20Protection%20Regulationness-b26dbe0db29865a4a3197570b90953b3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/18/technology/clearview-privacy-facial-recognition.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>20</sup></a> The world’s largest meat processing company resumed slaughter and the packaging of flesh after being halted by a ransomware attack, and the NFL promised to stop “race-norming”—a standard practice in injury law that, among other legally supported assumptions, asserts that black men have lower IQs than Caucasians and therefore deserve less money for cognitive impairments—when determining settlements for players who have suffered brain injuries.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/jbs-sa-lifestyle-health-coronavirus-pandemic-technology-bf82114d3f54e5be2241bd5f9a0b2639?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=June2_MorningWire&amp;utm_term=Morning%20Wire%20Subscribers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a href="http://apnews.com/article/pa-state-wire-race-and-ethnicity-health-nfl-sports-205b304c0c3724532d74fc54e58b4d1d?utm_campaign=SocialFlow&amp;utm_source=Twitter&amp;utm_medium=AP" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> <a href="https://www.alabseries.com/episodes/episode-21-baked-in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> “I thought it was some weird social experiment at first,” said Rebecca Smith, a Baton Rouge, Louisiana, resident who, along with four other jurors, was pulled off the street and forced to serve the day a personal-injury trial began.<sup><a href="https://www.theadvocate.com/baton_rouge/news/article_94ee392e-b996-11eb-ad60-279a5c797269.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a></sup> Scientists predicted that the tick population would be significantly larger than past seasons.<sup><a href="https://fox8.com/news/tick-population-expected-to-surge-and-theyre-carrying-more-than-lyme-disease-researchers-say/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a></sup></p>
<p>New research suggested that long, hot baths offer similar benefits to a long run, and that COVID-19 vaccines could offer immunity to the virus for a year to a lifetime.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/hot-tub-health-kick-why-a-long-bath-is-almost-as-good-for-you-as-a-long-run" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/26/health/coronavirus-immunity-vaccines.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a></sup> A Greenback, Tennessee, woman was arrested after she drove her car through a COVID-19 vaccination tent while yelling “no vaccine,” and William Shakespeare, the first man to receive an official COVID-19 vaccination, died of a stroke.<sup><a href="https://www.wkrn.com/news/woman-charged-after-car-plows-through-maryville-vaccination-tent/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a> </sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/cdc-director-cautions-americans-ahead-080019792.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>29</sup></a> A British drug dealer whose identity was revealed after he posted a photo of himself holding a block of blue Stilton cheese in a grocery store was sentenced to over 13 years in prison, and a bad dream led a Sherpa to postpone scaling Mount Everest for the 26th time until next year.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2021/05/26/carl-stewart-cheese-drug-dealer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a> <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/bad-dream-stopped-everest-guide-074418412.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a> </sup>Senate Democrats killed a Republican-sponsored bill that forbade the creation of “certain human-animal chimeras.”<sup><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/andrewsolender/2021/05/27/senate-kills-gop-legislation-to-prohibit-certain-human-animal-chimeras/?sh=67ab5dd14207" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a></sup> “It was very moving,” said Aussie Ark president Tim Faulkner of the birth of seven Tasmanian devils that were born in a semi-wild nature preserve, roughly 3,000 years after the animals had gone extinct in Australia.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/27/world/australia/tasmanian-devils.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">33</a></sup> China reported the first human case of H10N3, a rare strain of bird flu.<sup><a href="https://reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/china-reports-human-case-h10n3-bird-flu-2021-06-01/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">34</a></sup>—<em>Violet Lucca</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/weekly-review-boris-johnson-covid-19-amazen-sherpa-dream/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stages of Grief]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/06/stages-of-grief-covid-19-act-up/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/06/stages-of-grief-covid-19-act-up/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 21:46:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">For those who make, or might once have made, a living as artists, the pandemic and the economic depression that followed it took away two vital sources of revenue: in-person events and day jobs that sustained creative endeavors. Yet, as <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/06/stages-of-grief-what-the-pandemic-has-done-to-the-arts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">William Deresiewicz</a> describes in the June issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine,</em> all sectors of the arts economy were already vulnerable for collapse: years of declining public arts funding and education, as well as the rise of “free content,” had fundamentally destabilized the ability for expression.</p>
<p>The ways in which COVID-19 sharpened and highlighted existing social failures harkens back to another global health crisis: the AIDS epidemic. Writer, activist, and historian Sarah Schulman’s newest book, <em>Let the Record Show: A Political History of ACT UP New York, 1987-1993</em><em>,</em> tells the story of activists who waged some of the most effective political campaigns of the century to force politicians, the populace, and drug companies into acknowledging and addressing AIDS. An <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/06/blood-ties-sarah-schulman-let-the-record-show/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">excerpt</a> of <em>Let the Record Show </em>also appears in the June issue.</p>
<p>In this episode of the podcast, web editor Violet Lucca moderates a conversation between Sarah Schulman and William Deresiewicz, author of <em>The Death of the Artist,</em> exploring links between the two crises. Among other topics, they discuss the aesthetic and societal costs of confining art making to the margins of the workday, the new challenges of organizing against Big Tech, and the value of artists to social movements.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Stages of Grief by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1060813213&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/06/stages-of-grief-covid-19-act-up/" target="_blank">Stages of Grief</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-protests-covid-19-vote-audit/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-protests-covid-19-vote-audit/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 18:51:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Sasha Johnson, a prominent Black Lives Matter activist who had received numerous death threats, was shot in the head at a house party; London police are investigating whether she was the intended target.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/24/sasha-johnson-blm-activist-may-have-been-shot-by-mistake" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a></sup> At the behest of President Aleksandr Lukashenko, a Belarusian fighter jet forced a commercial airplane that was flying from Athens to Vilnius, Lithuania, to land in Minsk; once grounded, passenger Roman Protasevich, a journalist who had co-founded a Telegram channel that was critical of Lukashenko’s government, was immediately arrested.<sup><a href="https://nytimes.com/2021/05/23/world/europe/ryanair-belarus.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a></sup> Indian police arrested a muralist who painted a crying woman draped in a Palestinian flag along with at least 20 pro-Palestinian protesters in Kashmir.<sup><a href="https://thediplomat.com/2021/05/kashmiris-are-being-arrested-for-pro-palestine-protests/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> “[The Jammu and Kashmir] Police is keeping a very close watch on elements who are attempting to leverage the unfortunate situation in Palestine to disturb public peace and order in the Kashmir valley. We are a professional force and are sensitive to public anguish,” tweeted local law enforcement.<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/KashmirPolice/status/1393501546483093505" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a></sup> Israel and Hamas agreed to a ceasefire that brought an end to 11 days of bombing and rocket attacks that killed at least 248 Palestinians and 13 Israelis, and destroyed 258 buildings in the Gaza Strip.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/23/middleeast/israel-palestinians-truce-sheikh-jarrah-cmd-intl/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/5/21/thousands-of-gazans-return-to-destroyed-homes-after-israel-truce">6</a> <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/france/20210523-it-s-not-normal-paris-protesters-decry-gaza-conflict-s-palestinian-death-toll" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu tweeted, “We regret every loss of life, but I can tell you categorically, there is no army in the world that acts in a more moral fashion than the army of Israel.”<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/israelipm/status/1395720685843095562" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a></sup> Two days later, Israeli police beat and arrested Palestinian worshippers at the Al-Aqsa Mosque in East Jerusalem.<sup><a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/5/23/backed-by-israeli-police-jewish-settlers-storm-al-aqsa-compound" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a></sup> “Are the violent protests violating human rights? Of course,” said Colombian president Iván Duque in a professionally produced English-language video; in accompanying videos that were distributed over WhatsApp and addressed other questions about the ongoing nationwide protests—which have lasted over three weeks and resulted in the disappearances of at least 168 people—Duque suggested that the unrest was being supported by Venezuela, leftist and former presidential candidate Gustavo Petro, and those who “want to promote chaos.”<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/colombia-health-coronavirus-pandemic-e43eb87ac930ac9c0c26c1941661263c#:~:text=BOGOTA%2C%20Colombia%20(AP)%20%E2%80%94,human%20rights%20ombudsman%20said%20Tuesday." target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/jun/18/ivan-duque-wins-election-to-become-colombias-president" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a> <a href="https://www.archyde.com/ivan-duque-english-interview-when-i-won-the-candidate-i-defeated-said-he-was-going-to-be-in-the-streets-national/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://www.infobae.com/america/colombia/2021/05/23/se-conocen-nuevos-detalles-de-la-autoentrevista-del-presidente-duque-que-se-viralizo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> </sup>An arraignment was held for an arsonist known as “Joker” who set fire to the San Gabriel Mission in San Diego, California, and cryptocurrency investors lost approximately $800 billion.<sup><a href="https://timesofsandiego.com/crime/2021/05/18/arsonist-known-as-joker-charged-with-setting-2020-fire-inside-historic-san-gabriel-mission/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/charts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a></sup></p>
<p>An alliance of human rights organizations reported that the COVID-19 vaccine industry has created nine new billionaires, including the CEO of Moderna, and that their combined wealth would be “enough to fully vaccinate all people in low-income countries 1.3 times.”<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/21/business/covid-vaccine-billionaires/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a> <a href="https://app.box.com/s/c487wmiyquh9q1glpbatzf5sukls7ph2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a> </sup>Germany, where new billionaire BioNTech CEO U&#x0011F;ur &Scedil;ahin is a citizen, blocked travel from the United Kingdom as a COVID variant first observed in India spread to 86 of the island’s regions; England, Wales, and Scotland loosened social distancing restrictions; and an outbreak on Mount Everest caused more than 100 climbers and Sherpas to contract the virus.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/05/22/world/covid-vaccine-coronavirus-mask?action=click&amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/britain-england-scotland-wales-changing-coronavirus-restrictions-17-may" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> </sup><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/climbing-guide-says-coronavirus-outbreak-mount-everest-has-infected-least-n1268239" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>19</sup></a> Flanked by children and adults holding signs that read #<span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">stoptheabuse</span>, the governor of Iowa signed a law forbidding schools and local municipalities from issuing mask mandates, and in an interview Marjorie Taylor Greene, who was fined for not wearing a mask on the House floor, likened mask requirements to restrictions leading up to the Holocaust.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/554538-iowa-governor-banning-mask-mandates" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> </sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/21/politics/marjorie-taylor-greene-mask-mandates-holocaust/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>21</sup></a> To incentivize residents to get COVID vaccines, New York and Ohio established million-dollar lotteries, while Maryland announced daily prizes of $40,000 for the newly immunized.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/coronavirus-pandemic-oddities-government-and-politics-health-d38e4c1c11ef99dbb291559aa16b18aa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> <a href="https://www.baltimoresun.com/coronavirus/bs-md-vaccine-lottery-cash-promotion-20210520-2hrprtbqvbhzbc7yu4tcim3tde-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> More than 100 people lined up outside of an abandoned Bay Area gas station for the chance to sniff a corpse flower in bloom.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/ca-state-wire-california-corpse-flowers-oddities-e3095d7226d7f640dfd1df75d93d07bb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a></sup> Alabama repealed its 28-year ban on yoga in public schools but expressly prohibited meditation, hypnosis, and the greeting “namaste.”<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/05/21/999020140/its-now-legal-to-practice-yoga-in-alabamas-public-schools" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a></sup> In front of an audience of 45 men and 8 women, the governor of Texas signed a law banning abortions of fetuses after six weeks; in response, the Satanic Temple filed a lawsuit against the state alleging that the law violates its members’ First Amendment rights to an abortion ritual, “a ceremonial affirmation of self-worth and bodily autonomy.”<sup><a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2021/05/18/texas-heartbeat-bill-abortions-law" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a href="https://thesatanictemple.com/pages/texas-lawsuit" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> “She was a little younger than me, so it was like a Romeo and Juliet story,” said a Wyoming state senator and U.S. House candidate about his relationship with and impregnation of a 14-year-old girl.<sup><a href="https://amp.cnn.com/cnn/2021/05/22/politics/anthony-bouchard-wyoming-14-year-old/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a></sup> Arizona’s secretary of state called for the permanent decertification of Maricopa County voting machines investigated by Cyber Ninjas as part of an audit during which ballots were inspected for bamboo fibers that would prove they were shipped from Southeast Asia.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/donald-trump-arizona-election-2020-elections-technology-01d4c5d803bcf007ccd5bfbc54a67fab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/06/arizona-republicans-bamboo-ballots-audit-2020" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>29</sup></a> In response to an uptick in salmonella cases across the country, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention requested that Americans not “kiss or snuggle backyard poultry.”<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/policy/healthcare/public-global-health/554669-cdc-urges-against-kissing-and-snuggling-poultry-in" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a></sup> There were chicken wing shortages in the United States.<sup><a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/markets/chicken-wings-latest-shortage-to-hit-america" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a></sup></p>
<p>A Michigan town council refused to count a resident’s Juliana pig as a therapy animal, citing concerns that cows and chickens could be next.<sup><a href="https://www.hometownlife.com/story/news/local/milford/2021/05/21/milford-declares-pig-farm-animal-not-domesticated-therapy-pet/5138849001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a></sup> Federal law enforcement impounded 69 maltreated big cats, including tigers, lions, lion-tiger hybrids, and a jaguar, from Tiger King Park in Oklahoma.<sup><a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/clarissajanlim/tiger-king-park-jeff-lauren-lowe-animals-seized" target="_blank" rel="noopener">33</a></sup> “Joe Exotic and Jeff Lowe ran slipshod operations,” an animal rights activist said, “and the chickens have come home to roost.”<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/tiger-king-jeffrey-lowe-big-cats-seized-6d643586f0e3562428cb40e62e3424c2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">34</a></sup> An iceberg, now the world’s largest, calved from Antarctica.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/20/world/iceberg-antarctica-ronne-a76.html?action=click&amp;module=Science%20%20Technology&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener">35</a></sup> During a memorial procession for a Colorado man who died in a motorcycle crash, the deceased’s mother crashed one of her son’s old motorcycles and died, and a Sonoran woman stabbed her husband with a knife after finding photos of him with someone she initially assumed to be another woman and later realized was herself.<sup><a href="https://www.coloradoan.com/story/news/2021/05/17/larimer-county-mom-dies-motorcycle-crash-during-sons-memorial-ride/5125846001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">36</a> <a href="https://yucatanmagazine.com/confused-jealous-wife-stabs-husband-after-seeing-her-younger-self-in-old-photos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">37</a></sup> Tens of thousands of newly emerged cicadas suffered fungal infections that rendered them genital-less, bisexual, and unusually concupiscent.<sup><a href="https://npr.org/2021/05/18/997998920/the-fungus-thats-making-cicadas-sex-crazy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">38</a></sup> “Everyone’s having a good time while they’re infected,” a mycologist said, “so I don’t imagine there’s much pain.”—<em>Jordan Cutler-Tietjen</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-protests-covid-19-vote-audit/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Anxiety of Influencers]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-anxiety-of-influencers-tiktok-collab-house/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-anxiety-of-influencers-tiktok-collab-house/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 16:06:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">According to Hollywood legend, director Mervyn LeRoy “discovered” Lana Turner when she was sixteen, at the soda counter of Schwab’s Pharmacy in Los Angeles. While the tale is apocryphal, the notion that anyone could be a star motivated untold hordes of youths to go west for decades afterward. (Let’s be honest: most of them turned out like the “grotesques” of Nathanael West’s <em>The Day of the Locust.</em>) So is it so surprising that, according to a 2019 poll, 54 percent of Americans between the ages of thirteen and thirty-eight say they would become social-media influencers if given the chance? For the June issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine,</em> <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/06/tiktok-house-collab-house-the-anxiety-of-influencers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Barrett Swanson</a> spent five days at a TikTok collab house: a plush Los Angeles mansion, funded by two Silicon Valley investors, where a group of conventionally beautiful, college-aged influencers lived rent-free, tasked only with posting videos of themselves for their millions of followers. Yet, as sultry as this sounds, Swanson found that these young men struggled with anxiety, depression, and an inability to think critically about the forces driving them to generate content. The pressure to please, gain followers, and get good ratings is creeping into all of our lives, regardless of industry. (Even doctors get star ratings now.) In this episode, Swanson joins <em>Harper’s </em>web editor Violet Lucca to discuss the alternately surreal and sad reality of life inside of the collab house; the pressures of the “passion economy”; algorithms; and the critical thinking and digital literacy that everyone—not just the young—are sorely lacking.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="The Anxiety of Influencers by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1054641208&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-anxiety-of-influencers-tiktok-collab-house/" target="_blank">The Anxiety of Influencers</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-palestine-israel-darkside-pipeline-shutdown/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-palestine-israel-darkside-pipeline-shutdown/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 16:52:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The Israeli government launched dozens of airstrikes on Gaza, killing at least 212 Palestinians, and Hamas launched several thousand rockets on Israel, killing at least 10 Israelis, as violence prompted in part by a police raid on the Al-Aqsa Mosque and the eviction of Palestinian families from East Jerusalem broke out across the region.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-57138996" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/05/17/world/middleeast/israel-palestine-gaza-conflict-death-toll.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/22430488/israel-gaza-war-2021-hamas-sheikh-jarrah" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> Israel destroyed a 12-story tower that housed Associated Press and Al Jazeera offices, claiming that the building was also used by Hamas intelligence.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/gaza-tower-housing-ap-al-jazeera-collapses-after-missile-strike-witness-2021-05-15/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a></sup> The AP said that there was “no indication Hamas was in the building or active in the building,” Al Jazeera described the attack as “a clear act to stop journalists from conducting their sacred duty to inform the world and report events on the ground,” and Reporters Without Borders called for the International Criminal Court to investigate the bombing as a potential war crime.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-middle-east-business-israel-palestinian-conflict-f595d0ea0a7e21a4e4974ae55e00024d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/5/15/al-jazeera-strongly-condemns-israels-destruction-of-gaza-offices" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/middle-east-israel-business-israel-palestinian-conflict-government-and-politics-abd641af1607fbae7f49e1cce7dbc49e?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=Monday_News_Wire&amp;utm_term=Morning%20Wire%20Subscribers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> The Biden Administration approved the sale of $735 million in weapons to Israel and voiced support for the country’s “right to defend itself”; the United States blocked several UN Security Council statements condemning Israel’s actions; Instagram and Twitter blamed technical glitches for the removal of posts and accounts documenting the eviction of Palestinians; and graffiti at Bates College in Maine that read, in part, <span style="text-transform: lowercase; font-variant: small-caps;">stop ethnic cleansing</span>, was being investigated as a hate crime.<sup><a href="http://washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/05/17/power-up-biden-administration-approves-735-million-weapons-sale-israel-raising-red-flags-some-house-democrats/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/5/17/no-us-action-after-third-unsc-meeting-on-israel-palestine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/05/12/israeli-palestinian-conflict-social-media/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a> </sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/me-state-wire-middle-east-israel-education-f7f58273ada7adf0a4af46c2bde76808" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>11</sup></a> A Virginian was seen filling water bottles with gasoline, a Georgian was caught siphoning fuel out of UHauls with a drill, and the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission warned people to “not fill plastic bags with gasoline” following a ransomware attack by the DarkSide that disabled an oil pipeline that supplies the East Coast with nearly half of its gasoline.<sup><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/man-fills-water-bottles-gasoline-002121276.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2021/05/13/man-drills-into-uhaul-tanks-causes-spill-georgia-police-say/5070752001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/uscpsc/status/1392482092823502849" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/13/us/politics/biden-colonial-pipeline-ransomware.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/05/12/faq-gas-shortages/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> “Our goal is to make money and not creating problems for society,” the hacker group posted after receiving the equivalent of $5 million in bitcoin as ransom.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/05/14/darkside-ransomware-shutting-down/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> State legislators in Texas proposed a bill mandating a minimum of $250 in annual fees for owners of electric cars.<sup><a href="https://cleantechnica.com/2021/05/14/texas-wants-to-charge-tesla-other-ev-owners-400-in-annual-fees-for-owning-an-ev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> Chick-fil-A began rationing dipping sauces amid a nationwide shortage.<a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chick-fil-a-limits-sauce-industry-wide-shortage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>19</sup></a></p>
<p>Engineers in San Francisco were attempting to silence a loud hum emitted by the Golden Gate Bridge that could be heard 10 miles away.<sup><a href="https://www.nbcwashington.com/news/national-international/engineers-work-to-silence-loud-hum-on-golden-gate-bridge/2673938/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> Indian officials installed a net in the Ganges to catch the bodies of COVID-19 victims, hundreds of whom have been cast into the river or buried in shallow graves because of overcrowding in crematoriums, and a 76-year-old Indian woman who had tested positive for COVID-19 awoke just as her family was about to begin her cremation.<sup><a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-05-13/india-net-in-ganges-to-collect-dead-covid-bodies/100137758?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/india-coronavirus-pandemic-health-88f11eb66e0f505fe941793c291bc946" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> <a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-05-11/covid-india-who-bodies-wash-up-on-banks-of-ganges-river/100130032" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a> <a href="https://fox8.com/news/76-year-old-with-covid-19-wakes-up-moments-before-her-cremation-reports/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a></sup> A rock climber who was crushed by a boulder “the size of a refrigerator” was rescued from a region of the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Utah called Certain Death, and a host on <em>Good Morning Britain</em> mistakenly announced that the queen was dead.<sup><a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/utah-climber-rescued-boulder-mountain-little-cottonwood-canyon?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a href="https://metro.co.uk/2021/05/12/alastair-campbell-accidentally-announces-the-queens-death-on-gmb-14565643/?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a> </sup>Canadian psychologists reported that “bullshitters” are more intelligent, and Japanese researchers who discovered that mice, rats, and pigs can breathe through their anuses suggested that humans might have the same ability.<sup><a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/14747049211000317" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a> <a href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2021/05/15/national/science-health/mammals-breath-anus-study" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a> <a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/newslens/2021/0515/1221831-animals-oxygen-study/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29</a></sup></p>
<p>Sand samples from Cerne Abbas revealed that the chalk pictograph of a man with an enormous penis wielding a club dates to the late Saxon period.<a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/scholars-are-one-step-closer-solving-mystery-enormous-chalk-figure-180977725/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>30</sup></a> “Formal graffiti charges” were filed against an Auckland man who drew colorful penises around potholes to highlight poor road conditions.<sup><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-friday-edition-1.6018246/new-zealand-man-faces-legal-action-for-painting-penises-around-potholes-1.6020655" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a></sup> “I’ve tried other ways, you know,” said the man. “Quite often I feel like they simply ignore me.” Indian scientists concluded that a deceased herd of 18 Asiatic elephants had been killed by lightning, and an Oklahoma woman teaching an online class was shocked after lightning struck her house and traveled through its electricity system to her laptop.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/asia-india-elephants-environment-and-nature-c836bad5ff8dd6a62de188332d271105?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a> <a href="https://www.fox43.com/article/news/nation-world/oklahoma-woman-lightning-shock-through-laptop/507-bdf6048d-d07a-4cd8-bf15-83a3650fa1c9?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a> </sup>“You wouldn’t think that a laptop would do that,” said the local fire chief. In Chicago, which has held the top ranking on Orkin’s list of America’s “rattiest” cities for six years in a row, a humane society announced that it would be releasing 1,000 feral cats to combat infestations.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/changing-america/sustainability/environment/552911-1000-feral-cats-released-onto-chicago-streets-to?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">33</a></sup> An English veterinarian performed the first ever corneal surgery on a Sumatran tiger.<sup><a href="https://www.aol.co.uk/lifestyle/world-first-operation-sees-vet-save-tigers-eye-184802328.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAAGP7h0IUZ29qdcOd11zbR60xsMo5zcxmYEG4kZ-XWb8dkZK6mPd_59O1FaXk0H6jRBLE75Jc3K27FoToZ9HU8rIBGLQg1VfNbSEJsIRJy4P2i2BtaFU2Ntoa1h6FPCSDIe3LiBRZCXW9FoBznFvIj2MT0Bd2Tcvt-AUQBoHP_6u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">34</a></sup> “It’s like we might do with any domestic cat,” said the doctor. “But with a lot more anesthetic.” The actor Vincent D’Onofrio confirmed that he was once mugged by a monkey, the government of the United Kingdom announced legislation formally designating certain animals as sentient, and the U.K. health minister declared that it was once again okay to hug.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/12/vincent-donofrio-interview-book-mutha-poetry" target="_blank" rel="noopener">35</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/animals-to-be-formally-recognised-as-sentient-beings-in-uk-law" target="_blank" rel="noopener">36</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/government-advise-caution-when-hugging-allowed-england" target="_blank" rel="noopener">37</a></sup></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-palestine-israel-darkside-pipeline-shutdown/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Lightning Farm]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-lightning-farm/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-lightning-farm/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 16:58:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Shortly before he left office, Donald Trump reactivated the federal death penalty—putting an end to a seventeen-year hiatus and executing an unprecedented thirteen people in less than a year. While the brutality of this killing spree is well-documented, the byzantine legal process through which it was authorized has received little attention. For the May issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine, </em>Caroline Lester traveled to the federal execution chamber in Terre Haute, Indiana, for the execution of Dustin Higgs, illuminating the brutishness of state power. As an appeals lawyer put it: “I’ve never been more afraid of the government than I was after those seven months.” The story she tells of Higgs’s attempts to negotiate with a government bent on killing its citizens implicates the entire legal system, from the Supreme Court to Obama’s attorney general. In this episode, Lester joins <em>Harper’s</em> web editor Violet Lucca to discuss her harrowing reporting process, the long and bipartisan history of state violence, and the inequity of the death penalty.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="The Lightning Farm by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1048800700&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-lightning-farm/" target="_blank">The Lightning Farm</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Deal 2.0?]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/new-deal-2-0/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/new-deal-2-0/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 22:01:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The United States officially calls itself a nation under God, which is why I wasn’t surprised when the media announced the Second Coming. Except they weren’t talking about Jesus Christ but about the country’s 32nd president, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, founder of the American welfare state, whom they believe is reincarnated in the form of our current president, Joe Biden.</p>
<p>Excuse me? Apparently, the assassin who killed Bernie Sanders’ presidential aspirations and his popular appeal for Medicare for All is now donning the clothing of a New Deal social democrat. Biden—once a supporter of Wall Street deregulation, a friend to credit-card companies, and a champion of free trade—is now appearing under the guise of a progressive like Elizabeth Warren, who has defended the economically vulnerable, declared war on the banks, and opposed concentrating wealth in 1 percent of the population. Biden—an extremely prudent politician who is courteous with colleagues—has somehow morphed not only into FDR, the father of the New Deal, but also into Lyndon Johnson, a president famous for his aggression, even brutality, when it came to “persuading” recalcitrant opponents to his point of view.</p>
<p>In April, the French daily newspaper <em>Le Monde</em> summed up what many pro-Biden commentators have said: “By presenting himself as a pragmatist concerned with concrete results, Joe Biden aims to become nothing short of a transformational president of the likes of Lyndon Baines Jonson or Franklin Delano Roosevelt, even though he hasn’t made this intention official, like his illustrious predecessors did.” Simon Kuper of the <em>Financial Times</em> left no room for irony when he wrote of the current president’s “newfound radicalism.”</p>
<p>As we speak, “Uncle Joe” is enjoying the general confusion created by his two enormous relief packages—the first already in place and the other slated for future public works—in which everyone sees what he or she wants to see. I do my part to try to examine the “concrete” facts rather than the illusions created by PR firms and journalists, but the members of the media remain so traumatized by Donald Trump’s presidency that they seem to have lost the ability to analyze even the most mundane events.</p>
<p>My starting point is a healthy skepticism of Biden’s “progressive” tendencies. His track record as a “new democrat” or neoliberal over the past four decades goes a long way in explaining his real character. Sure, the president wants to spend a whole lot of cash, just as his predecessor did. But at $1.9 trillion, the American Rescue Plan (ARP) that Biden enacted in March is only a little less expensive than the first COVID-19 rescue plan launched by President Trump in March 2020, though it was more generous in its direct payments to individuals—$1,400 versus $1,200. Trump’s and Biden’s respective projects are similar in scope, yet <em>New York Times</em> columnist Paul Krugman practically prostrated himself before Biden’s plan. He called it “breathtaking,” in part because of the one-year expansion of the child tax credit (CTC), which allows low-income families to receive direct government subsidies without having to prove need. A direct-benefit system for underprivileged mothers provided just enough to support a family of three until Bill Clinton and his allies, who included then-Senator Joe Biden, dismantled it in the 1990s. According to Krugman, the increased CTC benefit included in Biden’s plan amounts to less money—$6,000 to $7,200 for families with two parents earning less than $75,000 per year, compared with $15,000 in the pre-Clinton direct benefit system—but it’s unconditional.</p>
<p>Can Biden’s reforms be classified as radical in comparison with the establishment of Social Security (1935) and Medicare (1965)? Obviously not, since Biden’s rescue plan barely tackles the plight of the most disadvantaged of the nation’s 34 million people classified as below the official poverty level. Not to mention that Biden recently announced that the CTC increase would probably be temporary. In fact, the gross inequalities—the federal minimum wage remains at a ridiculously low $7.25 an hour—seem to be here to stay. And that’s exactly where Biden’s true colors are revealed.</p>
<p>With a tenuous majority in the Senate (Vice President Kamala Harris casts the deciding vote for the Democrats), Biden was forced to push his relief plan through Republican roadblocks using a process called reconciliation; otherwise he would have needed 60 votes to end an opposition filibuster. Film buffs who have seen James Stewart in <em>Mr. Smith goes to Washington</em> know that a filibuster can serve noble purposes.  Historically, though, it is an outmoded tactic used to hinder reform.</p>
<p>When it was first proposed, Biden’s American Rescue Plan contained a gradual increase of the minimum wage to $15 an hour by 2025, a key issue for real progressives in Congress. But the Senate parliamentarian ruled that this increase couldn’t be part of a reconciliation. Biden and his advisers gave in, and the increase was removed from the act, over the objections of Senator Sanders. But the compromise must have been a big relief for Biden, who didn’t want to antagonize two conservative Democrats, Joe Manchin and Kyrsten Sinema, who preferred an increase to $11. LBJ likely would have had the Senate parliamentarian fired or threatened to punish Manchin and Sinema by putting them on shit committees and blocking their pet projects.</p>
<p>The fact of the matter is that a family of four cannot live on $7.25 an hour, even with two parents working full time. It also cannot live on $11 an hour and can just barely survive on $15 an hour. Calling Joe Biden a radical is nonsense.</p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/new-deal-2-0/" target="_blank">New Deal 2.0?</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-india-mucormycosis-uk-elections-medina-spirit/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-india-mucormycosis-uk-elections-medina-spirit/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 17:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">It was reported that an increasing number of Indian patients who have survived COVID-19 develop mucormycosis, also known as black fungus, a rare condition that is fatal in 50 percent of cases.<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-57027829" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>1</sup></a> Pfizer, which will generate an estimated $26 billion in revenue from its vaccine this year and whose veterinarian CEO told shareholders that he expected “durable demand” to continue indefinitely, opposed the World Trade Organization’s plan to waive intellectual-property protections for manufacturing coronavirus vaccines, as did the European Union.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/us/politics/biden-covid-vaccine-patents.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/04/business/pfizer-covid-vaccine-profits.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> In the United States, local officials have begun turning down hundreds of thousands of vaccine doses because demand has declined, and a new study estimated that the U.S. death toll from COVID-19 has reached 900,000 people, a number that is 57 percent higher than the official count.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2021/05/06/994287048/new-study-estimates-more-than-900-000-people-have-died-of-covid-19-in-u-s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/08/us/us-states-are-turning-down-hundreds-of-thousands-of-doses-as-demand-plummets.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> South Carolina’s legislature approved death by firing squad as a legal means of capital punishment, and evidence showed that the DNA of an Arkansas man who maintained his innocence before his execution in 2017 did not match genetic material from the crime scene.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/south-carolina-executions-a6bbef9c9a85b248f5bc7c0c57ad0cbe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://katv.com/news/local/tests-reveal-dna-evidence-in-executed-arkansas-inmates-case" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> “Every time we see a story that is the worst we’ve seen, another one comes along,” said an activist in San Francisco’s Chinese community after a man stabbed two Asian women in front of a flower stall in the city’s downtown, and in Piedmont, California, a school began and then ended a support group for white students to process the trial of Derek Chauvin.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/us/asian-attack-san-francisco.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://www.insider.com/ca-school-white-students-support-circle-chauvin-verdict-floyd-2021-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a></sup> Atlanta reinstated the police officer charged with murdering Rayshard Brooks, a black man, in the parking lot of a Wendy’s last June, finding that the officer’s firing “seemed rushed” and violated his right to due process.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/us/atlanta-rayshard-brooks-garrett-rolfe.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> “The sexual nature of this organ is irrelevant,” said a Canadian judge who ruled that an officer had acted lawfully when he grabbed and twisted a man’s genitals to garner compliance in an arrest.<sup><a href="https://www.nnsl.com/news/genital-grab-legal-in-gaining-compliance-for-arrest-judge-rules/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a></sup></p>
<p>France and England sent warships to the island of Jersey after French fishers blocked a port to protest new Brexit regulations, and after a church warden with the keys to a polling location overslept, residents of Oxford, England, cast votes for local elections in the trunk of a car.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/06/uk/britain-france-war-ships-jersey-cmd-intl-gbr/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-45337091" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> </sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-oxfordshire-57010009" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>14</sup></a> “What’s happened now is they can see we did get Brexit done,” said Boris Johnson in response to the Conservative Party’s winning seats across the United Kingdom.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/05/08/995069404/u-k-elections-conservatives-make-gains-pro-independence-parties-win-in-scotland" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> Arizona’s secretary of state criticized a Republican effort to overturn the presidential election by recounting ballots; among the concerns she cited were partisan tabulators, such as one man who was photographed at the January 6 Capitol riot, and untrained observers looking for traces of bamboo in an effort to uncloak fraudulent ballots shipped from Asia.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/06/us/arizona-vote-count-republicans.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> In Virginia, vote counting in Republican primary elections was delayed for hours after a housekeeper delivered coffee to a room where ballots were stored overnight.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/virginia-politics/virginia-republican-convention-remote-vote/2021/05/09/5becf312-ad12-11eb-acd3-24b44a57093a_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> “I just wanted to fit in with the circus that is this process,” said an observer who was dressed as a circus ringmaster with a top hat and red satin tails. “This is emblematic of what is happening to our Country. The whole world is laughing at us,” wrote Donald Trump in response to news that Medina Spirit, the winner of the Kentucky Derby, had been given performance-enhancing drugs.<sup><a href="https://www.cincinnati.com/story/news/2021/05/10/donald-trump-calls-medina-spirit-junky-kentucky-derby-winner-positive-drug-test/5019823001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> “It was like kind of a cancel culture kind of a thing,” said Medina Spirit’s trainer after the positive drug test.<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/Mediaite/status/1391765065179746306" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> “I’m so uninterested in that,” said Zoom CEO Eric Yuan while discussing his Zoom fatigue.<sup><a href="https://www.reportwire.in/even-the-ceo-of-zoom-says-he-has-zoom-fatigue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> Huawei’s CEO, whose daughter was arrested in Canada after U.S. authorities discovered a PowerPoint presentation that revealed the company’s violations of sanctions against Iran, instructed his employees to meet in person instead of emailing and to use fewer adjectives in written materials.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/the_americas/huawei-executive-facing-extradition-to-the-united-states-to-argue-the-allegations-arent-crimes-in-canada/2020/01/20/e6525174-37e7-11ea-a1ff-c48c1d59a4a1_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/huawei-ren-memo-ceo/2021/05/10/b321bf3a-b15b-11eb-bc96-fdf55de43bef_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup></p>
<p>West Midlands Trains received criticism after it emailed a phishing test to its employees in which they were praised for their hard work during the pandemic and informed they would receive a one-time payment once they clicked a link contained in the message.<sup><a href="https://theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/train-firms-worker-bonus-email-is-actually-cyber-security-test" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> Nebraska governor Pete Ricketts endorsed the Nebraska Beef Passport, and more than 45,000 people applied to cull bison herds in the Grand Canyon National Park.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/nebraska-lifestyle-business-environment-and-nature-government-and-politics-bccf3e94aeb44a33432995b9b1624b52" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/07/us/grand-canyon-national-park-bison-hunting.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a></sup> In Nashville, Tennessee, a man was arrested outside Kid Rock’s Big Honky Tonk Rock N’ Roll Steakhouse after swinging his colostomy bag at police officers.<sup><a href="https://www.foxnews.com/food-drink/kid-rock-tennessee-drunk-suspect-colostomy-bag" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> The DWI Dude, a Texas lawyer who specialized in defending those charged with drunk driving, was sentenced to more than 15 years in prison for defrauding Colombian cocaine traffickers.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/us/james-balagia-dwi-dude-texas.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a></sup> “We live in a country with the greatest system of justice in the world,” said the acting U.S. attorney in the Eastern District of Texas. A new book argues that famed scam artist Frank Abagnale Jr. lied about his time as a hoaxer.<sup><a href="https://whyy.org/segments/the-greatest-hoax-on-earth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a></sup> <em>—Cameron French</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-india-mucormycosis-uk-elections-medina-spirit/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-covid-vaccine-patents-variants-mike-lindell/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-covid-vaccine-patents-variants-mike-lindell/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 18:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">It was reported that there were almost as many COVID-19 cases globally last week as there were in the first five months of the pandemic, and that one out of every three new cases was in India, which is home to the world’s largest vaccine manufacturer.<sup><a href="https://www.who.int/multi-media/details/who-press-conference-on-coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)---26-april-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/03/india-covid-crisis-charts-show-the-severity-of-the-second-wave.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/05/why-covid-vaccine-producer-india-faces-major-shortage-of-doses.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> Bill Gates, whose foundation urged Oxford University to grant AstraZeneca exclusive rights to its vaccine, stated that he opposed lifting intellectual property restrictions on vaccines, urged the United Kingdom to increase its foreign aid budget in order to purchase more vaccines for developing countries, and falsely claimed that generic vaccine manufacturers in those countries wouldn’t be able to meet current demand quickly or safely.<sup><a href="https://news.sky.com/story/covid-19-bill-gates-hopeful-world-completely-back-to-normal-by-end-of-2022-and-vaccine-sharing-to-ramp-up-12285840" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://khn.org/news/rather-than-give-away-its-covid-vaccine-oxford-makes-a-deal-with-drugmaker/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/indias-covid-19-crisis-raises-pressure-to-waive-vaccine-patents-11619861401" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://lenews.ch/2021/04/29/basel-offers-beggars-one-way-tickets-anywhere-in-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> </sup>“People didn’t invest enough in this risk,” said Gates. “So I hope we keep in mind that we do need to invest and be ready for the next pandemic.” “I don’t want them to look back in 20 years and say that we could’ve done more,” said Ontario premier Doug Ford, who reopened his province’s economy over objections from epidemiologists about new COVID-19 variants, during a press conference in which he stated that 90 percent of average daily cases in the province were “variants of concern” and lamented his inability to restrict all land border crossings to essential travel.<sup><a href="https://www.cp24.com/news/40-of-adults-in-ontario-will-have-received-first-covid-19-vaccine-dose-by-end-of-friday-ford-1.5408668" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://www.cp24.com/news/ford-hints-at-announcement-next-week-on-eventual-reopening-of-the-economy-1.5294088?cache=havfyladuxaywoyv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/KamilKaramali/status/1388165513549946880" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> For a second week in a row, the Blackfeet Nation, which borders the province of Alberta, donated its extra vaccines to Canadians; “Do not send your kids. Period,” Joe Biden told an interviewer who asked the president what message he wanted to send to migrant parents; and the city of Basel, Switzerland, began offering one-way train tickets to beggars if they signed a contract agreeing not to return.<sup><a href="https://calgary.ctvnews.ca/we-want-our-lives-back-blackfeet-nation-shares-covid-vaccines-with-canadians-1.5406699" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://people.com/politics/joe-biden-message-to-migrant-parents-do-not-send-your-kids/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> </sup><a href="http://reuters.com/world/us/biden-heeds-complaints-lifts-refugee-cap-62500-2021-05-03/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>13</sup></a> <sup><a href="https://lenews.ch/2021/04/29/basel-offers-beggars-one-way-tickets-anywhere-in-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a></sup> “If everybody would be this generous, we wouldn’t have much trouble in the world,” said a woman who drove six hours to receive her second shot at the reservation.</p>
<p>Corn prices hit a seven-year high amid fears of scarcity, and, citing increased consumer interest in vitamins, Nestlé purchased Nature’s Bounty.<sup><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/26/corn-futures-jump-to-a-7-year-high-on-supply-concerns.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/nestle-expands-in-vitamins-with-5-75-billion-natures-bounty-deal-11619778234" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> The FDA announced that it would move to ban the sale of menthol cigarettes and flavored cigars.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/04/29/991973192/fda-moves-to-ban-menthol-cigarettes-and-flavored-cigars" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> Governor Greg Abbott said that he would sign a bill allowing Texans to carry firearms without background checks, training, or permits.<sup><a href="https://www.kctv5.com/texas-pushes-closer-to-dropping-handgun-license-requirement/article_2387b5ce-ecbc-5903-a851-7c39df2ae275.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> Idaho’s governor signed a bill banning abortions after six weeks, Arizona’s governor signed a bill banning abortions performed because of nonfatal genetic abnormalities, and Republican members of both chambers of the Tennessee state legislature revived a bill that would make it a felony to block traffic while protesting and extend immunity to drivers who run over demonstrators as long as they are “exercising due care.”<sup><a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/top-news/articles/2021-04-28/idaho-passes-fetal-heartbeat-abortion-ban" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/arizona-governor-signs-abortion-ban-genetic-issues-n1265645" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> <a href="https://www.tennessean.com/story/news/politics/2021/04/29/tennessee-bill-offers-immunity-drivers-running-over-protesters/4881949001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></sup> In a Zoom meeting, former secretaries of state Condoleezza Rice and Hillary Clinton expressed concern over the withdrawal of U.S. troops from Afghanistan and asserted the need to maintain counterterrorism programs in the region.<sup><a href="https://www.axios.com/hillary-clinton-condoleezza-rice-biden-afghanistan-troops-9e115f31-85c4-4f30-9663-30dd6e572895.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup> “Condi Rice is like, ‘You know, we’re probably gonna have to go back,’&thinsp;” said one attendee. The Catholic Mobilizing Network and other anti–death penalty activist groups criticized Biden, the second Catholic president and the first to have campaigned on ending the death penalty, for failing in his first 100 days in office to take steps to cease capital punishment.<sup><a href="https://www.catholicnewsagency.com/news/247460/as-biden-presidency-passes-100-days-catholics-push-him-to-end-federal-death-penalty" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> Mitt Romney was booed and almost censured at the Utah Republican Convention, and George Walker Bush, whose ancestors arrived on the <em>Mayflower, </em>said that the Republican Party should move away from “exclusivity” and favoritism toward white Anglo-Saxon Protestants if it hopes to rule again.<sup><a href="https://www.sltrib.com/news/politics/2021/05/03/rundown-romney/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Prescott-Bush" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/george-w-bush-republicans-elections-white-anglo-saxon-protestantism-2021-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> Legislators in Maine voted to more strictly regulate “forever chemicals” in drinking water.<sup><a href="https://www.pressherald.com/2021/04/30/committee-recommends-stricter-water-standards-for-forever-chemicals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a></sup></p>
<p>It was reported that the online retailer Etsy has failed to prevent the sale of items prohibited by its terms of service and U.S. laws, including ivory, replica WWI trench clubs, the remains of cats and dogs, and uranium ore.<sup><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/etsy-sells-ivory-weapons-poisonous-plants-mass-produced-products-2021-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a></sup> A web designer in Buenos Aires purchased Google’s Argentinian domain for approximately $2.90.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/apr/27/argentinian-buys-googles-domain-name-for-2-pounds?utm_term=27d75a4476c221c41afb9c0382c47fe9&amp;utm_campaign=GuardianTodayUK&amp;utm_source=esp&amp;utm_medium=Email&amp;CMP=GTUK_email" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a></sup> MyPillow CEO Mike Lindell announced that he would launch Frank, a social media and podcasting platform, at an upcoming rally to be held at South Dakota’s Corn Palace.<sup><a href="https://www.twincities.com/2021/04/29/mypillow-mike-lindell-social-media-frank-south-dakota-corn-palace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a></sup> A day before Facebook’s oversight board announced its decision to uphold the platform’s ban on Donald Trump for the next six months, the former president launched “From the Desk of Donald Trump,” a website where Trump’s microblogs can be liked and shared on Twitter or Facebook.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56989500" target="_blank" rel="noopener">33</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/technology/facebook-trump-ban-upheld.html?action=click&amp;module=Spotlight&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener">34</a></sup> Bill Gates announced his divorce in a tweet.<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/BillGates/status/1389316412259270657" target="_blank" rel="noopener">35</a></sup>—<em>Violet Lucca</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-covid-vaccine-patents-variants-mike-lindell/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>