<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Harper's Magazine</title>
        <link>https://harpers.org/</link>
        <description>null</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 16:58:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/ruicosta042/rssconv-action</generator>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Lightning Farm]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-lightning-farm/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-lightning-farm/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 16:58:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Shortly before he left office, Donald Trump reactivated the federal death penalty—putting an end to a seventeen-year hiatus and executing an unprecedented thirteen people in less than a year. While the brutality of this killing spree is well-documented, the byzantine legal process through which it was authorized has received little attention. For the May issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine, </em>Caroline Lester traveled to the federal execution chamber in Terre Haute, Indiana, for the execution of Dustin Higgs, illuminating the brutishness of state power. As an appeals lawyer put it: “I’ve never been more afraid of the government than I was after those seven months.” The story she tells of Higgs’s attempts to negotiate with a government bent on killing its citizens implicates the entire legal system, from the Supreme Court to Obama’s attorney general. In this episode, Lester joins <em>Harper’s</em> web editor Violet Lucca to discuss her harrowing reporting process, the long and bipartisan history of state violence, and the inequity of the death penalty.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="The Lightning Farm by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1048800700&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-lightning-farm/" target="_blank">The Lightning Farm</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Deal 2.0?]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/new-deal-2-0/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/new-deal-2-0/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 22:01:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">The United States officially calls itself a nation under God, which is why I wasn’t surprised when the media announced the Second Coming. Except they weren’t talking about Jesus Christ but about the country’s 32nd president, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, founder of the American welfare state, whom they believe is reincarnated in the form of our current president, Joe Biden.</p>
<p>Excuse me? Apparently, the assassin who killed Bernie Sanders’ presidential aspirations and his popular appeal for Medicare for All is now donning the clothing of a New Deal social democrat. Biden—once a supporter of Wall Street deregulation, a friend to credit-card companies, and a champion of free trade—is now appearing under the guise of a progressive like Elizabeth Warren, who has defended the economically vulnerable, declared war on the banks, and opposed concentrating wealth in 1 percent of the population. Biden—an extremely prudent politician who is courteous with colleagues—has somehow morphed not only into FDR, the father of the New Deal, but also into Lyndon Johnson, a president famous for his aggression, even brutality, when it came to “persuading” recalcitrant opponents to his point of view.</p>
<p>In April, the French daily newspaper <em>Le Monde</em> summed up what many pro-Biden commentators have said: “By presenting himself as a pragmatist concerned with concrete results, Joe Biden aims to become nothing short of a transformational president of the likes of Lyndon Baines Jonson or Franklin Delano Roosevelt, even though he hasn’t made this intention official, like his illustrious predecessors did.” Simon Kuper of the <em>Financial Times</em> left no room for irony when he wrote of the current president’s “newfound radicalism.”</p>
<p>As we speak, “Uncle Joe” is enjoying the general confusion created by his two enormous relief packages—the first already in place and the other slated for future public works—in which everyone sees what he or she wants to see. I do my part to try to examine the “concrete” facts rather than the illusions created by PR firms and journalists, but the members of the media remain so traumatized by Donald Trump’s presidency that they seem to have lost the ability to analyze even the most mundane events.</p>
<p>My starting point is a healthy skepticism of Biden’s “progressive” tendencies. His track record as a “new democrat” or neoliberal over the past four decades goes a long way in explaining his real character. Sure, the president wants to spend a whole lot of cash, just as his predecessor did. But at $1.9 trillion, the American Rescue Plan (ARP) that Biden enacted in March is only a little less expensive than the first COVID-19 rescue plan launched by President Trump in March 2020, though it was more generous in its direct payments to individuals—$1,400 versus $1,200. Trump’s and Biden’s respective projects are similar in scope, yet <em>New York Times</em> columnist Paul Krugman practically prostrated himself before Biden’s plan. He called it “breathtaking,” in part because of the one-year expansion of the child tax credit (CTC), which allows low-income families to receive direct government subsidies without having to prove need. A direct-benefit system for underprivileged mothers provided just enough to support a family of three until Bill Clinton and his allies, who included then-Senator Joe Biden, dismantled it in the 1990s. According to Krugman, the increased CTC benefit included in Biden’s plan amounts to less money—$6,000 to $7,200 for families with two parents earning less than $75,000 per year, compared with $15,000 in the pre-Clinton direct benefit system—but it’s unconditional.</p>
<p>Can Biden’s reforms be classified as radical in comparison with the establishment of Social Security (1935) and Medicare (1965)? Obviously not, since Biden’s rescue plan barely tackles the plight of the most disadvantaged of the nation’s 34 million people classified as below the official poverty level. Not to mention that Biden recently announced that the CTC increase would probably be temporary. In fact, the gross inequalities—the federal minimum wage remains at a ridiculously low $7.25 an hour—seem to be here to stay. And that’s exactly where Biden’s true colors are revealed.</p>
<p>With a tenuous majority in the Senate (Vice President Kamala Harris casts the deciding vote for the Democrats), Biden was forced to push his relief plan through Republican roadblocks using a process called reconciliation; otherwise he would have needed 60 votes to end an opposition filibuster. Film buffs who have seen James Stewart in <em>Mr. Smith goes to Washington</em> know that a filibuster can serve noble purposes.  Historically, though, it is an outmoded tactic used to hinder reform.</p>
<p>When it was first proposed, Biden’s American Rescue Plan contained a gradual increase of the minimum wage to $15 an hour by 2025, a key issue for real progressives in Congress. But the Senate parliamentarian ruled that this increase couldn’t be part of a reconciliation. Biden and his advisers gave in, and the increase was removed from the act, over the objections of Senator Sanders. But the compromise must have been a big relief for Biden, who didn’t want to antagonize two conservative Democrats, Joe Manchin and Kyrsten Sinema, who preferred an increase to $11. LBJ likely would have had the Senate parliamentarian fired or threatened to punish Manchin and Sinema by putting them on shit committees and blocking their pet projects.</p>
<p>The fact of the matter is that a family of four cannot live on $7.25 an hour, even with two parents working full time. It also cannot live on $11 an hour and can just barely survive on $15 an hour. Calling Joe Biden a radical is nonsense.</p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/new-deal-2-0/" target="_blank">New Deal 2.0?</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-india-mucormycosis-uk-elections-medina-spirit/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-india-mucormycosis-uk-elections-medina-spirit/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 17:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">It was reported that an increasing number of Indian patients who have survived COVID-19 develop mucormycosis, also known as black fungus, a rare condition that is fatal in 50 percent of cases.<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-57027829" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>1</sup></a> Pfizer, which will generate an estimated $26 billion in revenue from its vaccine this year and whose veterinarian CEO told shareholders that he expected “durable demand” to continue indefinitely, opposed the World Trade Organization’s plan to waive intellectual-property protections for manufacturing coronavirus vaccines, as did the European Union.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/us/politics/biden-covid-vaccine-patents.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/04/business/pfizer-covid-vaccine-profits.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> In the United States, local officials have begun turning down hundreds of thousands of vaccine doses because demand has declined, and a new study estimated that the U.S. death toll from COVID-19 has reached 900,000 people, a number that is 57 percent higher than the official count.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2021/05/06/994287048/new-study-estimates-more-than-900-000-people-have-died-of-covid-19-in-u-s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/08/us/us-states-are-turning-down-hundreds-of-thousands-of-doses-as-demand-plummets.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> South Carolina’s legislature approved death by firing squad as a legal means of capital punishment, and evidence showed that the DNA of an Arkansas man who maintained his innocence before his execution in 2017 did not match genetic material from the crime scene.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/south-carolina-executions-a6bbef9c9a85b248f5bc7c0c57ad0cbe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://katv.com/news/local/tests-reveal-dna-evidence-in-executed-arkansas-inmates-case" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> “Every time we see a story that is the worst we’ve seen, another one comes along,” said an activist in San Francisco’s Chinese community after a man stabbed two Asian women in front of a flower stall in the city’s downtown, and in Piedmont, California, a school began and then ended a support group for white students to process the trial of Derek Chauvin.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/us/asian-attack-san-francisco.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://www.insider.com/ca-school-white-students-support-circle-chauvin-verdict-floyd-2021-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a></sup> Atlanta reinstated the police officer charged with murdering Rayshard Brooks, a black man, in the parking lot of a Wendy’s last June, finding that the officer’s firing “seemed rushed” and violated his right to due process.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/us/atlanta-rayshard-brooks-garrett-rolfe.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> “The sexual nature of this organ is irrelevant,” said a Canadian judge who ruled that an officer had acted lawfully when he grabbed and twisted a man’s genitals to garner compliance in an arrest.<sup><a href="https://www.nnsl.com/news/genital-grab-legal-in-gaining-compliance-for-arrest-judge-rules/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a></sup></p>
<p>France and England sent warships to the island of Jersey after French fishers blocked a port to protest new Brexit regulations, and after a church warden with the keys to a polling location overslept, residents of Oxford, England, cast votes for local elections in the trunk of a car.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/06/uk/britain-france-war-ships-jersey-cmd-intl-gbr/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-45337091" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> </sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-oxfordshire-57010009" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>14</sup></a> “What’s happened now is they can see we did get Brexit done,” said Boris Johnson in response to the Conservative Party’s winning seats across the United Kingdom.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/05/08/995069404/u-k-elections-conservatives-make-gains-pro-independence-parties-win-in-scotland" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> Arizona’s secretary of state criticized a Republican effort to overturn the presidential election by recounting ballots; among the concerns she cited were partisan tabulators, such as one man who was photographed at the January 6 Capitol riot, and untrained observers looking for traces of bamboo in an effort to uncloak fraudulent ballots shipped from Asia.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/06/us/arizona-vote-count-republicans.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> In Virginia, vote counting in Republican primary elections was delayed for hours after a housekeeper delivered coffee to a room where ballots were stored overnight.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/virginia-politics/virginia-republican-convention-remote-vote/2021/05/09/5becf312-ad12-11eb-acd3-24b44a57093a_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> “I just wanted to fit in with the circus that is this process,” said an observer who was dressed as a circus ringmaster with a top hat and red satin tails. “This is emblematic of what is happening to our Country. The whole world is laughing at us,” wrote Donald Trump in response to news that Medina Spirit, the winner of the Kentucky Derby, had been given performance-enhancing drugs.<sup><a href="https://www.cincinnati.com/story/news/2021/05/10/donald-trump-calls-medina-spirit-junky-kentucky-derby-winner-positive-drug-test/5019823001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> “It was like kind of a cancel culture kind of a thing,” said Medina Spirit’s trainer after the positive drug test.<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/Mediaite/status/1391765065179746306" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> “I’m so uninterested in that,” said Zoom CEO Eric Yuan while discussing his Zoom fatigue.<sup><a href="https://www.reportwire.in/even-the-ceo-of-zoom-says-he-has-zoom-fatigue/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a></sup> Huawei’s CEO, whose daughter was arrested in Canada after U.S. authorities discovered a PowerPoint presentation that revealed the company’s violations of sanctions against Iran, instructed his employees to meet in person instead of emailing and to use fewer adjectives in written materials.<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/the_americas/huawei-executive-facing-extradition-to-the-united-states-to-argue-the-allegations-arent-crimes-in-canada/2020/01/20/e6525174-37e7-11ea-a1ff-c48c1d59a4a1_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/huawei-ren-memo-ceo/2021/05/10/b321bf3a-b15b-11eb-bc96-fdf55de43bef_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup></p>
<p>West Midlands Trains received criticism after it emailed a phishing test to its employees in which they were praised for their hard work during the pandemic and informed they would receive a one-time payment once they clicked a link contained in the message.<sup><a href="https://theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/train-firms-worker-bonus-email-is-actually-cyber-security-test" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> Nebraska governor Pete Ricketts endorsed the Nebraska Beef Passport, and more than 45,000 people applied to cull bison herds in the Grand Canyon National Park.<sup><a href="https://apnews.com/article/nebraska-lifestyle-business-environment-and-nature-government-and-politics-bccf3e94aeb44a33432995b9b1624b52" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/07/us/grand-canyon-national-park-bison-hunting.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a></sup> In Nashville, Tennessee, a man was arrested outside Kid Rock’s Big Honky Tonk Rock N’ Roll Steakhouse after swinging his colostomy bag at police officers.<sup><a href="https://www.foxnews.com/food-drink/kid-rock-tennessee-drunk-suspect-colostomy-bag" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> The DWI Dude, a Texas lawyer who specialized in defending those charged with drunk driving, was sentenced to more than 15 years in prison for defrauding Colombian cocaine traffickers.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/us/james-balagia-dwi-dude-texas.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a></sup> “We live in a country with the greatest system of justice in the world,” said the acting U.S. attorney in the Eastern District of Texas. A new book argues that famed scam artist Frank Abagnale Jr. lied about his time as a hoaxer.<sup><a href="https://whyy.org/segments/the-greatest-hoax-on-earth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a></sup> <em>—Cameron French</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-india-mucormycosis-uk-elections-medina-spirit/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-covid-vaccine-patents-variants-mike-lindell/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-covid-vaccine-patents-variants-mike-lindell/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 18:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">It was reported that there were almost as many COVID-19 cases globally last week as there were in the first five months of the pandemic, and that one out of every three new cases was in India, which is home to the world’s largest vaccine manufacturer.<sup><a href="https://www.who.int/multi-media/details/who-press-conference-on-coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)---26-april-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/03/india-covid-crisis-charts-show-the-severity-of-the-second-wave.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/05/why-covid-vaccine-producer-india-faces-major-shortage-of-doses.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a></sup> Bill Gates, whose foundation urged Oxford University to grant AstraZeneca exclusive rights to its vaccine, stated that he opposed lifting intellectual property restrictions on vaccines, urged the United Kingdom to increase its foreign aid budget in order to purchase more vaccines for developing countries, and falsely claimed that generic vaccine manufacturers in those countries wouldn’t be able to meet current demand quickly or safely.<sup><a href="https://news.sky.com/story/covid-19-bill-gates-hopeful-world-completely-back-to-normal-by-end-of-2022-and-vaccine-sharing-to-ramp-up-12285840" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://khn.org/news/rather-than-give-away-its-covid-vaccine-oxford-makes-a-deal-with-drugmaker/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/indias-covid-19-crisis-raises-pressure-to-waive-vaccine-patents-11619861401" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a> <a href="https://lenews.ch/2021/04/29/basel-offers-beggars-one-way-tickets-anywhere-in-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a> </sup>“People didn’t invest enough in this risk,” said Gates. “So I hope we keep in mind that we do need to invest and be ready for the next pandemic.” “I don’t want them to look back in 20 years and say that we could’ve done more,” said Ontario premier Doug Ford, who reopened his province’s economy over objections from epidemiologists about new COVID-19 variants, during a press conference in which he stated that 90 percent of average daily cases in the province were “variants of concern” and lamented his inability to restrict all land border crossings to essential travel.<sup><a href="https://www.cp24.com/news/40-of-adults-in-ontario-will-have-received-first-covid-19-vaccine-dose-by-end-of-friday-ford-1.5408668" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a href="https://www.cp24.com/news/ford-hints-at-announcement-next-week-on-eventual-reopening-of-the-economy-1.5294088?cache=havfyladuxaywoyv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/KamilKaramali/status/1388165513549946880" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> For a second week in a row, the Blackfeet Nation, which borders the province of Alberta, donated its extra vaccines to Canadians; “Do not send your kids. Period,” Joe Biden told an interviewer who asked the president what message he wanted to send to migrant parents; and the city of Basel, Switzerland, began offering one-way train tickets to beggars if they signed a contract agreeing not to return.<sup><a href="https://calgary.ctvnews.ca/we-want-our-lives-back-blackfeet-nation-shares-covid-vaccines-with-canadians-1.5406699" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a href="https://people.com/politics/joe-biden-message-to-migrant-parents-do-not-send-your-kids/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> </sup><a href="http://reuters.com/world/us/biden-heeds-complaints-lifts-refugee-cap-62500-2021-05-03/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>13</sup></a> <sup><a href="https://lenews.ch/2021/04/29/basel-offers-beggars-one-way-tickets-anywhere-in-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a></sup> “If everybody would be this generous, we wouldn’t have much trouble in the world,” said a woman who drove six hours to receive her second shot at the reservation.</p>
<p>Corn prices hit a seven-year high amid fears of scarcity, and, citing increased consumer interest in vitamins, Nestlé purchased Nature’s Bounty.<sup><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/26/corn-futures-jump-to-a-7-year-high-on-supply-concerns.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/nestle-expands-in-vitamins-with-5-75-billion-natures-bounty-deal-11619778234" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> The FDA announced that it would move to ban the sale of menthol cigarettes and flavored cigars.<sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/04/29/991973192/fda-moves-to-ban-menthol-cigarettes-and-flavored-cigars" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a></sup> Governor Greg Abbott said that he would sign a bill allowing Texans to carry firearms without background checks, training, or permits.<sup><a href="https://www.kctv5.com/texas-pushes-closer-to-dropping-handgun-license-requirement/article_2387b5ce-ecbc-5903-a851-7c39df2ae275.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a></sup> Idaho’s governor signed a bill banning abortions after six weeks, Arizona’s governor signed a bill banning abortions performed because of nonfatal genetic abnormalities, and Republican members of both chambers of the Tennessee state legislature revived a bill that would make it a felony to block traffic while protesting and extend immunity to drivers who run over demonstrators as long as they are “exercising due care.”<sup><a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/top-news/articles/2021-04-28/idaho-passes-fetal-heartbeat-abortion-ban" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/arizona-governor-signs-abortion-ban-genetic-issues-n1265645" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> <a href="https://www.tennessean.com/story/news/politics/2021/04/29/tennessee-bill-offers-immunity-drivers-running-over-protesters/4881949001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></sup> In a Zoom meeting, former secretaries of state Condoleezza Rice and Hillary Clinton expressed concern over the withdrawal of U.S. troops from Afghanistan and asserted the need to maintain counterterrorism programs in the region.<sup><a href="https://www.axios.com/hillary-clinton-condoleezza-rice-biden-afghanistan-troops-9e115f31-85c4-4f30-9663-30dd6e572895.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup> “Condi Rice is like, ‘You know, we’re probably gonna have to go back,’&thinsp;” said one attendee. The Catholic Mobilizing Network and other anti–death penalty activist groups criticized Biden, the second Catholic president and the first to have campaigned on ending the death penalty, for failing in his first 100 days in office to take steps to cease capital punishment.<sup><a href="https://www.catholicnewsagency.com/news/247460/as-biden-presidency-passes-100-days-catholics-push-him-to-end-federal-death-penalty" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a></sup> Mitt Romney was booed and almost censured at the Utah Republican Convention, and George Walker Bush, whose ancestors arrived on the <em>Mayflower, </em>said that the Republican Party should move away from “exclusivity” and favoritism toward white Anglo-Saxon Protestants if it hopes to rule again.<sup><a href="https://www.sltrib.com/news/politics/2021/05/03/rundown-romney/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Prescott-Bush" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/george-w-bush-republicans-elections-white-anglo-saxon-protestantism-2021-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> Legislators in Maine voted to more strictly regulate “forever chemicals” in drinking water.<sup><a href="https://www.pressherald.com/2021/04/30/committee-recommends-stricter-water-standards-for-forever-chemicals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a></sup></p>
<p>It was reported that the online retailer Etsy has failed to prevent the sale of items prohibited by its terms of service and U.S. laws, including ivory, replica WWI trench clubs, the remains of cats and dogs, and uranium ore.<sup><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/etsy-sells-ivory-weapons-poisonous-plants-mass-produced-products-2021-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a></sup> A web designer in Buenos Aires purchased Google’s Argentinian domain for approximately $2.90.<sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/apr/27/argentinian-buys-googles-domain-name-for-2-pounds?utm_term=27d75a4476c221c41afb9c0382c47fe9&amp;utm_campaign=GuardianTodayUK&amp;utm_source=esp&amp;utm_medium=Email&amp;CMP=GTUK_email" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a></sup> MyPillow CEO Mike Lindell announced that he would launch Frank, a social media and podcasting platform, at an upcoming rally to be held at South Dakota’s Corn Palace.<sup><a href="https://www.twincities.com/2021/04/29/mypillow-mike-lindell-social-media-frank-south-dakota-corn-palace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">32</a></sup> A day before Facebook’s oversight board announced its decision to uphold the platform’s ban on Donald Trump for the next six months, the former president launched “From the Desk of Donald Trump,” a website where Trump’s microblogs can be liked and shared on Twitter or Facebook.<sup><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56989500" target="_blank" rel="noopener">33</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/05/technology/facebook-trump-ban-upheld.html?action=click&amp;module=Spotlight&amp;pgtype=Homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener">34</a></sup> Bill Gates announced his divorce in a tweet.<sup><a href="https://twitter.com/BillGates/status/1389316412259270657" target="_blank" rel="noopener">35</a></sup>—<em>Violet Lucca</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/weekly-review-covid-vaccine-patents-variants-mike-lindell/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The French Fiasco]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-french-fiasco/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-french-fiasco/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 15:10:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<div style="width: 200px; border: 1px solid black; background-color: white; margin-left: 30px; padding: 30px; padding-bottom: 30px; float: right; font-size: 90%;">A <a href="https://www.ledevoir.com/opinion/chroniques/598600/le-fiasco-francais" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">version</a> of this column originally ran in <em>Le Devoir</em> on May 3, 2021. Translated from the French by Elettra Pauletto.</div>
<p class="drop-cap">When the COVID-19 lockdown began, I jokingly told friends that I could take advantage of my dual citizenship to get vaccinated before my fellow Americans at my neighborhood pharmacy in Paris or at the French consulate in New York. Sooner rather than later, I thought, France would be stocked with plenty of vaccines to protect the fortunate descendants of Joan of Arc. After all, it’s only natural to believe that the birthplace of Louis Pasteur would be leading the charge to prevent and treat the virus. Along with its strong tradition of biological research, France had a significant political edge: Emmanuel Macron possesses an intelligence and education up to the task of vaccine distribution, as opposed to the self-centered Donald Trump, who is downright idiotic in his views on science. France’s centralized, interventionist government would have no problem besting a country dominated by states’ rights and capitalist ideologies often blind to the public interest.</p>
<p>But there I was, on March 31, receiving my second shot, not in Paris’s swanky 7th arrondissement or in the elegant halls of the French consulate in Manhattan but in a clinic in the South Bronx, one of the poorest neighborhoods in New York City. What’s more, I was given Moderna, a vaccine developed by an American company. As I left the clinic, I was delighted to see the city coming alive again, even as Paris was sinking back into another depressing lockdown.</p>
<p>What went wrong in France? How did the Trump Administration manage to succeed where France had failed so spectacularly? How can it be that 56 percent of American adults are now vaccinated against COVID-19 compared to 27 percent of French adults? According to the weekly magazine <em>Paris Match</em>, France’s “fiasco” was in large part due to a rivalry between two scientists at the Pasteur Institute, Frédéric Tangy and Nicolas Escriou. Apparently unable to get them to collaborate, the institute ended up betting, wrongly, on Escriou, as well as Merck, an American pharmaceutical giant that had purchased the exclusive license to the vaccine labeled “project V591.” Another theory, espoused by the online magazine <em>Mediapart</em>, blames the failure to produce a vaccine in France on Sanofi, the last officially French pharmaceutical company. Sanofi had declined to purchase V591 and instead pursued its own research, which to date has come to naught, aside from a few grandiose PR statements. According to <em>Mediapart</em>, this catastrophic failure can be attributed to “the rejection of all industrial politics, together with the disappearance of countless skill sets among state actors, 30 years of sacrifices imposed on public research because considered an excessive expenditure, and the entrenched belief that our now private national defenders are far more effective than the state at finding answers.”</p>
<p>Perhaps. But these analyses fail to consider the motivations and ideologies driving current elected officials in France. Some time ago, a well-connected political operative told me that since the Treaty of Maastricht, French politicians have suffered from a lack of ambition and energy, regardless of their political philosophies, because “in the end, Brussels decides.” But one can reasonably wonder what European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen is irksomely “deciding” right now as she squirms in front of the cameras and hospitals continue to overflow. Furious with the United Kingdom, which dared to leave the E.U.—and financed the homegrown Oxford-AstraZeneca vaccine—she doesn’t know which way to turn anymore. How can she be a good “liberal” when Anglo-Saxon “populist-nationalists” and Russian and Chinese dictators—each one more power hungry than the next—control the production of these crucial vaccines? The <em>Wall Street Journal</em> captured the irony best when it reported that, as of mid-March, the E.U. was the top global exporter of COVID-19 vaccines, at 40 million doses, “despite its difficulties procuring and delivering vaccines” for Europeans. Now everything is going sideways for President von der Leyen. A lover of private markets and free trade, she has been reduced to issuing threats, in a rather protectionist tone, against private companies AstraZeneca and Pfizer in order to limit their exports of European-made vaccines to faraway countries.</p>
<p>And what of Macron? Discrediting the British vaccine was a foolish tactic—and far from being sound policy. But Brussels, or rather Berlin, is the lead actor determining the tactics of Élysée bureaucrats these days. Macron’s constant health care policy shake-ups have flummoxed everyone, including President von der Leyen, who seems to want to appear more European than German. On March 15, when France temporarily suspended the AstraZeneca vaccine because of extremely rare occurrences of blood clots, the European Medicines Agency (EMA) was quick to reassure the public that the vaccine posed no danger. But why bother? A source close to the French president told the daily newspaper <em>Les</em> <em>Échos</em> that France wanted to wait until the next EMA meeting before suspending the vaccine, “but Berlin jumped the gun, under internal pressure.” So Berlin decided that more French people (and Germans, Italians, and Spaniards) would die rather than take the AstraZeneca shot—and all because of a four-day suspension—with no regard for European “unity.” And then we wonder why the French are so hesitant to get vaccinated?</p>
<p><em>Read MacArthur’s remembrance of <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/in-memoriam-john-cullen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John Cullen</a>, the former translator of these columns.</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/05/the-french-fiasco/" target="_blank">The French Fiasco</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Birds of a Feather]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/birds-of-a-feather/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/birds-of-a-feather/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 20:54:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Whether or not you remember anything from high school biology, the word “species” seems fairly self-explanatory: a kitten isn’t the same thing as a crab. Yet what distinguishes a particular species from its subspecies is a far trickier determination to make than “cat ? crustacean.” The act of taxonomic classification has befuddled biologists regardless of specialization or era. “I look at the term species as one arbitrarily given for the sake of convenience,” wrote Charles Darwin. In the May issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine,</em> <a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/05/birds-of-a-feather-endangered-species-list-revision/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zach St. George</a> tracks the saga of the California gnatcatcher, a gray bird that sits at the center of a dispute between the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, which decides which species merit Endangered Species Act protection, and the Pacific Legal Foundation, a libertarian law firm arguing that the bird is functionally indistinct from any number of other gnatcatchers. Even if Pacific Legal’s motives are less than purely scientific, its case highlights legitimate criticisms—echoed by many biologists—about the imprecise way the Endangered Species Act codifies what counts as a species. St. George explains how this argument has led to further questions about the bill, such as how it might be changed to better suit an era in which the environment is deteriorating faster than ever.</p>
<p>In this episode of the podcast, <em>Harper’s </em>web editor Violet Lucca talks with St. George about the ESA, the philosophical and scientific questions prompted by the practice of taxonomy, and the more proactive ways we might approach the likely irreversible damage of climate change.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Birds of a Feather by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1039442386&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/birds-of-a-feather/" target="_blank">Birds of a Feather</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-chauvin-conviction-nasa-unknown-flying-object-donald-trump/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-chauvin-conviction-nasa-unknown-flying-object-donald-trump/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 16:21:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Derek Chauvin was found guilty of the second-degree murder, third-degree murder, and second-degree manslaughter of George Floyd, and at least six people were killed in the United States by police officers in the 24 hours following the conviction.<sup><a title="CNN" href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/20/us/derek-chauvin-trial-george-floyd-deliberations/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a title="AP News" href="http://apnews.com/article/columbus-shootings-death-of-george-floyd-racial-injustice-arrests-89cc1cbfd8d7e452c4b4670e319cdfa9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a></sup> Days before Philadelphia’s first official day of remembrance for the 1985 police bombing of the MOVE organization, it was revealed that the bones of black children murdered in the siege had been used without permission for an online course titled Real Bones: Adventures in Forensic Anthropology.<a title="The Guardian" href="https://theguardian.com/us-news/2021/apr/22/move-bombing-black-children-bones-philadelphia-princeton-pennsylvania" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>3</sup></a> In Des Moines, Iowa, a woman who ran over two children with her 1998 Jeep Grand Cherokee because of their ethnicities pleaded guilty to two counts of attempted murder, and in Oklahoma, Governor Kevin Stitt signed a bill that protects drivers who run over protesters.<sup><a title="Des Moines Register" href="https://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/crime-and-courts/2021/04/21/des-moines-woman-hate-crime-pleads-guilty-hitting-black-latino-children-car-nicole-poole-franklin/7299782002/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a title="CNN" href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/22/us/oklahoma-law-drivers-protesters/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a></sup> “I remain unequivocally committed to protecting every Oklahoman’s First Amendment right to peacefully protest as well as their right to feel safe in their community,” Stitt said. A bill to combat anti-Asian hate crimes passed in the Senate, 94–1; the single nay vote came from Senator Josh Hawley, who tweeted that it “turns the federal government into the speech police.”<a title="CNN/WDJT-Milwaukee" href="https://www.cbs58.com/news/senate-overwhelmingly-passes-anti-asian-hate-crimes-bill" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>6</sup></a> <sup><a title="KTVO" href="https://ktvo.com/news/local/police-officers-in-need-of-more-support-says-sen-josh-hawley" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> President Biden officially acknowledged the Armenian genocide, and a White House official said that the United States, whose current and previous presidential administrations have both asserted that there is an ongoing genocide of Uighur Muslims, will pressure China at a G7 meeting in June about its use of forced labor in Xinjiang.<sup><a title="Wall Street Journal" href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/bidens-recognition-of-armenian-genocide-helps-healing-of-a-deep-wound-11619435877" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a> <a title="Reuters" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/exclusive-biden-will-push-allies-act-china-forced-labor-g7-adviser-2021-04-24/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">9</a> </sup> “Is it enough? No,” said John Kerry, Biden’s special envoy for climate, of the president’s commitment to halve U.S. greenhouse-gas emissions by 2030.<sup><a title="CNBC" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/22/biden-pledges-to-slash-greenhouse-gas-emissions-in-half-by-2030.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup></p>
<p>In India, which is currently facing the largest COVID-19 surge on record, a thief returned a bag stolen from a hospital after realizing that it contained vaccine vials, attaching an apology note that read, “Sorry, didn’t know they were Covid vaccines,” and in Catanzaro, Italy, a civil servant assigned to a hospital was accused of collecting his full salary despite skipping work since 2005.<sup><a title="Wall Street Journal" href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/indias-covid-surge-is-most-ferocious-yet-spreading-like-wildfire-11619388584" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> <a title="The Print" href="https://theprint.in/india/sorry-didnt-know-they-were-covid-vaccines-haryana-thief-returns-stolen-vials-with-note/644447/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">12</a> <a title="BBC" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-56822571" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a></sup> Before it was announced that he would host an upcoming episode of <em>Saturday Night Live,</em> Elon Musk tweeted “Autopilot was not enabled” in response to news reports that a Tesla Model S car had crashed, killing two people, and that an initial investigation of the wreck suggested that the driver’s seat was vacant at the time of impact.<sup><a title="NPR" href="https://www.npr.org/2021/04/25/990603441/elon-musk-to-host-saturday-night-live" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a> <a title="BBC" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56799749" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15</a></sup> After SpaceX and NASA successfully launched the spacecraft Crew Dragon <em>Endeavour,</em> its crew was warned of a possible collision with a flying object that, according to NASA, was classified as “unknown,” before arriving safely at the International Space Station, which no longer has enough beds for all the astronauts on board; a new study by MIT found that, in settings with mixed air, even masked individuals who spend significant time in such a space are as likely to contract COVID-19 as unmasked people, whether they are six or 60 feet apart; and a NASA executive pleaded guilty to using pandemic relief loans to pay off his Disney Vacation Club membership fees.<sup><a title="Futurism" href="https://futurism.com/spacex-unidentified-object" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a> <a title="NPR" href="https://www.npr.org/2021/04/24/990482441/tight-quarters-aboard-the-space-station-as-spacex-capsule-docks-with-4-new-arriv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a> <a title="News &amp; Observer" href="https://www.newsobserver.com/news/coronavirus/article250810009.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">18</a> <a title="CNBC" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/23/mit-researchers-say-youre-no-safer-from-covid-indoors-at-6-feet-or-60-feet-in-new-study.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup> Reflecting on his time in the White House, Donald Trump told fellow Palm Beach Billionaire’s Row resident Sean Hannity that what he misses the most is “helping people.”<sup><a title="Salon" href="https://www.salon.com/2021/04/20/trump-declares-being-commander-in-chief-was-very-traumatic-in-softball-sean-hannity-interview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> <a title="New York Daily News" href="https://www.nydailynews.com/snyde/ny-sean-hannity-house-palm-beach-mar-a-lago-20210422-jj3xqtpsfrbl5gkwsdgtoesgkm-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a> <a title="Vanity Fair" href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2021/04/sean-hannitys-trump-florida-mansion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup> George W. Bush, who withdrew the United States from the Rome Statute and therefore shielded Americans from prosecution in the International Criminal Court, said that he wrote in the name of Condoleezza Rice when he voted in the 2020 presidential election.<sup><a title="NBC" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/george-w-bush-walks-back-nativist-comment-says-he-wrote-n1265036" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> <a title="Human Rights Watch" href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2020/09/02/qa-international-criminal-court-and-united-states" target="_blank" rel="noopener">21</a></sup></p>
<p>A renowned tyrannosaur expert studying a mass-death site said that the “synchronous death event” suggests that these dinosaurs, formerly thought to have been solitary, may have in fact been “capable of interacting as gregarious packs.”<sup><a title="U.S. Department of Land Management" href="https://www.blm.gov/press-release/evidence-indicates-tyrannosaurs-may-not-have-been-solitary-species-after-all" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a> </sup>American honey made in the recent past was found to contain radioactive fallout from nuclear-weapons testing in the Fifties and Sixties.<a title="Smithsonian Magazine" href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/cold-war-era-nuclear-fallout-detected-us-honey-180977576/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>23</sup></a> A rioter who bragged about his illegal actions at the U.S. Capitol to someone he chatted with on the dating app Bumble was arrested after his match provided screenshots of their conversation to law enforcement, a man in Japan was arrested for defrauding at least 35 women he was dating after he received “birthday” gifts valued at 100,000 yen, and a Taiwanese couple got married four times and divorced three times over a period of 37 days in order to take advantage of the country’s eight days of paid marriage leave.<sup><a title="CNN" href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/23/politics/bumble-capitol-riot-robert-chapman/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> <a title="Sora News 24" href="https://soranews24.com/2021/04/22/kansai-man-arrested-for-defrauding-his-35-girlfriends/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25</a> <a title="New York Times" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/22/world/asia/taiwan-marriage-leave-scam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup> A psychologist at a Minnesota sex-offender treatment center was charged with sexually assaulting two of her patients, a British teacher who brought students to a strip club while intoxicated was banned from teaching for three years, and a French mayor convicted of rape received criticism from feminist groups for continuing to run the town from his prison cell.<sup><a title="Star Tribune" href="https://www.startribune.com/psychologist-at-minnesota-sex-offender-program-charged-with-sexually-assaulting-two-clients/600049133/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">27</a> <a title="BBC" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-tyne-56858188" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28</a> <a title="The Guardian" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/23/outrage-french-mayor-georges-tron-convicted-rape-still-running-town-prison" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29</a></sup> President Jair Bolsonaro offered to reduce Brazil’s deforestation of the Amazon by 40 percent in exchange for $1 billion from the Biden Administration, and two fishermen who recovered a buoy owned by the U.S. government asked for $13,000 in exchange for its return.<sup><a title="Wall Street Journal" href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/brazils-climate-overture-to-biden-pay-us-not-to-raze-amazon-11618997400?mod=hp_lead_pos10" target="_blank" rel="noopener">30</a> <a title="Ars Technica" href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2016/03/2-men-take-us-govt-ocean-science-buoy-now-want-to-sell-it-back-for-13000/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">31</a></sup> “If you lose something in the ocean, it doesn’t stay yours forever,” said their attorney, who is also the father of one of the fishermen. “It becomes salvaged.”—<em>Clara Olshansky</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-chauvin-conviction-nasa-unknown-flying-object-donald-trump/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Memoriam: John Cullen]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/in-memoriam-john-cullen/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/in-memoriam-john-cullen/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 20:38:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">Readers may be wondering why I haven’t posted a new, translated column in the past two weeks, since I write monthly (almost without fail) for <em>Le Devoir</em> of Montreal. There are two reasons: the first is that Catholic Quebec shuts down the day after Easter, so my column was delayed a week from its usual first-Monday-of-the-month publication schedule, and the second is that during the delay my friend and translator, John Cullen, fell ill and died. John’s passing, at seventy-nine, is a terrible loss for his partner, the novelist Valerie Martin, and for his family and friends back in New Orleans, where he was born. If you knew him, you would instantly recognize the easy and ironic humor of John’s hometown in every story and every joke he told. Raconteur is one of those French words that has gravitated seamlessly into English, and it describes John to a T. Like the city that bred him, he was never boring, and like the people he grew up with, he always took sufficient time to tell a story with style and aplomb. New Orleans is America’s most unusual and, in some respects, most “foreign” city, with a culture that defies American stereotypes. I suspect that it’s the mélange of New Orleans French, Creole, Spanish, and English that turned John into a linguist, and it was his ease in commuting between cultures that made him such a good translator. That facility, with varied tongues and nationalities, is no doubt what made him valuable to novelists and journalists alike.</p>
<p>You might ask why I had my column translated at all, why I didn’t just rewrite myself in English. The answer is partly because I don’t have the time or the patience, and partly because I think so separately in two languages because my mother was French and my father was American. But there’s another very specific reason. In 2014, when I stopped writing my column in the <em>Providence Journal</em>, I suddenly had no regular outlet in English for the first time in many years. The easiest solution was to have my French column translated, and, I thought, wouldn’t that be a novelty? But I almost never read French in translation, so I didn’t know any translators or even how to judge them. Then I remembered John Cullen. I hadn’t met him, but I knew one of his star clients, the novelist Philippe Claudel, from having moderated a discussion between Claudel and A.M. Homes at NYU’s Maison Française back in 2011. It was there that the actor Robert Adrian read an excerpt of Claudel’s extraordinary work <em>Le Rapport de </em><em>Brodeck</em>, and it struck me: “This is how Claudel should sound in English.” It was pitch perfect. My American mind heard my French understanding of the novel and read it back to me so well in English that I hardly noticed the difference in languages.</p>
<p>Later I learned that John occasionally translated francophone journalists like Kamel Daoud, whose pieces on the op-ed page of the <em>New York Times</em> betrayed none of the standard awkwardness from foreign contributors. Lost in translation is a well-worn cliché, but it’s axiomatically true that meaning gets dispersed and hidden from one culture to another, one set of idioms to another. When I asked John if he would translate my column, he at first demurred. But he finally agreed, and from February 2016 until this past March, for fifty-three columns, John explained my French conception to my American readers. With considerable editing help from <em>Harper’s Magazine</em>’s then editor Ellen Rosenbush, we turned it into something resembling my “voice.” Sometimes it worked perfectly, and Ellen, who continues to edit the column, changed almost nothing. Sometimes we struggled, but those occasions had more to do with my French construction failing me than with John failing me. Now that he’s gone, I will have a hard time finding a replacement. And I know that while I miss him very much as a person, I’m also missing something inside my head, and I don’t quite know where to look for it. Is it in French or is it in English? I may have to go to New Orleans to find out.</p>
<p><a href="https://obits.nola.com/obituaries/nola/obituary.aspx?n=john-christopher-cullen&amp;pid=198368944" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Read John’s obituary in the </em>Times-Picayune.</a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/in-memoriam-john-cullen/" target="_blank">In Memoriam: John Cullen</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost in Thought]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/lost-in-thought/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/lost-in-thought/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 02:58:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">As work subsumes leisure time, worldwide anxieties mount, and a pandemic reshapes comfort and togetherness, meditation has been touted as a panacea. People who are stressed out (are there any other kind?) can take a meditation course, read an article, go on a retreat, or use an app; the hope is to gain from meditation peace, health, productivity, focus, or a good night’s sleep. It comes almost universally recommended and has precious few public detractors.</p>
<p>David Kortava’s article “<a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/04/lost-in-thought-psychological-risks-of-meditation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lost in Thought</a>,” from the April issue of <em>Harper’s Magazine</em>, is an investigation into the possible negative side effects of meditation. Kortava reports on a practitioner’s bout with psychosis during an extended stay at a vipassana meditation center that had her wishing for death. Kortava presents evidence of meditation’s potential to distress and harm. In this episode of the podcast, <em>Harper’s</em> web editor Violet Lucca speaks with Kortava about the experiential gap filled by meditation, the perils of a one-size-fits-all approach, and the gulf between the origins of meditative practice and its modern-day deployment.</p>
<div class="entry-content-asset"><iframe loading="lazy" title="Lost in Thought by Harper’s Magazine" width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F1035050125&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750&#038;dnt=1"></iframe></div>
<p>Never miss an episode! Subscribe to our podcast:<br />
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-harpers-podcast/id1405872370?mt=2"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-269336 alignnone" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/iTunes.png" alt="" width="85" height="94" /></a><a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/harpers-magazine/the-harpers-podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269334" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Stitcher-with-name.png" alt="" width="85" height="85" /></a><a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Iscsisgytu65tg446s3xukl7jja?t=The_Harpers_Podcast"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-269335" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Google-Play.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4h9SICTDppd1iJv9n5jXfc?si=zzWUGj8vQfaDJlzDaxmnwg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-275673" src="https://harpers.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/spotify_icon_cmyk_green.png" alt="" width="85" height="80" /></a></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/lost-in-thought/" target="_blank">Lost in Thought</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></title>
            <link>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-mass-shooting-fukushima-water-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine/</link>
            <guid>https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-mass-shooting-fukushima-water-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 17:55:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p class="drop-cap">In Indianapolis, a 19-year-old killed eight people and wounded several others at a FedEx warehouse where employees were unable to call the police or family members because of a company policy forbidding workers from carrying cell phones.<sup><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/16/politics/mass-shootings-america-guns/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/fedex-indianapolis-cell-phone-policy-employee-shooting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2</a></sup> A police department in Minnesota released body-cam footage of an officer killing an unarmed 20-year-old named Daunte Wright, some 10 miles away from the courthouse in which another officer, Derek Chauvin, is on trial for the death of George Floyd; the City of Chicago released a video recording of an officer killing 13-year-old Adam Toledo after he had lifted his hands in the air; Kenosha, Wisconsin, law enforcement announced that the officer who shot and paralyzed Jacob Blake would not face disciplinary action; and one of the police officers who shot Breonna Taylor in Louisville, Kentucky, was given a book deal.<sup><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1_H710uztOQ3b6G-OvE_XWhlLQsMXypGHkrUW25JCzFU/edit?ts=607ee496#gid=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/15/us/adam-toledo-chicago-shooting-video.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/nbcblk/no-discipline-kenosha-police-officer-who-shot-jacob-blake-chief-n1263986" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5</a> <a href="https://www.thecut.com/2021/04/one-of-the-cops-who-killed-breonna-taylor-got-a-book-deal.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6</a></sup> Federal health officials called for a temporarily halt to distribution of the Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine after six people out of the more than 7 million who have received the shot fell ill.<sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/13/us/politics/johnson-johnson-vaccine-blood-clots-fda-cdc.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">7</a></sup> President Joe Biden announced that the United States will withdraw all troops from Afghanistan by September 11, and Republican members of Congress announced, and then subsequently canceled, plans for an America First caucus that would work to foster “common respect for uniquely Anglo-Saxon political traditions.”<sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/biden-us-troop-withdrawal-afghanistan/2021/04/13/918c3cae-9beb-11eb-8a83-3bc1fa69c2e8_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8</a></sup> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/04/20/marjorie-taylor-greene-implosion-america-first-caucus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>9</sup></a></p>
<p>The assistant defense minister of Australia reminded the nation’s armed forces that their chief mission remained the “application of lethal violence” after a controversial commissioning ceremony for the HMAS <em>Supply</em> that featured a dance troupe twerking in front of the 21,500-pound replenishment oiler.<sup><a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-04-14/military-reminded-lethal-violence-defend-australian-values/100066796" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10</a></sup> A Czech man turned over to authorities a T-34 tank and a SD-100 tank destroyer as part of a nationwide weapon-amnesty program, and a Yorkshire, England, woman whose partner was killed with a crossbow issued a call for British legislation regulating access to “medieval weapons.”<sup><a href="https://praguemorning.cz/czech-nationwide-weapon-amnesty-prompts-citizen-to-turn-tank-over-to-authorities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">11</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/apr/16/woman-who-lost-partner-in-crossbow-attack-wants-medieval-weapon-regulated" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>12</sup></a> The city council in Placerville, California—whose nickname, “Hangtown,” derives from a series of 19th-century lynchings—decided to remove the noose that had been featured on its seal, and Facebook apologized for removing the official page of the French town of Bitche after it was mistakenly flagged for containing offensive language.<sup><a href="https://localnews8.com/news/2021/04/14/city-known-as-hangtown-votes-to-remove-noose-from-its-logo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">13</a> <a href="https://www.cityofplacerville.org/placerville-city-history" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14</a> </sup><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/13/lifes-a-bitche-french-towns-facebook-page-shut-down-over-offensive-name" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>15</sup></a> “The name of our town seems to suffer from a bad interpretation,” said Bitche’s mayor. The Florida House of Representatives passed a bill forbidding transgender students from participating in women’s high school and college sports, and authorizing genital inspections in cases in which a student’s gender is disputed.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/changing-america/respect/equality/548534-floridas-new-ban-on-transgender-students-in-sports-would" target="_blank" rel="noopener">16</a></sup> “This is about giving women and girls an equal chance to succeed,” said one Florida Republican who supported the bill. “It’s simple.” A Republican state senator in Missouri introduced legislation to designate January 12 as Rush Limbaugh Day, and Tennessee lawmakers proposed naming the ladder as the official state tool.<sup><a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/548526-missouri-state-gop-lawmakers-propose-rush-limbaugh-day" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17</a> </sup><a href="https://www.wkrn.com/news/local-news/ladder-could-be-named-official-state-tool-of-tennessee/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>18</sup></a> An Austrian court ruled that intentional flatulence contains no “communicative content” and thus is not protected by the freedom of expression.<sup><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/z3xb59/man-fined-for-farting-on-cop-argues-farts-are-protected-forms-of-expression" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19</a></sup></p>
<p>Japan announced plans to release into the Pacific Ocean more than 1 million tons of treated wastewater that was contaminated in the Fukushima nuclear disaster, prompting a spokesperson for the Chinese Foreign Ministry to urge Japan’s deputy prime minister to drink it himself.<sup><a href="https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2021/04/japan-plans-release-fukushima-s-contaminated-water-ocean" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20</a> </sup><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/04/14/china-japan-fukushima-water-drink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>21</sup></a> “The ocean is not Japan’s trash can,” said the spokesperson. The islanders of Tanna, who view the late Prince Philip as a “recycled descendant of a very powerful spirit or god that lives on one of their mountains,” mourned the royal’s passing.<sup><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/prince-philip-death-vanuatu-tribes-tanna-worship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">22</a></sup> Darius, the world’s largest rabbit, was reported missing; a mysterious creature spotted in a tree in Kraków was revealed by animal-welfare workers to be a croissant; and a group of scientists created chimeric embryos consisting of both human and monkey cells.<sup><a href="https://www.livescience.com/worlds-largest-rabbit-darius-missing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">23</a> <a href="https://www.euronews.com/2021/04/16/mystery-animal-sighting-in-krakow-ends-up-being-a-croissant" target="_blank" rel="noopener">24</a> </sup><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2021/04/15/987164563/scientists-create-early-embryos-that-are-part-human-part-monkey" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><sup>25</sup></a> “My first question is, why?” asked one researcher who was not involved in the project. A study determined that the total number of <em>Tyrannosaurus</em> <em>rexes</em> that ever existed was roughly 2.5 billion, though only about 20,000 adults were alive at any given time.<sup><a href="https://www.reuters.com/lifestyle/science/like-godzilla-actually-real-study-shows-t-rex-numbered-25-billion-2021-04-15/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">26</a></sup></p><p>The post <a href="https://harpers.org/2021/04/weekly-review-mass-shooting-fukushima-water-johnson-and-johnson-vaccine/" target="_blank">Weekly Review</a> first appeared on <a href="https://harpers.org/" target="_blank">Harper&#039;s Magazine</a>.</p>]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>